[{
	"category_id": null,
	"question": "_________ is a branch of physical science that studies the composition, structure, properties and change of matter.",
	"topic_id": null,
	"sub_cat_id": null,
	"id": null,
	"answer": "Chemistry"
}, {
	"category_id": null,
	"question": "_________ includes topics such as the properties of individual atoms, how atoms form chemical bonds to create chemical compounds, the interactions of substances through intermolecular forces that give matter its general properties, and the interactions between substances through chemical reactions to form different substances.",
	"topic_id": null,
	"sub_cat_id": null,
	"id": null,
	"answer": "Chemistry"
}, {
	"category_id": null,
	"question": "_________ is sometimes called the central science because it bridges other natural sciences, including physics, geology and biology.",
	"topic_id": null,
	"sub_cat_id": null,
	"id": null,
	"answer": "Chemistry"
}, {
	"category_id": null,
	"question": "For the differences between chemistry and physics see comparison of chemistry and physics.",
	"topic_id": null,
	"sub_cat_id": null,
	"id": null,
	"answer": "Chemistry"
}, {
	"category_id": null,
	"question": "The history of chemistry can be traced to _______, which had been practiced for several millennia in various parts of the world.",
	"topic_id": null,
	"sub_cat_id": null,
	"id": null,
	"answer": "alchemy"
}, {
	"category_id": null,
	"question": "__________________ comes from the word alchemy which was an earlier set of practices that encompassed elements of chemistry, metallurgy, philosophy, astrology, astronomy, mysticism and medicine.",
	"topic_id": null,
	"sub_cat_id": null,
	"id": null,
	"answer": "The word chemistry"
}, {
	"category_id": null,
	"question": "It is often seen as linked to the quest to turn lead or another common starting material into gold.",
	"topic_id": null,
	"sub_cat_id": null,
	"id": null,
	"answer": "Alchemy"
}, {
	"category_id": null,
	"question": "_______, which was practiced around 330, is the study of the composition of waters, movement, growth, embodying, disembodying, drawing the spirits from bodies and bonding the spirits within bodies (Zosimos).",
	"topic_id": null,
	"sub_cat_id": null,
	"id": null,
	"answer": "Alchemy"
}, {
	"category_id": null,
	"question": "An alchemist was called a 'chemist' in popular speech, and later the suffix \"-ry\" was added to this to describe the art of the chemist as \"chemistry\".",
	"topic_id": null,
	"sub_cat_id": null,
	"id": null,
	"answer": "Alchemy"
}, {
	"category_id": null,
	"question": "Alchemy, which was practiced around 330, is the study of the composition of waters, movement, growth, embodying, disembodying, drawing the spirits from bodies and bonding the spirits within bodies (Zosimos).",
	"topic_id": null,
	"sub_cat_id": null,
	"id": null,
	"answer": "gold.[6] Alchemy"
}, {
	"category_id": null,
	"question": "In origin, ________ is borrowed from the Greek \u03c7\u03b7\u03bc\u03af\u03b1 or \u03c7\u03b7\u03bc\u03b5\u03af\u03b1.",
	"topic_id": null,
	"sub_cat_id": null,
	"id": null,
	"answer": "the term"
}, {
	"category_id": null,
	"question": "This may have Egyptian origins since al-k\u012bm\u012b\u0101 is derived from the Greek \u03c7\u03b7\u03bc\u03af\u03b1, which is in turn derived from the word Chemi or Kimi, which is the ancient name of Egypt in Egyptian.",
	"topic_id": null,
	"sub_cat_id": null,
	"id": null,
	"answer": "the term"
}, {
	"category_id": null,
	"question": "Alternately, al-k\u012bm\u012b\u0101 may derive from \u03c7\u03b7\u03bc\u03b5\u03af\u03b1, meaning \"cast together\".",
	"topic_id": null,
	"sub_cat_id": null,
	"id": null,
	"answer": "the term"
}, {
	"category_id": null,
	"question": "In origin, the term is borrowed from the Greek \u03c7\u03b7\u03bc\u03af\u03b1 or \u03c7\u03b7\u03bc\u03b5\u03af\u03b1.",
	"topic_id": null,
	"sub_cat_id": null,
	"id": null,
	"answer": "al-k\u012bm\u012b\u0101"
}, {
	"category_id": null,
	"question": "This may have Egyptian origins since ________ is derived from the Greek \u03c7\u03b7\u03bc\u03af\u03b1, which is in turn derived from the word Chemi or Kimi, which is the ancient name of Egypt in Egyptian.",
	"topic_id": null,
	"sub_cat_id": null,
	"id": null,
	"answer": "al-k\u012bm\u012b\u0101"
}, {
	"category_id": null,
	"question": "Alternately, ________ may derive from \u03c7\u03b7\u03bc\u03b5\u03af\u03b1, meaning \"cast together\".",
	"topic_id": null,
	"sub_cat_id": null,
	"id": null,
	"answer": "al-k\u012bm\u012b\u0101"
}, {
	"category_id": null,
	"question": "In origin, the term is borrowed from _______________ or \u03c7\u03b7\u03bc\u03b5\u03af\u03b1.",
	"topic_id": null,
	"sub_cat_id": null,
	"id": null,
	"answer": "the Greek \u03c7\u03b7\u03bc\u03af\u03b1"
}, {
	"category_id": null,
	"question": "This may have Egyptian origins since al-k\u012bm\u012b\u0101 is derived from _______________, which is in turn derived from the word Chemi or Kimi, which is the ancient name of Egypt in Egyptian.",
	"topic_id": null,
	"sub_cat_id": null,
	"id": null,
	"answer": "the Greek \u03c7\u03b7\u03bc\u03af\u03b1"
}, {
	"category_id": null,
	"question": "______________________________ was later adopted by Epicurus (341\u2013270 BCE).",
	"topic_id": null,
	"sub_cat_id": null,
	"id": null,
	"answer": "Democritus' atomist philosophy"
}, {
	"category_id": null,
	"question": "A basic chemical hypothesis first emerged in Classical Greece with the theory of four elements as propounded definitively by _________ stating that that fire, air, earth and water were the fundamental elements from which everything is formed as a combination.",
	"topic_id": null,
	"sub_cat_id": null,
	"id": null,
	"answer": "Aristotle"
}, {
	"category_id": null,
	"question": "Greek atomism dates back to ______, arising in works by philosophers such as Democritus and Epicurus.",
	"topic_id": null,
	"sub_cat_id": null,
	"id": null,
	"answer": "440 BC"
}, {
	"category_id": null,
	"question": "In 50 BC, the Roman philosopher Lucretius expanded upon the theory in his book De rerum natura (On The Nature of Things).",
	"topic_id": null,
	"sub_cat_id": null,
	"id": null,
	"answer": "Greek atomism"
}, {
	"category_id": null,
	"question": "Unlike modern concepts of science, _____________ was purely philosophical in nature, with little concern for empirical observations and no concern for chemical experiments.",
	"topic_id": null,
	"sub_cat_id": null,
	"id": null,
	"answer": "Greek atomism"
}, {
	"category_id": null,
	"question": "In the Hellenistic world the art of alchemy first proliferated, mingling magic and occultism into the study of natural substances with the ultimate goal of transmuting ________ into gold and discovering the elixir of eternal life.",
	"topic_id": null,
	"sub_cat_id": null,
	"id": null,
	"answer": "elements"
}, {
	"category_id": null,
	"question": "Alchemy was discovered and practised widely throughout the Arab world after the Muslim conquests,[23] and from there, diffused into medieval and Renaissance Europe through Latin translations.",
	"topic_id": null,
	"sub_cat_id": null,
	"id": null,
	"answer": "elements"
}, {
	"category_id": null,
	"question": "In the Hellenistic world the art of alchemy first proliferated, mingling magic and occultism into the study of natural substances with the ultimate goal of transmuting elements into gold and discovering the elixir of eternal life.",
	"topic_id": null,
	"sub_cat_id": null,
	"id": null,
	"answer": "Alchemy"
}, {
	"category_id": null,
	"question": "_______ was discovered and practised widely throughout the Arab world after the Muslim conquests,[23] and from there, diffused into medieval and Renaissance Europe through Latin translations.",
	"topic_id": null,
	"sub_cat_id": null,
	"id": null,
	"answer": "Alchemy"
}, {
	"category_id": null,
	"question": "___________________ is regarded as the founding father of chemistry due to his most important work, the classic chemistry text The Sceptical Chymist where the differentiation is made between the claims of alchemy and the empirical scientific discoveries of the new chemistry.",
	"topic_id": null,
	"sub_cat_id": null,
	"id": null,
	"answer": "Boyle in particular"
}, {
	"category_id": null,
	"question": "He formulated Boyle's law, rejected the classical \"four elements\" and proposed a mechanistic alternative of atoms and chemical reactions that could be subject to rigorous experiment.",
	"topic_id": null,
	"sub_cat_id": null,
	"id": null,
	"answer": "Boyle in particular"
}, {
	"category_id": null,
	"question": "Boyle in particular is regarded as the founding ______ of chemistry due to his most important work, the classic chemistry text The Sceptical Chymist where the differentiation is made between the claims of alchemy and the empirical scientific discoveries of the new chemistry.",
	"topic_id": null,
	"sub_cat_id": null,
	"id": null,
	"answer": "father"
}, {
	"category_id": null,
	"question": "Boyle in particular is regarded as the founding father of chemistry due to his most important work, the classic chemistry text The Sceptical Chymist where ___________________ is made between the claims of alchemy and the empirical scientific discoveries of the new chemistry.",
	"topic_id": null,
	"sub_cat_id": null,
	"id": null,
	"answer": "the differentiation"
}, {
	"category_id": null,
	"question": "_________ is a branch of physical science that studies the composition, structure, properties and change of matter.",
	"topic_id": null,
	"sub_cat_id": null,
	"id": null,
	"answer": "Chemistry"
}, {
	"category_id": null,
	"question": "_________ includes topics such as the properties of individual atoms, how atoms form chemical bonds to create chemical compounds, the interactions of substances through intermolecular forces that give matter its general properties, and the interactions between substances through chemical reactions to form different substances.",
	"topic_id": null,
	"sub_cat_id": null,
	"id": null,
	"answer": "Chemistry"
}, {
	"category_id": null,
	"question": "_________ is sometimes called the central science because it bridges other natural sciences, including physics, geology and biology.",
	"topic_id": null,
	"sub_cat_id": null,
	"id": null,
	"answer": "Chemistry"
}, {
	"category_id": null,
	"question": "For the differences between chemistry and physics see comparison of chemistry and physics.",
	"topic_id": null,
	"sub_cat_id": null,
	"id": null,
	"answer": "Chemistry"
}, {
	"category_id": null,
	"question": "The history of chemistry can be traced to _______, which had been practiced for several millennia in various parts of the world.",
	"topic_id": null,
	"sub_cat_id": null,
	"id": null,
	"answer": "alchemy"
}, {
	"category_id": null,
	"question": "__________________ comes from the word alchemy which was an earlier set of practices that encompassed elements of chemistry, metallurgy, philosophy, astrology, astronomy, mysticism and medicine.",
	"topic_id": null,
	"sub_cat_id": null,
	"id": null,
	"answer": "The word chemistry"
}, {
	"category_id": null,
	"question": "It is often seen as linked to the quest to turn lead or another common starting material into gold.",
	"topic_id": null,
	"sub_cat_id": null,
	"id": null,
	"answer": "Alchemy"
}, {
	"category_id": null,
	"question": "_______, which was practiced around 330, is the study of the composition of waters, movement, growth, embodying, disembodying, drawing the spirits from bodies and bonding the spirits within bodies (Zosimos).",
	"topic_id": null,
	"sub_cat_id": null,
	"id": null,
	"answer": "Alchemy"
}, {
	"category_id": null,
	"question": "An alchemist was called a 'chemist' in popular speech, and later the suffix \"-ry\" was added to this to describe the art of the chemist as \"chemistry\".",
	"topic_id": null,
	"sub_cat_id": null,
	"id": null,
	"answer": "Alchemy"
}, {
	"category_id": null,
	"question": "Alchemy, which was practiced around 330, is the study of the composition of waters, movement, growth, embodying, disembodying, drawing the spirits from bodies and bonding the spirits within bodies (Zosimos).",
	"topic_id": null,
	"sub_cat_id": null,
	"id": null,
	"answer": "gold.[6] Alchemy"
}, {
	"category_id": null,
	"question": "In origin, ________ is borrowed from the Greek \u03c7\u03b7\u03bc\u03af\u03b1 or \u03c7\u03b7\u03bc\u03b5\u03af\u03b1.",
	"topic_id": null,
	"sub_cat_id": null,
	"id": null,
	"answer": "the term"
}, {
	"category_id": null,
	"question": "This may have Egyptian origins since al-k\u012bm\u012b\u0101 is derived from the Greek \u03c7\u03b7\u03bc\u03af\u03b1, which is in turn derived from the word Chemi or Kimi, which is the ancient name of Egypt in Egyptian.",
	"topic_id": null,
	"sub_cat_id": null,
	"id": null,
	"answer": "the term"
}, {
	"category_id": null,
	"question": "Alternately, al-k\u012bm\u012b\u0101 may derive from \u03c7\u03b7\u03bc\u03b5\u03af\u03b1, meaning \"cast together\".",
	"topic_id": null,
	"sub_cat_id": null,
	"id": null,
	"answer": "the term"
}, {
	"category_id": null,
	"question": "In origin, the term is borrowed from the Greek \u03c7\u03b7\u03bc\u03af\u03b1 or \u03c7\u03b7\u03bc\u03b5\u03af\u03b1.",
	"topic_id": null,
	"sub_cat_id": null,
	"id": null,
	"answer": "al-k\u012bm\u012b\u0101"
}, {
	"category_id": null,
	"question": "This may have Egyptian origins since ________ is derived from the Greek \u03c7\u03b7\u03bc\u03af\u03b1, which is in turn derived from the word Chemi or Kimi, which is the ancient name of Egypt in Egyptian.",
	"topic_id": null,
	"sub_cat_id": null,
	"id": null,
	"answer": "al-k\u012bm\u012b\u0101"
}, {
	"category_id": null,
	"question": "Alternately, ________ may derive from \u03c7\u03b7\u03bc\u03b5\u03af\u03b1, meaning \"cast together\".",
	"topic_id": null,
	"sub_cat_id": null,
	"id": null,
	"answer": "al-k\u012bm\u012b\u0101"
}, {
	"category_id": null,
	"question": "In origin, the term is borrowed from _______________ or \u03c7\u03b7\u03bc\u03b5\u03af\u03b1.",
	"topic_id": null,
	"sub_cat_id": null,
	"id": null,
	"answer": "the Greek \u03c7\u03b7\u03bc\u03af\u03b1"
}, {
	"category_id": null,
	"question": "This may have Egyptian origins since al-k\u012bm\u012b\u0101 is derived from _______________, which is in turn derived from the word Chemi or Kimi, which is the ancient name of Egypt in Egyptian.",
	"topic_id": null,
	"sub_cat_id": null,
	"id": null,
	"answer": "the Greek \u03c7\u03b7\u03bc\u03af\u03b1"
}, {
	"category_id": null,
	"question": "______________________________ was later adopted by Epicurus (341\u2013270 BCE).",
	"topic_id": null,
	"sub_cat_id": null,
	"id": null,
	"answer": "Democritus' atomist philosophy"
}, {
	"category_id": null,
	"question": "A basic chemical hypothesis first emerged in Classical Greece with the theory of four elements as propounded definitively by _________ stating that that fire, air, earth and water were the fundamental elements from which everything is formed as a combination.",
	"topic_id": null,
	"sub_cat_id": null,
	"id": null,
	"answer": "Aristotle"
}, {
	"category_id": null,
	"question": "Greek atomism dates back to ______, arising in works by philosophers such as Democritus and Epicurus.",
	"topic_id": null,
	"sub_cat_id": null,
	"id": null,
	"answer": "440 BC"
}, {
	"category_id": null,
	"question": "In 50 BC, the Roman philosopher Lucretius expanded upon the theory in his book De rerum natura (On The Nature of Things).",
	"topic_id": null,
	"sub_cat_id": null,
	"id": null,
	"answer": "Greek atomism"
}, {
	"category_id": null,
	"question": "Unlike modern concepts of science, _____________ was purely philosophical in nature, with little concern for empirical observations and no concern for chemical experiments.",
	"topic_id": null,
	"sub_cat_id": null,
	"id": null,
	"answer": "Greek atomism"
}, {
	"category_id": null,
	"question": "In the Hellenistic world the art of alchemy first proliferated, mingling magic and occultism into the study of natural substances with the ultimate goal of transmuting ________ into gold and discovering the elixir of eternal life.",
	"topic_id": null,
	"sub_cat_id": null,
	"id": null,
	"answer": "elements"
}, {
	"category_id": null,
	"question": "Alchemy was discovered and practised widely throughout the Arab world after the Muslim conquests,[23] and from there, diffused into medieval and Renaissance Europe through Latin translations.",
	"topic_id": null,
	"sub_cat_id": null,
	"id": null,
	"answer": "elements"
}, {
	"category_id": null,
	"question": "In the Hellenistic world the art of alchemy first proliferated, mingling magic and occultism into the study of natural substances with the ultimate goal of transmuting elements into gold and discovering the elixir of eternal life.",
	"topic_id": null,
	"sub_cat_id": null,
	"id": null,
	"answer": "Alchemy"
}, {
	"category_id": null,
	"question": "_______ was discovered and practised widely throughout the Arab world after the Muslim conquests,[23] and from there, diffused into medieval and Renaissance Europe through Latin translations.",
	"topic_id": null,
	"sub_cat_id": null,
	"id": null,
	"answer": "Alchemy"
}, {
	"category_id": null,
	"question": "___________________ is regarded as the founding father of chemistry due to his most important work, the classic chemistry text The Sceptical Chymist where the differentiation is made between the claims of alchemy and the empirical scientific discoveries of the new chemistry.",
	"topic_id": null,
	"sub_cat_id": null,
	"id": null,
	"answer": "Boyle in particular"
}, {
	"category_id": null,
	"question": "He formulated Boyle's law, rejected the classical \"four elements\" and proposed a mechanistic alternative of atoms and chemical reactions that could be subject to rigorous experiment.",
	"topic_id": null,
	"sub_cat_id": null,
	"id": null,
	"answer": "Boyle in particular"
}, {
	"category_id": null,
	"question": "Boyle in particular is regarded as the founding ______ of chemistry due to his most important work, the classic chemistry text The Sceptical Chymist where the differentiation is made between the claims of alchemy and the empirical scientific discoveries of the new chemistry.",
	"topic_id": null,
	"sub_cat_id": null,
	"id": null,
	"answer": "father"
}, {
	"category_id": null,
	"question": "Boyle in particular is regarded as the founding father of chemistry due to his most important work, the classic chemistry text The Sceptical Chymist where ___________________ is made between the claims of alchemy and the empirical scientific discoveries of the new chemistry.",
	"topic_id": null,
	"sub_cat_id": null,
	"id": null,
	"answer": "the differentiation"
}, {
	"category_id": null,
	"question": "_____________ in line-angle representation, showing four carbon-hydrogen single (\u03c3) bonds in black, and the 3D shape of such tetrahedral molecules, with ~109\u00b0 interior bond angles, in green.",
	"topic_id": null,
	"sub_cat_id": null,
	"id": null,
	"answer": "Methane, CH4,"
}, {
	"category_id": null,
	"question": "_______ is the simplest organic chemical and simplest hydrocarbon, and molecules can be built up conceptually from it by exchanging up to all 4 hydrogens with carbon or other atoms.",
	"topic_id": null,
	"sub_cat_id": null,
	"id": null,
	"answer": "Methane"
}, {
	"category_id": null,
	"question": "_________________ is a chemistry subdiscipline involving the scientific study of the structure, properties, and reactions of organic compounds and organic materials, i.",
	"topic_id": null,
	"sub_cat_id": null,
	"id": null,
	"answer": "Organic chemistry"
}, {
	"category_id": null,
	"question": "Study of structure includes many physical and chemical methods to determine the chemical composition and the chemical constitution of organic compounds and materials.",
	"topic_id": null,
	"sub_cat_id": null,
	"id": null,
	"answer": "Organic chemistry"
}, {
	"category_id": null,
	"question": "Organic chemistry is a chemistry subdiscipline involving the scientific study of the structure, properties, and reactions of organic compounds and organic materials, i.",
	"topic_id": null,
	"sub_cat_id": null,
	"id": null,
	"answer": "its various forms"
}, {
	"category_id": null,
	"question": "_____ of properties includes both physical properties and chemical properties, and uses similar methods as well as methods to evaluate chemical reactivity, with the aim to understand the behavior of the organic matter in its pure form (when possible), but also in solutions, mixtures, and fabricated forms.",
	"topic_id": null,
	"sub_cat_id": null,
	"id": null,
	"answer": "Study"
}, {
	"category_id": null,
	"question": "Study of properties includes both physical properties and chemical properties, and uses similar _______ as well as _______ to evaluate chemical reactivity, with the aim to understand the behavior of the organic matter in its pure form (when possible), but also in solutions, mixtures, and fabricated forms.",
	"topic_id": null,
	"sub_cat_id": null,
	"id": null,
	"answer": "methods"
}, {
	"category_id": null,
	"question": "The range of _________ studied in organic chemistry include hydrocarbons (compounds containing only carbon and hydrogen), as well as myriad compositions based always on carbon, but also containing other elements,[1] [3] [4] especially oxygen, nitrogen, sulfur, phosphorus (these, included in many organic _________ in biology) and the radiostable elements of the halogens.",
	"topic_id": null,
	"sub_cat_id": null,
	"id": null,
	"answer": "chemicals"
}, {
	"category_id": null,
	"question": "The range of chemicals studied in organic chemistry include hydrocarbons (_________ containing only carbon and hydrogen), as well as myriad compositions based always on carbon, but also containing other elements,[1] [3] [4] especially oxygen, nitrogen, sulfur, phosphorus (these, included in many organic chemicals in biology) and the radiostable elements of the halogens.",
	"topic_id": null,
	"sub_cat_id": null,
	"id": null,
	"answer": "compounds"
}, {
	"category_id": null,
	"question": "The range of chemicals studied in organic chemistry include hydrocarbons (compounds containing only carbon and hydrogen), as well as ___________________ based always on carbon, but also containing other elements,[1] [3] [4] especially oxygen, nitrogen, sulfur, phosphorus (these, included in many organic chemicals in biology) and the radiostable elements of the halogens.",
	"topic_id": null,
	"sub_cat_id": null,
	"id": null,
	"answer": "myriad compositions"
}, {
	"category_id": null,
	"question": "In addition, much modern research focuses on organic chemistry involving further organometallics, including _______________, but especially the transition metals; (e.",
	"topic_id": null,
	"sub_cat_id": null,
	"id": null,
	"answer": "the lanthanides"
}, {
	"category_id": null,
	"question": "Finally, _________________ form the basis of all earthly life and constitute a significant part of human endeavors in chemistry.",
	"topic_id": null,
	"sub_cat_id": null,
	"id": null,
	"answer": "organic compounds"
}, {
	"category_id": null,
	"question": "Finally, ______________________ the basis of all earthly life and constitute a significant part of human endeavors in chemistry.",
	"topic_id": null,
	"sub_cat_id": null,
	"id": null,
	"answer": "organic compounds form"
}, {
	"category_id": null,
	"question": "They either form the basis of, or are important constituents of, many commercial products including _______________; petrochemicals and products made from them (including lubricants, solvents, etc.",
	"topic_id": null,
	"sub_cat_id": null,
	"id": null,
	"answer": "pharmaceuticals"
}, {
	"category_id": null,
	"question": "They either form the basis of, or are important constituents of, many commercial products including pharmaceuticals; ___________________________ made from them (including lubricants, solvents, etc.",
	"topic_id": null,
	"sub_cat_id": null,
	"id": null,
	"answer": "petrochemicals and products"
}, {
	"category_id": null,
	"question": "_________ illustrates all elements of current interest in modern organic and organometallic chemistry, indicating main group elements in orange, and transition metals and lanthanides (Lan) in grey.",
	"topic_id": null,
	"sub_cat_id": null,
	"id": null,
	"answer": "The table"
}, {
	"category_id": null,
	"question": "Before the nineteenth century, ________ generally believed that compounds obtained from living organisms were endowed with a vital force that distinguished them from inorganic compounds.",
	"topic_id": null,
	"sub_cat_id": null,
	"id": null,
	"answer": "chemists"
}, {
	"category_id": null,
	"question": "Before the nineteenth century, chemists generally believed that _________ obtained from living organisms were endowed with a vital force that distinguished them from inorganic _________.",
	"topic_id": null,
	"sub_cat_id": null,
	"id": null,
	"answer": "compounds"
}, {
	"category_id": null,
	"question": "Before the nineteenth century, chemists generally believed that compounds obtained from living organisms were endowed with _____________ that distinguished them from inorganic compounds.",
	"topic_id": null,
	"sub_cat_id": null,
	"id": null,
	"answer": "a vital force"
}, {
	"category_id": null,
	"question": "According to the concept of vitalism (vital force theory), ______________ was endowed with a \"vital force\".",
	"topic_id": null,
	"sub_cat_id": null,
	"id": null,
	"answer": "organic matter"
}, {
	"category_id": null,
	"question": "During the first half of the nineteenth century, some of the first systematic studies of organic compounds were reported.",
	"topic_id": null,
	"sub_cat_id": null,
	"id": null,
	"answer": "organic matter"
}, {
	"category_id": null,
	"question": "Around 1816 _______________ started a study of soaps made from various fats and alkalis.",
	"topic_id": null,
	"sub_cat_id": null,
	"id": null,
	"answer": "Michel Chevreul"
}, {
	"category_id": null,
	"question": "He separated ___________________ that, in combination with the alkali, produced the soap.",
	"topic_id": null,
	"sub_cat_id": null,
	"id": null,
	"answer": "the different acids"
}, {
	"category_id": null,
	"question": "Since these were all individual compounds, he demonstrated that it was possible to make _________________ in various fats (which traditionally come from organic sources), producing new compounds, without \"vital force\".",
	"topic_id": null,
	"sub_cat_id": null,
	"id": null,
	"answer": "a chemical change"
}, {
	"category_id": null,
	"question": "Since these were all individual compounds, he demonstrated that it was possible to make a chemical change in ____________ (which traditionally come from organic sources), producing new compounds, without \"vital force\".",
	"topic_id": null,
	"sub_cat_id": null,
	"id": null,
	"answer": "various fats"
}, {
	"category_id": null,
	"question": "Although ______ was always cautious about claiming that he had disproved the theory of vital force, this event has often been thought of as a turning point.",
	"topic_id": null,
	"sub_cat_id": null,
	"id": null,
	"answer": "W\u00f6hler"
}, {
	"category_id": null,
	"question": "Although W\u00f6hler was always cautious about claiming that he had disproved the theory of vital force, __________ has often been thought of as a turning point.",
	"topic_id": null,
	"sub_cat_id": null,
	"id": null,
	"answer": "this event"
}, {
	"category_id": null,
	"question": "In 1856 William Henry Perkin, while trying to manufacture quinine, accidentally manufactured _______________ now known as Perkin's mauve.",
	"topic_id": null,
	"sub_cat_id": null,
	"id": null,
	"answer": "the organic dye"
}, {
	"category_id": null,
	"question": "Through its great financial success, this discovery greatly increased ________ in organic chemistry.",
	"topic_id": null,
	"sub_cat_id": null,
	"id": null,
	"answer": "interest"
}, {
	"category_id": null,
	"question": "_________ is a branch of physical science that studies the composition, structure, properties and change of matter.",
	"topic_id": null,
	"sub_cat_id": null,
	"id": null,
	"answer": "Chemistry"
}, {
	"category_id": null,
	"question": "_________ includes topics such as the properties of individual atoms, how atoms form chemical bonds to create chemical compounds, the interactions of substances through intermolecular forces that give matter its general properties, and the interactions between substances through chemical reactions to form different substances.",
	"topic_id": null,
	"sub_cat_id": null,
	"id": null,
	"answer": "Chemistry"
}, {
	"category_id": null,
	"question": "_________ is sometimes called the central science because it bridges other natural sciences, including physics, geology and biology.",
	"topic_id": null,
	"sub_cat_id": null,
	"id": null,
	"answer": "Chemistry"
}, {
	"category_id": null,
	"question": "For the differences between chemistry and physics see comparison of chemistry and physics.",
	"topic_id": null,
	"sub_cat_id": null,
	"id": null,
	"answer": "Chemistry"
}, {
	"category_id": null,
	"question": "The history of chemistry can be traced to _______, which had been practiced for several millennia in various parts of the world.",
	"topic_id": null,
	"sub_cat_id": null,
	"id": null,
	"answer": "alchemy"
}, {
	"category_id": null,
	"question": "__________________ comes from the word alchemy which was an earlier set of practices that encompassed elements of chemistry, metallurgy, philosophy, astrology, astronomy, mysticism and medicine.",
	"topic_id": null,
	"sub_cat_id": null,
	"id": null,
	"answer": "The word chemistry"
}, {
	"category_id": null,
	"question": "It is often seen as linked to the quest to turn lead or another common starting material into gold.",
	"topic_id": null,
	"sub_cat_id": null,
	"id": null,
	"answer": "Alchemy"
}, {
	"category_id": null,
	"question": "_______, which was practiced around 330, is the study of the composition of waters, movement, growth, embodying, disembodying, drawing the spirits from bodies and bonding the spirits within bodies (Zosimos).",
	"topic_id": null,
	"sub_cat_id": null,
	"id": null,
	"answer": "Alchemy"
}, {
	"category_id": null,
	"question": "An alchemist was called a 'chemist' in popular speech, and later the suffix \"-ry\" was added to this to describe the art of the chemist as \"chemistry\".",
	"topic_id": null,
	"sub_cat_id": null,
	"id": null,
	"answer": "Alchemy"
}, {
	"category_id": null,
	"question": "Alchemy, which was practiced around 330, is the study of the composition of waters, movement, growth, embodying, disembodying, drawing the spirits from bodies and bonding the spirits within bodies (Zosimos).",
	"topic_id": null,
	"sub_cat_id": null,
	"id": null,
	"answer": "gold.[6] Alchemy"
}, {
	"category_id": null,
	"question": "In origin, ________ is borrowed from the Greek \u03c7\u03b7\u03bc\u03af\u03b1 or \u03c7\u03b7\u03bc\u03b5\u03af\u03b1.",
	"topic_id": null,
	"sub_cat_id": null,
	"id": null,
	"answer": "the term"
}, {
	"category_id": null,
	"question": "This may have Egyptian origins since al-k\u012bm\u012b\u0101 is derived from the Greek \u03c7\u03b7\u03bc\u03af\u03b1, which is in turn derived from the word Chemi or Kimi, which is the ancient name of Egypt in Egyptian.",
	"topic_id": null,
	"sub_cat_id": null,
	"id": null,
	"answer": "the term"
}, {
	"category_id": null,
	"question": "Alternately, al-k\u012bm\u012b\u0101 may derive from \u03c7\u03b7\u03bc\u03b5\u03af\u03b1, meaning \"cast together\".",
	"topic_id": null,
	"sub_cat_id": null,
	"id": null,
	"answer": "the term"
}, {
	"category_id": null,
	"question": "In origin, the term is borrowed from the Greek \u03c7\u03b7\u03bc\u03af\u03b1 or \u03c7\u03b7\u03bc\u03b5\u03af\u03b1.",
	"topic_id": null,
	"sub_cat_id": null,
	"id": null,
	"answer": "al-k\u012bm\u012b\u0101"
}, {
	"category_id": null,
	"question": "This may have Egyptian origins since ________ is derived from the Greek \u03c7\u03b7\u03bc\u03af\u03b1, which is in turn derived from the word Chemi or Kimi, which is the ancient name of Egypt in Egyptian.",
	"topic_id": null,
	"sub_cat_id": null,
	"id": null,
	"answer": "al-k\u012bm\u012b\u0101"
}, {
	"category_id": null,
	"question": "Alternately, ________ may derive from \u03c7\u03b7\u03bc\u03b5\u03af\u03b1, meaning \"cast together\".",
	"topic_id": null,
	"sub_cat_id": null,
	"id": null,
	"answer": "al-k\u012bm\u012b\u0101"
}, {
	"category_id": null,
	"question": "In origin, the term is borrowed from _______________ or \u03c7\u03b7\u03bc\u03b5\u03af\u03b1.",
	"topic_id": null,
	"sub_cat_id": null,
	"id": null,
	"answer": "the Greek \u03c7\u03b7\u03bc\u03af\u03b1"
}, {
	"category_id": null,
	"question": "This may have Egyptian origins since al-k\u012bm\u012b\u0101 is derived from _______________, which is in turn derived from the word Chemi or Kimi, which is the ancient name of Egypt in Egyptian.",
	"topic_id": null,
	"sub_cat_id": null,
	"id": null,
	"answer": "the Greek \u03c7\u03b7\u03bc\u03af\u03b1"
}, {
	"category_id": null,
	"question": "______________________________ was later adopted by Epicurus (341\u2013270 BCE).",
	"topic_id": null,
	"sub_cat_id": null,
	"id": null,
	"answer": "Democritus' atomist philosophy"
}, {
	"category_id": null,
	"question": "A basic chemical hypothesis first emerged in Classical Greece with the theory of four elements as propounded definitively by _________ stating that that fire, air, earth and water were the fundamental elements from which everything is formed as a combination.",
	"topic_id": null,
	"sub_cat_id": null,
	"id": null,
	"answer": "Aristotle"
}, {
	"category_id": null,
	"question": "Greek atomism dates back to ______, arising in works by philosophers such as Democritus and Epicurus.",
	"topic_id": null,
	"sub_cat_id": null,
	"id": null,
	"answer": "440 BC"
}, {
	"category_id": null,
	"question": "In 50 BC, the Roman philosopher Lucretius expanded upon the theory in his book De rerum natura (On The Nature of Things).",
	"topic_id": null,
	"sub_cat_id": null,
	"id": null,
	"answer": "Greek atomism"
}, {
	"category_id": null,
	"question": "Unlike modern concepts of science, _____________ was purely philosophical in nature, with little concern for empirical observations and no concern for chemical experiments.",
	"topic_id": null,
	"sub_cat_id": null,
	"id": null,
	"answer": "Greek atomism"
}, {
	"category_id": null,
	"question": "In the Hellenistic world the art of alchemy first proliferated, mingling magic and occultism into the study of natural substances with the ultimate goal of transmuting ________ into gold and discovering the elixir of eternal life.",
	"topic_id": null,
	"sub_cat_id": null,
	"id": null,
	"answer": "elements"
}, {
	"category_id": null,
	"question": "Alchemy was discovered and practised widely throughout the Arab world after the Muslim conquests,[23] and from there, diffused into medieval and Renaissance Europe through Latin translations.",
	"topic_id": null,
	"sub_cat_id": null,
	"id": null,
	"answer": "elements"
}, {
	"category_id": null,
	"question": "In the Hellenistic world the art of alchemy first proliferated, mingling magic and occultism into the study of natural substances with the ultimate goal of transmuting elements into gold and discovering the elixir of eternal life.",
	"topic_id": null,
	"sub_cat_id": null,
	"id": null,
	"answer": "Alchemy"
}, {
	"category_id": null,
	"question": "_______ was discovered and practised widely throughout the Arab world after the Muslim conquests,[23] and from there, diffused into medieval and Renaissance Europe through Latin translations.",
	"topic_id": null,
	"sub_cat_id": null,
	"id": null,
	"answer": "Alchemy"
}, {
	"category_id": null,
	"question": "___________________ is regarded as the founding father of chemistry due to his most important work, the classic chemistry text The Sceptical Chymist where the differentiation is made between the claims of alchemy and the empirical scientific discoveries of the new chemistry.",
	"topic_id": null,
	"sub_cat_id": null,
	"id": null,
	"answer": "Boyle in particular"
}, {
	"category_id": null,
	"question": "He formulated Boyle's law, rejected the classical \"four elements\" and proposed a mechanistic alternative of atoms and chemical reactions that could be subject to rigorous experiment.",
	"topic_id": null,
	"sub_cat_id": null,
	"id": null,
	"answer": "Boyle in particular"
}, {
	"category_id": null,
	"question": "Boyle in particular is regarded as the founding ______ of chemistry due to his most important work, the classic chemistry text The Sceptical Chymist where the differentiation is made between the claims of alchemy and the empirical scientific discoveries of the new chemistry.",
	"topic_id": null,
	"sub_cat_id": null,
	"id": null,
	"answer": "father"
}, {
	"category_id": null,
	"question": "Boyle in particular is regarded as the founding father of chemistry due to his most important work, the classic chemistry text The Sceptical Chymist where ___________________ is made between the claims of alchemy and the empirical scientific discoveries of the new chemistry.",
	"topic_id": null,
	"sub_cat_id": null,
	"id": null,
	"answer": "the differentiation"
}, {
	"category_id": null,
	"question": "_____________ in line-angle representation, showing four carbon-hydrogen single (\u03c3) bonds in black, and the 3D shape of such tetrahedral molecules, with ~109\u00b0 interior bond angles, in green.",
	"topic_id": null,
	"sub_cat_id": null,
	"id": null,
	"answer": "Methane, CH4,"
}, {
	"category_id": null,
	"question": "_______ is the simplest organic chemical and simplest hydrocarbon, and molecules can be built up conceptually from it by exchanging up to all 4 hydrogens with carbon or other atoms.",
	"topic_id": null,
	"sub_cat_id": null,
	"id": null,
	"answer": "Methane"
}, {
	"category_id": null,
	"question": "_________________ is a chemistry subdiscipline involving the scientific study of the structure, properties, and reactions of organic compounds and organic materials, i.",
	"topic_id": null,
	"sub_cat_id": null,
	"id": null,
	"answer": "Organic chemistry"
}, {
	"category_id": null,
	"question": "Study of structure includes many physical and chemical methods to determine the chemical composition and the chemical constitution of organic compounds and materials.",
	"topic_id": null,
	"sub_cat_id": null,
	"id": null,
	"answer": "Organic chemistry"
}, {
	"category_id": null,
	"question": "Organic chemistry is a chemistry subdiscipline involving the scientific study of the structure, properties, and reactions of organic compounds and organic materials, i.",
	"topic_id": null,
	"sub_cat_id": null,
	"id": null,
	"answer": "its various forms"
}, {
	"category_id": null,
	"question": "_____ of properties includes both physical properties and chemical properties, and uses similar methods as well as methods to evaluate chemical reactivity, with the aim to understand the behavior of the organic matter in its pure form (when possible), but also in solutions, mixtures, and fabricated forms.",
	"topic_id": null,
	"sub_cat_id": null,
	"id": null,
	"answer": "Study"
}, {
	"category_id": null,
	"question": "Study of properties includes both physical properties and chemical properties, and uses similar _______ as well as _______ to evaluate chemical reactivity, with the aim to understand the behavior of the organic matter in its pure form (when possible), but also in solutions, mixtures, and fabricated forms.",
	"topic_id": null,
	"sub_cat_id": null,
	"id": null,
	"answer": "methods"
}, {
	"category_id": null,
	"question": "The range of _________ studied in organic chemistry include hydrocarbons (compounds containing only carbon and hydrogen), as well as myriad compositions based always on carbon, but also containing other elements,[1] [3] [4] especially oxygen, nitrogen, sulfur, phosphorus (these, included in many organic _________ in biology) and the radiostable elements of the halogens.",
	"topic_id": null,
	"sub_cat_id": null,
	"id": null,
	"answer": "chemicals"
}, {
	"category_id": null,
	"question": "The range of chemicals studied in organic chemistry include hydrocarbons (_________ containing only carbon and hydrogen), as well as myriad compositions based always on carbon, but also containing other elements,[1] [3] [4] especially oxygen, nitrogen, sulfur, phosphorus (these, included in many organic chemicals in biology) and the radiostable elements of the halogens.",
	"topic_id": null,
	"sub_cat_id": null,
	"id": null,
	"answer": "compounds"
}, {
	"category_id": null,
	"question": "The range of chemicals studied in organic chemistry include hydrocarbons (compounds containing only carbon and hydrogen), as well as ___________________ based always on carbon, but also containing other elements,[1] [3] [4] especially oxygen, nitrogen, sulfur, phosphorus (these, included in many organic chemicals in biology) and the radiostable elements of the halogens.",
	"topic_id": null,
	"sub_cat_id": null,
	"id": null,
	"answer": "myriad compositions"
}, {
	"category_id": null,
	"question": "In addition, much modern research focuses on organic chemistry involving further organometallics, including _______________, but especially the transition metals; (e.",
	"topic_id": null,
	"sub_cat_id": null,
	"id": null,
	"answer": "the lanthanides"
}, {
	"category_id": null,
	"question": "Finally, _________________ form the basis of all earthly life and constitute a significant part of human endeavors in chemistry.",
	"topic_id": null,
	"sub_cat_id": null,
	"id": null,
	"answer": "organic compounds"
}, {
	"category_id": null,
	"question": "Finally, ______________________ the basis of all earthly life and constitute a significant part of human endeavors in chemistry.",
	"topic_id": null,
	"sub_cat_id": null,
	"id": null,
	"answer": "organic compounds form"
}, {
	"category_id": null,
	"question": "They either form the basis of, or are important constituents of, many commercial products including _______________; petrochemicals and products made from them (including lubricants, solvents, etc.",
	"topic_id": null,
	"sub_cat_id": null,
	"id": null,
	"answer": "pharmaceuticals"
}, {
	"category_id": null,
	"question": "They either form the basis of, or are important constituents of, many commercial products including pharmaceuticals; ___________________________ made from them (including lubricants, solvents, etc.",
	"topic_id": null,
	"sub_cat_id": null,
	"id": null,
	"answer": "petrochemicals and products"
}, {
	"category_id": null,
	"question": "_________ illustrates all elements of current interest in modern organic and organometallic chemistry, indicating main group elements in orange, and transition metals and lanthanides (Lan) in grey.",
	"topic_id": null,
	"sub_cat_id": null,
	"id": null,
	"answer": "The table"
}, {
	"category_id": null,
	"question": "Before the nineteenth century, ________ generally believed that compounds obtained from living organisms were endowed with a vital force that distinguished them from inorganic compounds.",
	"topic_id": null,
	"sub_cat_id": null,
	"id": null,
	"answer": "chemists"
}, {
	"category_id": null,
	"question": "Before the nineteenth century, chemists generally believed that _________ obtained from living organisms were endowed with a vital force that distinguished them from inorganic _________.",
	"topic_id": null,
	"sub_cat_id": null,
	"id": null,
	"answer": "compounds"
}, {
	"category_id": null,
	"question": "Before the nineteenth century, chemists generally believed that compounds obtained from living organisms were endowed with _____________ that distinguished them from inorganic compounds.",
	"topic_id": null,
	"sub_cat_id": null,
	"id": null,
	"answer": "a vital force"
}, {
	"category_id": null,
	"question": "According to the concept of vitalism (vital force theory), ______________ was endowed with a \"vital force\".",
	"topic_id": null,
	"sub_cat_id": null,
	"id": null,
	"answer": "organic matter"
}, {
	"category_id": null,
	"question": "During the first half of the nineteenth century, some of the first systematic studies of organic compounds were reported.",
	"topic_id": null,
	"sub_cat_id": null,
	"id": null,
	"answer": "organic matter"
}, {
	"category_id": null,
	"question": "Around 1816 _______________ started a study of soaps made from various fats and alkalis.",
	"topic_id": null,
	"sub_cat_id": null,
	"id": null,
	"answer": "Michel Chevreul"
}, {
	"category_id": null,
	"question": "He separated ___________________ that, in combination with the alkali, produced the soap.",
	"topic_id": null,
	"sub_cat_id": null,
	"id": null,
	"answer": "the different acids"
}, {
	"category_id": null,
	"question": "Since these were all individual compounds, he demonstrated that it was possible to make _________________ in various fats (which traditionally come from organic sources), producing new compounds, without \"vital force\".",
	"topic_id": null,
	"sub_cat_id": null,
	"id": null,
	"answer": "a chemical change"
}, {
	"category_id": null,
	"question": "Since these were all individual compounds, he demonstrated that it was possible to make a chemical change in ____________ (which traditionally come from organic sources), producing new compounds, without \"vital force\".",
	"topic_id": null,
	"sub_cat_id": null,
	"id": null,
	"answer": "various fats"
}, {
	"category_id": null,
	"question": "Although ______ was always cautious about claiming that he had disproved the theory of vital force, this event has often been thought of as a turning point.",
	"topic_id": null,
	"sub_cat_id": null,
	"id": null,
	"answer": "W\u00f6hler"
}, {
	"category_id": null,
	"question": "Although W\u00f6hler was always cautious about claiming that he had disproved the theory of vital force, __________ has often been thought of as a turning point.",
	"topic_id": null,
	"sub_cat_id": null,
	"id": null,
	"answer": "this event"
}, {
	"category_id": null,
	"question": "In 1856 William Henry Perkin, while trying to manufacture quinine, accidentally manufactured _______________ now known as Perkin's mauve.",
	"topic_id": null,
	"sub_cat_id": null,
	"id": null,
	"answer": "the organic dye"
}, {
	"category_id": null,
	"question": "Through its great financial success, this discovery greatly increased ________ in organic chemistry.",
	"topic_id": null,
	"sub_cat_id": null,
	"id": null,
	"answer": "interest"
}, {
	"category_id": null,
	"question": "__________________ is the study of macroscopic, atomic, subatomic, and particulate phenomena in chemical systems in terms of laws and concepts of physics.",
	"topic_id": null,
	"sub_cat_id": null,
	"id": null,
	"answer": "Physical chemistry"
}, {
	"category_id": null,
	"question": "Physical chemistry is the study of macroscopic, atomic, subatomic, and particulate _________ in chemical systems in terms of laws and concepts of physics.",
	"topic_id": null,
	"sub_cat_id": null,
	"id": null,
	"answer": "phenomena"
}, {
	"category_id": null,
	"question": "The key concepts of physical chemistry are the ways in which ____________ is applied to chemical problems.",
	"topic_id": null,
	"sub_cat_id": null,
	"id": null,
	"answer": "pure physics"
}, {
	"category_id": null,
	"question": "One of the key concepts in classical chemistry is that ______________________ can be described as groups of atoms bonded together and chemical reactions can be described as the making and breaking of those bonds.",
	"topic_id": null,
	"sub_cat_id": null,
	"id": null,
	"answer": "all chemical compounds"
}, {
	"category_id": null,
	"question": "Quantum chemistry, a subfield of physical chemistry especially concerned with the application of quantum mechanics to chemical problems, provides _____ to determine how strong and what shape bonds are,[2] how nuclei move, and how light can be absorbed or emitted by a chemical compound.",
	"topic_id": null,
	"sub_cat_id": null,
	"id": null,
	"answer": "tools"
}, {
	"category_id": null,
	"question": "Spectroscopy is the related sub-discipline of physical chemistry which is specifically concerned with the interaction of electromagnetic radiation with matter.",
	"topic_id": null,
	"sub_cat_id": null,
	"id": null,
	"answer": "tools"
}, {
	"category_id": null,
	"question": "Quantum chemistry, a subfield of physical chemistry especially concerned with the application of quantum mechanics to chemical problems, provides tools to determine how strong and what shape bonds are,[2] how nuclei move, and _________ can be absorbed or emitted by a chemical compound.",
	"topic_id": null,
	"sub_cat_id": null,
	"id": null,
	"answer": "how light"
}, {
	"category_id": null,
	"question": "Quantum chemistry, a subfield of physical chemistry especially concerned with the application of quantum mechanics to chemical problems, provides tools to determine how strong and what shape bonds are,[2] how nuclei move, and how light can be absorbed or emitted by a chemical compound.",
	"topic_id": null,
	"sub_cat_id": null,
	"id": null,
	"answer": "Spectroscopy"
}, {
	"category_id": null,
	"question": "____________ is the related sub-discipline of physical chemistry which is specifically concerned with the interaction of electromagnetic radiation with matter.",
	"topic_id": null,
	"sub_cat_id": null,
	"id": null,
	"answer": "Spectroscopy"
}, {
	"category_id": null,
	"question": "Another set of important questions in chemistry concerns what _________________ can happen spontaneously and which properties are possible for a given chemical mixture.",
	"topic_id": null,
	"sub_cat_id": null,
	"id": null,
	"answer": "kind of reactions"
}, {
	"category_id": null,
	"question": "Another set of important questions in chemistry concerns what kind of reactions can happen spontaneously and which __________ are possible for a given chemical mixture.",
	"topic_id": null,
	"sub_cat_id": null,
	"id": null,
	"answer": "properties"
}, {
	"category_id": null,
	"question": "This is studied in _______________________, which sets limits on quantities like how far a reaction can proceed, or how much energy can be converted into work in an internal combustion engine, and which provides links between properties like the thermal expansion coefficient and rate of change of entropy with pressure for a gas or a liquid.",
	"topic_id": null,
	"sub_cat_id": null,
	"id": null,
	"answer": "chemical thermodynamics"
}, {
	"category_id": null,
	"question": "It can frequently be used to assess whether a reactor or engine design is feasible, or to check the validity of experimental data.",
	"topic_id": null,
	"sub_cat_id": null,
	"id": null,
	"answer": "chemical thermodynamics"
}, {
	"category_id": null,
	"question": "This is studied in chemical thermodynamics, which sets limits on quantities like how far a reaction can proceed, or how ___________ can be converted into work in an internal combustion engine, and which provides links between properties like the thermal expansion coefficient and rate of change of entropy with pressure for a gas or a liquid.",
	"topic_id": null,
	"sub_cat_id": null,
	"id": null,
	"answer": "much energy"
}, {
	"category_id": null,
	"question": "To a limited extent, quasi-equilibrium and non-equilibrium thermodynamics can describe irreversible changes.",
	"topic_id": null,
	"sub_cat_id": null,
	"id": null,
	"answer": "classical thermodynamics"
}, {
	"category_id": null,
	"question": "However, ________________________ is mostly concerned with systems in equilibrium and reversible changes and not what actually does happen, or how fast, away from equilibrium.",
	"topic_id": null,
	"sub_cat_id": null,
	"id": null,
	"answer": "classical thermodynamics"
}, {
	"category_id": null,
	"question": "A key idea in chemical kinetics is that for _________ to react and form products, most chemical species must go through transition states which are higher in energy than either the _________ or the products and serve as a barrier to reaction.",
	"topic_id": null,
	"sub_cat_id": null,
	"id": null,
	"answer": "reactants"
}, {
	"category_id": null,
	"question": "In general, the higher the barrier, the slower the reaction.",
	"topic_id": null,
	"sub_cat_id": null,
	"id": null,
	"answer": "reactants"
}, {
	"category_id": null,
	"question": "A key idea in chemical kinetics is that for reactants to react and form products, _____________________ must go through transition states which are higher in energy than either the reactants or the products and serve as a barrier to reaction.",
	"topic_id": null,
	"sub_cat_id": null,
	"id": null,
	"answer": "most chemical species"
}, {
	"category_id": null,
	"question": "_____________________ also provides ways to predict the properties we see in everyday life from molecular properties without relying on empirical correlations based on chemical similarities.",
	"topic_id": null,
	"sub_cat_id": null,
	"id": null,
	"answer": "Statistical mechanics"
}, {
	"category_id": null,
	"question": "The term \"physical chemistry\" was coined ____________________ in 1752, when he presented a lecture course entitled \"A Course in True Physical Chemistry\" (Russian: \u00ab\u041a\u0443\u0440\u0441 \u0438\u0441\u0442\u0438\u043d\u043d\u043e\u0439 \u0444\u0438\u0437\u0438\u0447\u0435\u0441\u043a\u043e\u0439 \u0445\u0438\u043c\u0438\u0438\u00bb) before the students of Petersburg University.",
	"topic_id": null,
	"sub_cat_id": null,
	"id": null,
	"answer": "by Mikhail Lomonosov"
}, {
	"category_id": null,
	"question": "In the preamble to these lectures he gives definition: \"Physical chemistry is the science that must explain under provisions of physical experiments the reason for what is happening in complex bodies through chemical operations\".",
	"topic_id": null,
	"sub_cat_id": null,
	"id": null,
	"answer": "by Mikhail Lomonosov"
}, {
	"category_id": null,
	"question": "The term \"physical chemistry\" was coined by Mikhail Lomonosov in 1752, when he presented a lecture course entitled \"A Course in True Physical Chemistry\" (Russian: \u00ab\u041a\u0443\u0440\u0441 \u0438\u0441\u0442\u0438\u043d\u043d\u043e\u0439 \u0444\u0438\u0437\u0438\u0447\u0435\u0441\u043a\u043e\u0439 \u0445\u0438\u043c\u0438\u0438\u00bb) before the students of Petersburg University.",
	"topic_id": null,
	"sub_cat_id": null,
	"id": null,
	"answer": "Physical chemistry"
}, {
	"category_id": null,
	"question": "In the preamble to these lectures he gives definition: \"__________________ is the science that must explain under provisions of physical experiments the reason for what is happening in complex bodies through chemical operations\".",
	"topic_id": null,
	"sub_cat_id": null,
	"id": null,
	"answer": "Physical chemistry"
}, {
	"category_id": null,
	"question": "In the preamble to these lectures he gives definition: \"Physical chemistry is ___________ that must explain under provisions of physical experiments the reason for what is happening in complex bodies through chemical operations\".",
	"topic_id": null,
	"sub_cat_id": null,
	"id": null,
	"answer": "the science"
}, {
	"category_id": null,
	"question": "_________________________ originated in the 1860s to 1880s with work on chemical thermodynamics, electrolytes in solutions, chemical kinetics and other subjects.",
	"topic_id": null,
	"sub_cat_id": null,
	"id": null,
	"answer": "Modern physical chemistry"
}, {
	"category_id": null,
	"question": "_____________ was the publication in 1876 by Josiah Willard Gibbs of his paper, On the Equilibrium of Heterogeneous Substances.",
	"topic_id": null,
	"sub_cat_id": null,
	"id": null,
	"answer": "One milestone"
}, {
	"category_id": null,
	"question": "_________ is a branch of physical science that studies the composition, structure, properties and change of matter.",
	"topic_id": null,
	"sub_cat_id": null,
	"id": null,
	"answer": "Chemistry"
}, {
	"category_id": null,
	"question": "_________ includes topics such as the properties of individual atoms, how atoms form chemical bonds to create chemical compounds, the interactions of substances through intermolecular forces that give matter its general properties, and the interactions between substances through chemical reactions to form different substances.",
	"topic_id": null,
	"sub_cat_id": null,
	"id": null,
	"answer": "Chemistry"
}, {
	"category_id": null,
	"question": "_________ is sometimes called the central science because it bridges other natural sciences, including physics, geology and biology.",
	"topic_id": null,
	"sub_cat_id": null,
	"id": null,
	"answer": "Chemistry"
}, {
	"category_id": null,
	"question": "For the differences between chemistry and physics see comparison of chemistry and physics.",
	"topic_id": null,
	"sub_cat_id": null,
	"id": null,
	"answer": "Chemistry"
}, {
	"category_id": null,
	"question": "The history of chemistry can be traced to _______, which had been practiced for several millennia in various parts of the world.",
	"topic_id": null,
	"sub_cat_id": null,
	"id": null,
	"answer": "alchemy"
}, {
	"category_id": null,
	"question": "__________________ comes from the word alchemy which was an earlier set of practices that encompassed elements of chemistry, metallurgy, philosophy, astrology, astronomy, mysticism and medicine.",
	"topic_id": null,
	"sub_cat_id": null,
	"id": null,
	"answer": "The word chemistry"
}, {
	"category_id": null,
	"question": "It is often seen as linked to the quest to turn lead or another common starting material into gold.",
	"topic_id": null,
	"sub_cat_id": null,
	"id": null,
	"answer": "Alchemy"
}, {
	"category_id": null,
	"question": "_______, which was practiced around 330, is the study of the composition of waters, movement, growth, embodying, disembodying, drawing the spirits from bodies and bonding the spirits within bodies (Zosimos).",
	"topic_id": null,
	"sub_cat_id": null,
	"id": null,
	"answer": "Alchemy"
}, {
	"category_id": null,
	"question": "An alchemist was called a 'chemist' in popular speech, and later the suffix \"-ry\" was added to this to describe the art of the chemist as \"chemistry\".",
	"topic_id": null,
	"sub_cat_id": null,
	"id": null,
	"answer": "Alchemy"
}, {
	"category_id": null,
	"question": "Alchemy, which was practiced around 330, is the study of the composition of waters, movement, growth, embodying, disembodying, drawing the spirits from bodies and bonding the spirits within bodies (Zosimos).",
	"topic_id": null,
	"sub_cat_id": null,
	"id": null,
	"answer": "gold.[6] Alchemy"
}, {
	"category_id": null,
	"question": "In origin, ________ is borrowed from the Greek \u03c7\u03b7\u03bc\u03af\u03b1 or \u03c7\u03b7\u03bc\u03b5\u03af\u03b1.",
	"topic_id": null,
	"sub_cat_id": null,
	"id": null,
	"answer": "the term"
}, {
	"category_id": null,
	"question": "This may have Egyptian origins since al-k\u012bm\u012b\u0101 is derived from the Greek \u03c7\u03b7\u03bc\u03af\u03b1, which is in turn derived from the word Chemi or Kimi, which is the ancient name of Egypt in Egyptian.",
	"topic_id": null,
	"sub_cat_id": null,
	"id": null,
	"answer": "the term"
}, {
	"category_id": null,
	"question": "Alternately, al-k\u012bm\u012b\u0101 may derive from \u03c7\u03b7\u03bc\u03b5\u03af\u03b1, meaning \"cast together\".",
	"topic_id": null,
	"sub_cat_id": null,
	"id": null,
	"answer": "the term"
}, {
	"category_id": null,
	"question": "In origin, the term is borrowed from the Greek \u03c7\u03b7\u03bc\u03af\u03b1 or \u03c7\u03b7\u03bc\u03b5\u03af\u03b1.",
	"topic_id": null,
	"sub_cat_id": null,
	"id": null,
	"answer": "al-k\u012bm\u012b\u0101"
}, {
	"category_id": null,
	"question": "This may have Egyptian origins since ________ is derived from the Greek \u03c7\u03b7\u03bc\u03af\u03b1, which is in turn derived from the word Chemi or Kimi, which is the ancient name of Egypt in Egyptian.",
	"topic_id": null,
	"sub_cat_id": null,
	"id": null,
	"answer": "al-k\u012bm\u012b\u0101"
}, {
	"category_id": null,
	"question": "Alternately, ________ may derive from \u03c7\u03b7\u03bc\u03b5\u03af\u03b1, meaning \"cast together\".",
	"topic_id": null,
	"sub_cat_id": null,
	"id": null,
	"answer": "al-k\u012bm\u012b\u0101"
}, {
	"category_id": null,
	"question": "In origin, the term is borrowed from _______________ or \u03c7\u03b7\u03bc\u03b5\u03af\u03b1.",
	"topic_id": null,
	"sub_cat_id": null,
	"id": null,
	"answer": "the Greek \u03c7\u03b7\u03bc\u03af\u03b1"
}, {
	"category_id": null,
	"question": "This may have Egyptian origins since al-k\u012bm\u012b\u0101 is derived from _______________, which is in turn derived from the word Chemi or Kimi, which is the ancient name of Egypt in Egyptian.",
	"topic_id": null,
	"sub_cat_id": null,
	"id": null,
	"answer": "the Greek \u03c7\u03b7\u03bc\u03af\u03b1"
}, {
	"category_id": null,
	"question": "______________________________ was later adopted by Epicurus (341\u2013270 BCE).",
	"topic_id": null,
	"sub_cat_id": null,
	"id": null,
	"answer": "Democritus' atomist philosophy"
}, {
	"category_id": null,
	"question": "A basic chemical hypothesis first emerged in Classical Greece with the theory of four elements as propounded definitively by _________ stating that that fire, air, earth and water were the fundamental elements from which everything is formed as a combination.",
	"topic_id": null,
	"sub_cat_id": null,
	"id": null,
	"answer": "Aristotle"
}, {
	"category_id": null,
	"question": "Greek atomism dates back to ______, arising in works by philosophers such as Democritus and Epicurus.",
	"topic_id": null,
	"sub_cat_id": null,
	"id": null,
	"answer": "440 BC"
}, {
	"category_id": null,
	"question": "In 50 BC, the Roman philosopher Lucretius expanded upon the theory in his book De rerum natura (On The Nature of Things).",
	"topic_id": null,
	"sub_cat_id": null,
	"id": null,
	"answer": "Greek atomism"
}, {
	"category_id": null,
	"question": "Unlike modern concepts of science, _____________ was purely philosophical in nature, with little concern for empirical observations and no concern for chemical experiments.",
	"topic_id": null,
	"sub_cat_id": null,
	"id": null,
	"answer": "Greek atomism"
}, {
	"category_id": null,
	"question": "In the Hellenistic world the art of alchemy first proliferated, mingling magic and occultism into the study of natural substances with the ultimate goal of transmuting ________ into gold and discovering the elixir of eternal life.",
	"topic_id": null,
	"sub_cat_id": null,
	"id": null,
	"answer": "elements"
}, {
	"category_id": null,
	"question": "Alchemy was discovered and practised widely throughout the Arab world after the Muslim conquests,[23] and from there, diffused into medieval and Renaissance Europe through Latin translations.",
	"topic_id": null,
	"sub_cat_id": null,
	"id": null,
	"answer": "elements"
}, {
	"category_id": null,
	"question": "In the Hellenistic world the art of alchemy first proliferated, mingling magic and occultism into the study of natural substances with the ultimate goal of transmuting elements into gold and discovering the elixir of eternal life.",
	"topic_id": null,
	"sub_cat_id": null,
	"id": null,
	"answer": "Alchemy"
}, {
	"category_id": null,
	"question": "_______ was discovered and practised widely throughout the Arab world after the Muslim conquests,[23] and from there, diffused into medieval and Renaissance Europe through Latin translations.",
	"topic_id": null,
	"sub_cat_id": null,
	"id": null,
	"answer": "Alchemy"
}, {
	"category_id": null,
	"question": "___________________ is regarded as the founding father of chemistry due to his most important work, the classic chemistry text The Sceptical Chymist where the differentiation is made between the claims of alchemy and the empirical scientific discoveries of the new chemistry.",
	"topic_id": null,
	"sub_cat_id": null,
	"id": null,
	"answer": "Boyle in particular"
}, {
	"category_id": null,
	"question": "He formulated Boyle's law, rejected the classical \"four elements\" and proposed a mechanistic alternative of atoms and chemical reactions that could be subject to rigorous experiment.",
	"topic_id": null,
	"sub_cat_id": null,
	"id": null,
	"answer": "Boyle in particular"
}, {
	"category_id": null,
	"question": "Boyle in particular is regarded as the founding ______ of chemistry due to his most important work, the classic chemistry text The Sceptical Chymist where the differentiation is made between the claims of alchemy and the empirical scientific discoveries of the new chemistry.",
	"topic_id": null,
	"sub_cat_id": null,
	"id": null,
	"answer": "father"
}, {
	"category_id": null,
	"question": "Boyle in particular is regarded as the founding father of chemistry due to his most important work, the classic chemistry text The Sceptical Chymist where ___________________ is made between the claims of alchemy and the empirical scientific discoveries of the new chemistry.",
	"topic_id": null,
	"sub_cat_id": null,
	"id": null,
	"answer": "the differentiation"
}, {
	"category_id": null,
	"question": "_____________ in line-angle representation, showing four carbon-hydrogen single (\u03c3) bonds in black, and the 3D shape of such tetrahedral molecules, with ~109\u00b0 interior bond angles, in green.",
	"topic_id": null,
	"sub_cat_id": null,
	"id": null,
	"answer": "Methane, CH4,"
}, {
	"category_id": null,
	"question": "_______ is the simplest organic chemical and simplest hydrocarbon, and molecules can be built up conceptually from it by exchanging up to all 4 hydrogens with carbon or other atoms.",
	"topic_id": null,
	"sub_cat_id": null,
	"id": null,
	"answer": "Methane"
}, {
	"category_id": null,
	"question": "_________________ is a chemistry subdiscipline involving the scientific study of the structure, properties, and reactions of organic compounds and organic materials, i.",
	"topic_id": null,
	"sub_cat_id": null,
	"id": null,
	"answer": "Organic chemistry"
}, {
	"category_id": null,
	"question": "Study of structure includes many physical and chemical methods to determine the chemical composition and the chemical constitution of organic compounds and materials.",
	"topic_id": null,
	"sub_cat_id": null,
	"id": null,
	"answer": "Organic chemistry"
}, {
	"category_id": null,
	"question": "Organic chemistry is a chemistry subdiscipline involving the scientific study of the structure, properties, and reactions of organic compounds and organic materials, i.",
	"topic_id": null,
	"sub_cat_id": null,
	"id": null,
	"answer": "its various forms"
}, {
	"category_id": null,
	"question": "_____ of properties includes both physical properties and chemical properties, and uses similar methods as well as methods to evaluate chemical reactivity, with the aim to understand the behavior of the organic matter in its pure form (when possible), but also in solutions, mixtures, and fabricated forms.",
	"topic_id": null,
	"sub_cat_id": null,
	"id": null,
	"answer": "Study"
}, {
	"category_id": null,
	"question": "Study of properties includes both physical properties and chemical properties, and uses similar _______ as well as _______ to evaluate chemical reactivity, with the aim to understand the behavior of the organic matter in its pure form (when possible), but also in solutions, mixtures, and fabricated forms.",
	"topic_id": null,
	"sub_cat_id": null,
	"id": null,
	"answer": "methods"
}, {
	"category_id": null,
	"question": "The range of _________ studied in organic chemistry include hydrocarbons (compounds containing only carbon and hydrogen), as well as myriad compositions based always on carbon, but also containing other elements,[1] [3] [4] especially oxygen, nitrogen, sulfur, phosphorus (these, included in many organic _________ in biology) and the radiostable elements of the halogens.",
	"topic_id": null,
	"sub_cat_id": null,
	"id": null,
	"answer": "chemicals"
}, {
	"category_id": null,
	"question": "The range of chemicals studied in organic chemistry include hydrocarbons (_________ containing only carbon and hydrogen), as well as myriad compositions based always on carbon, but also containing other elements,[1] [3] [4] especially oxygen, nitrogen, sulfur, phosphorus (these, included in many organic chemicals in biology) and the radiostable elements of the halogens.",
	"topic_id": null,
	"sub_cat_id": null,
	"id": null,
	"answer": "compounds"
}, {
	"category_id": null,
	"question": "The range of chemicals studied in organic chemistry include hydrocarbons (compounds containing only carbon and hydrogen), as well as ___________________ based always on carbon, but also containing other elements,[1] [3] [4] especially oxygen, nitrogen, sulfur, phosphorus (these, included in many organic chemicals in biology) and the radiostable elements of the halogens.",
	"topic_id": null,
	"sub_cat_id": null,
	"id": null,
	"answer": "myriad compositions"
}, {
	"category_id": null,
	"question": "In addition, much modern research focuses on organic chemistry involving further organometallics, including _______________, but especially the transition metals; (e.",
	"topic_id": null,
	"sub_cat_id": null,
	"id": null,
	"answer": "the lanthanides"
}, {
	"category_id": null,
	"question": "Finally, _________________ form the basis of all earthly life and constitute a significant part of human endeavors in chemistry.",
	"topic_id": null,
	"sub_cat_id": null,
	"id": null,
	"answer": "organic compounds"
}, {
	"category_id": null,
	"question": "Finally, ______________________ the basis of all earthly life and constitute a significant part of human endeavors in chemistry.",
	"topic_id": null,
	"sub_cat_id": null,
	"id": null,
	"answer": "organic compounds form"
}, {
	"category_id": null,
	"question": "They either form the basis of, or are important constituents of, many commercial products including _______________; petrochemicals and products made from them (including lubricants, solvents, etc.",
	"topic_id": null,
	"sub_cat_id": null,
	"id": null,
	"answer": "pharmaceuticals"
}, {
	"category_id": null,
	"question": "They either form the basis of, or are important constituents of, many commercial products including pharmaceuticals; ___________________________ made from them (including lubricants, solvents, etc.",
	"topic_id": null,
	"sub_cat_id": null,
	"id": null,
	"answer": "petrochemicals and products"
}, {
	"category_id": null,
	"question": "_________ illustrates all elements of current interest in modern organic and organometallic chemistry, indicating main group elements in orange, and transition metals and lanthanides (Lan) in grey.",
	"topic_id": null,
	"sub_cat_id": null,
	"id": null,
	"answer": "The table"
}, {
	"category_id": null,
	"question": "Before the nineteenth century, ________ generally believed that compounds obtained from living organisms were endowed with a vital force that distinguished them from inorganic compounds.",
	"topic_id": null,
	"sub_cat_id": null,
	"id": null,
	"answer": "chemists"
}, {
	"category_id": null,
	"question": "Before the nineteenth century, chemists generally believed that _________ obtained from living organisms were endowed with a vital force that distinguished them from inorganic _________.",
	"topic_id": null,
	"sub_cat_id": null,
	"id": null,
	"answer": "compounds"
}, {
	"category_id": null,
	"question": "Before the nineteenth century, chemists generally believed that compounds obtained from living organisms were endowed with _____________ that distinguished them from inorganic compounds.",
	"topic_id": null,
	"sub_cat_id": null,
	"id": null,
	"answer": "a vital force"
}, {
	"category_id": null,
	"question": "According to the concept of vitalism (vital force theory), ______________ was endowed with a \"vital force\".",
	"topic_id": null,
	"sub_cat_id": null,
	"id": null,
	"answer": "organic matter"
}, {
	"category_id": null,
	"question": "During the first half of the nineteenth century, some of the first systematic studies of organic compounds were reported.",
	"topic_id": null,
	"sub_cat_id": null,
	"id": null,
	"answer": "organic matter"
}, {
	"category_id": null,
	"question": "Around 1816 _______________ started a study of soaps made from various fats and alkalis.",
	"topic_id": null,
	"sub_cat_id": null,
	"id": null,
	"answer": "Michel Chevreul"
}, {
	"category_id": null,
	"question": "He separated ___________________ that, in combination with the alkali, produced the soap.",
	"topic_id": null,
	"sub_cat_id": null,
	"id": null,
	"answer": "the different acids"
}, {
	"category_id": null,
	"question": "Since these were all individual compounds, he demonstrated that it was possible to make _________________ in various fats (which traditionally come from organic sources), producing new compounds, without \"vital force\".",
	"topic_id": null,
	"sub_cat_id": null,
	"id": null,
	"answer": "a chemical change"
}, {
	"category_id": null,
	"question": "Since these were all individual compounds, he demonstrated that it was possible to make a chemical change in ____________ (which traditionally come from organic sources), producing new compounds, without \"vital force\".",
	"topic_id": null,
	"sub_cat_id": null,
	"id": null,
	"answer": "various fats"
}, {
	"category_id": null,
	"question": "Although ______ was always cautious about claiming that he had disproved the theory of vital force, this event has often been thought of as a turning point.",
	"topic_id": null,
	"sub_cat_id": null,
	"id": null,
	"answer": "W\u00f6hler"
}, {
	"category_id": null,
	"question": "Although W\u00f6hler was always cautious about claiming that he had disproved the theory of vital force, __________ has often been thought of as a turning point.",
	"topic_id": null,
	"sub_cat_id": null,
	"id": null,
	"answer": "this event"
}, {
	"category_id": null,
	"question": "In 1856 William Henry Perkin, while trying to manufacture quinine, accidentally manufactured _______________ now known as Perkin's mauve.",
	"topic_id": null,
	"sub_cat_id": null,
	"id": null,
	"answer": "the organic dye"
}, {
	"category_id": null,
	"question": "Through its great financial success, this discovery greatly increased ________ in organic chemistry.",
	"topic_id": null,
	"sub_cat_id": null,
	"id": null,
	"answer": "interest"
}, {
	"category_id": null,
	"question": "__________________ is the study of macroscopic, atomic, subatomic, and particulate phenomena in chemical systems in terms of laws and concepts of physics.",
	"topic_id": null,
	"sub_cat_id": null,
	"id": null,
	"answer": "Physical chemistry"
}, {
	"category_id": null,
	"question": "Physical chemistry is the study of macroscopic, atomic, subatomic, and particulate _________ in chemical systems in terms of laws and concepts of physics.",
	"topic_id": null,
	"sub_cat_id": null,
	"id": null,
	"answer": "phenomena"
}, {
	"category_id": null,
	"question": "The key concepts of physical chemistry are the ways in which ____________ is applied to chemical problems.",
	"topic_id": null,
	"sub_cat_id": null,
	"id": null,
	"answer": "pure physics"
}, {
	"category_id": null,
	"question": "One of the key concepts in classical chemistry is that ______________________ can be described as groups of atoms bonded together and chemical reactions can be described as the making and breaking of those bonds.",
	"topic_id": null,
	"sub_cat_id": null,
	"id": null,
	"answer": "all chemical compounds"
}, {
	"category_id": null,
	"question": "Quantum chemistry, a subfield of physical chemistry especially concerned with the application of quantum mechanics to chemical problems, provides _____ to determine how strong and what shape bonds are,[2] how nuclei move, and how light can be absorbed or emitted by a chemical compound.",
	"topic_id": null,
	"sub_cat_id": null,
	"id": null,
	"answer": "tools"
}, {
	"category_id": null,
	"question": "Spectroscopy is the related sub-discipline of physical chemistry which is specifically concerned with the interaction of electromagnetic radiation with matter.",
	"topic_id": null,
	"sub_cat_id": null,
	"id": null,
	"answer": "tools"
}, {
	"category_id": null,
	"question": "Quantum chemistry, a subfield of physical chemistry especially concerned with the application of quantum mechanics to chemical problems, provides tools to determine how strong and what shape bonds are,[2] how nuclei move, and _________ can be absorbed or emitted by a chemical compound.",
	"topic_id": null,
	"sub_cat_id": null,
	"id": null,
	"answer": "how light"
}, {
	"category_id": null,
	"question": "Quantum chemistry, a subfield of physical chemistry especially concerned with the application of quantum mechanics to chemical problems, provides tools to determine how strong and what shape bonds are,[2] how nuclei move, and how light can be absorbed or emitted by a chemical compound.",
	"topic_id": null,
	"sub_cat_id": null,
	"id": null,
	"answer": "Spectroscopy"
}, {
	"category_id": null,
	"question": "____________ is the related sub-discipline of physical chemistry which is specifically concerned with the interaction of electromagnetic radiation with matter.",
	"topic_id": null,
	"sub_cat_id": null,
	"id": null,
	"answer": "Spectroscopy"
}, {
	"category_id": null,
	"question": "Another set of important questions in chemistry concerns what _________________ can happen spontaneously and which properties are possible for a given chemical mixture.",
	"topic_id": null,
	"sub_cat_id": null,
	"id": null,
	"answer": "kind of reactions"
}, {
	"category_id": null,
	"question": "Another set of important questions in chemistry concerns what kind of reactions can happen spontaneously and which __________ are possible for a given chemical mixture.",
	"topic_id": null,
	"sub_cat_id": null,
	"id": null,
	"answer": "properties"
}, {
	"category_id": null,
	"question": "This is studied in _______________________, which sets limits on quantities like how far a reaction can proceed, or how much energy can be converted into work in an internal combustion engine, and which provides links between properties like the thermal expansion coefficient and rate of change of entropy with pressure for a gas or a liquid.",
	"topic_id": null,
	"sub_cat_id": null,
	"id": null,
	"answer": "chemical thermodynamics"
}, {
	"category_id": null,
	"question": "It can frequently be used to assess whether a reactor or engine design is feasible, or to check the validity of experimental data.",
	"topic_id": null,
	"sub_cat_id": null,
	"id": null,
	"answer": "chemical thermodynamics"
}, {
	"category_id": null,
	"question": "This is studied in chemical thermodynamics, which sets limits on quantities like how far a reaction can proceed, or how ___________ can be converted into work in an internal combustion engine, and which provides links between properties like the thermal expansion coefficient and rate of change of entropy with pressure for a gas or a liquid.",
	"topic_id": null,
	"sub_cat_id": null,
	"id": null,
	"answer": "much energy"
}, {
	"category_id": null,
	"question": "To a limited extent, quasi-equilibrium and non-equilibrium thermodynamics can describe irreversible changes.",
	"topic_id": null,
	"sub_cat_id": null,
	"id": null,
	"answer": "classical thermodynamics"
}, {
	"category_id": null,
	"question": "However, ________________________ is mostly concerned with systems in equilibrium and reversible changes and not what actually does happen, or how fast, away from equilibrium.",
	"topic_id": null,
	"sub_cat_id": null,
	"id": null,
	"answer": "classical thermodynamics"
}, {
	"category_id": null,
	"question": "A key idea in chemical kinetics is that for _________ to react and form products, most chemical species must go through transition states which are higher in energy than either the _________ or the products and serve as a barrier to reaction.",
	"topic_id": null,
	"sub_cat_id": null,
	"id": null,
	"answer": "reactants"
}, {
	"category_id": null,
	"question": "In general, the higher the barrier, the slower the reaction.",
	"topic_id": null,
	"sub_cat_id": null,
	"id": null,
	"answer": "reactants"
}, {
	"category_id": null,
	"question": "A key idea in chemical kinetics is that for reactants to react and form products, _____________________ must go through transition states which are higher in energy than either the reactants or the products and serve as a barrier to reaction.",
	"topic_id": null,
	"sub_cat_id": null,
	"id": null,
	"answer": "most chemical species"
}, {
	"category_id": null,
	"question": "_____________________ also provides ways to predict the properties we see in everyday life from molecular properties without relying on empirical correlations based on chemical similarities.",
	"topic_id": null,
	"sub_cat_id": null,
	"id": null,
	"answer": "Statistical mechanics"
}, {
	"category_id": null,
	"question": "The term \"physical chemistry\" was coined ____________________ in 1752, when he presented a lecture course entitled \"A Course in True Physical Chemistry\" (Russian: \u00ab\u041a\u0443\u0440\u0441 \u0438\u0441\u0442\u0438\u043d\u043d\u043e\u0439 \u0444\u0438\u0437\u0438\u0447\u0435\u0441\u043a\u043e\u0439 \u0445\u0438\u043c\u0438\u0438\u00bb) before the students of Petersburg University.",
	"topic_id": null,
	"sub_cat_id": null,
	"id": null,
	"answer": "by Mikhail Lomonosov"
}, {
	"category_id": null,
	"question": "In the preamble to these lectures he gives definition: \"Physical chemistry is the science that must explain under provisions of physical experiments the reason for what is happening in complex bodies through chemical operations\".",
	"topic_id": null,
	"sub_cat_id": null,
	"id": null,
	"answer": "by Mikhail Lomonosov"
}, {
	"category_id": null,
	"question": "The term \"physical chemistry\" was coined by Mikhail Lomonosov in 1752, when he presented a lecture course entitled \"A Course in True Physical Chemistry\" (Russian: \u00ab\u041a\u0443\u0440\u0441 \u0438\u0441\u0442\u0438\u043d\u043d\u043e\u0439 \u0444\u0438\u0437\u0438\u0447\u0435\u0441\u043a\u043e\u0439 \u0445\u0438\u043c\u0438\u0438\u00bb) before the students of Petersburg University.",
	"topic_id": null,
	"sub_cat_id": null,
	"id": null,
	"answer": "Physical chemistry"
}, {
	"category_id": null,
	"question": "In the preamble to these lectures he gives definition: \"__________________ is the science that must explain under provisions of physical experiments the reason for what is happening in complex bodies through chemical operations\".",
	"topic_id": null,
	"sub_cat_id": null,
	"id": null,
	"answer": "Physical chemistry"
}, {
	"category_id": null,
	"question": "In the preamble to these lectures he gives definition: \"Physical chemistry is ___________ that must explain under provisions of physical experiments the reason for what is happening in complex bodies through chemical operations\".",
	"topic_id": null,
	"sub_cat_id": null,
	"id": null,
	"answer": "the science"
}, {
	"category_id": null,
	"question": "_________________________ originated in the 1860s to 1880s with work on chemical thermodynamics, electrolytes in solutions, chemical kinetics and other subjects.",
	"topic_id": null,
	"sub_cat_id": null,
	"id": null,
	"answer": "Modern physical chemistry"
}, {
	"category_id": null,
	"question": "_____________ was the publication in 1876 by Josiah Willard Gibbs of his paper, On the Equilibrium of Heterogeneous Substances.",
	"topic_id": null,
	"sub_cat_id": null,
	"id": null,
	"answer": "One milestone"
}, {
	"category_id": null,
	"question": "_________________ is the subfield of chemistry dealing with radioactivity, nuclear processes, such as nuclear transmutation, and nuclear properties.",
	"topic_id": null,
	"sub_cat_id": null,
	"id": null,
	"answer": "Nuclear chemistry"
}, {
	"category_id": null,
	"question": "It is _____________ of radioactive elements such as the actinides, radium and radon together with _____________ associated with equipment (such as nuclear reactors) which are designed to perform nuclear processes.",
	"topic_id": null,
	"sub_cat_id": null,
	"id": null,
	"answer": "the chemistry"
}, {
	"category_id": null,
	"question": "_________________ is the behavior of objects and materials after being placed into a nuclear waste storage or disposal site.",
	"topic_id": null,
	"sub_cat_id": null,
	"id": null,
	"answer": "An important area"
}, {
	"category_id": null,
	"question": "_______________________ controls much of radiation biology as radiation has an effect on living things at the molecular scale, to explain it another way the radiation alters the biochemicals within an organism, the alteration of the biomolecules then changes the chemistry which occurs within the organism, this change in chemistry then can lead to a biological outcome.",
	"topic_id": null,
	"sub_cat_id": null,
	"id": null,
	"answer": "The radiation chemistry"
}, {
	"category_id": null,
	"question": "The radiation chemistry controls much of radiation biology as radiation has an effect on living things at the molecular scale, to explain it another way the radiation alters the biochemicals within an organism, the alteration of ________________ then changes the chemistry which occurs within the organism, this change in chemistry then can lead to a biological outcome.",
	"topic_id": null,
	"sub_cat_id": null,
	"id": null,
	"answer": "the biomolecules"
}, {
	"category_id": null,
	"question": "The radiation chemistry controls much of radiation biology as radiation has an effect on living things at the molecular scale, to explain it another way the radiation alters the biochemicals within an organism, the alteration of the biomolecules then changes _____________ which occurs within the organism, this change in chemistry then can lead to a biological outcome.",
	"topic_id": null,
	"sub_cat_id": null,
	"id": null,
	"answer": "the chemistry"
}, {
	"category_id": null,
	"question": "As a result, _________________ greatly assists the understanding of medical treatments (such as cancer radiotherapy) and has enabled these treatments to improve.",
	"topic_id": null,
	"sub_cat_id": null,
	"id": null,
	"answer": "nuclear chemistry"
}, {
	"category_id": null,
	"question": "After the discovery of X-rays by Wilhelm R\u00f6ntgen, _______________ began to work on ionizing radiation.",
	"topic_id": null,
	"sub_cat_id": null,
	"id": null,
	"answer": "many scientists"
}, {
	"category_id": null,
	"question": "____________ was Henri Becquerel, who investigated the relationship between phosphorescence and the blackening of photographic plates.",
	"topic_id": null,
	"sub_cat_id": null,
	"id": null,
	"answer": "One of these"
}, {
	"category_id": null,
	"question": "One of these was _______________, who investigated the relationship between phosphorescence and the blackening of photographic plates.",
	"topic_id": null,
	"sub_cat_id": null,
	"id": null,
	"answer": "Henri Becquerel"
}, {
	"category_id": null,
	"question": "When _________ (working in France) discovered that, with no external source of energy, the uranium generated rays which could blacken (or fog) the photographic plate, radioactivity was discovered.",
	"topic_id": null,
	"sub_cat_id": null,
	"id": null,
	"answer": "Becquerel"
}, {
	"category_id": null,
	"question": "When Becquerel (working in France) discovered that, with no external source of energy, ___________ generated rays which could blacken (or fog) the photographic plate, radioactivity was discovered.",
	"topic_id": null,
	"sub_cat_id": null,
	"id": null,
	"answer": "the uranium"
}, {
	"category_id": null,
	"question": "When Becquerel (working in France) discovered that, with no external source of energy, the uranium generated rays which could blacken (or fog) the photographic plate, _____________ was discovered.",
	"topic_id": null,
	"sub_cat_id": null,
	"id": null,
	"answer": "radioactivity"
}, {
	"category_id": null,
	"question": "They used radiometric methods to identify which ________________________ was in after each chemical separation; they separated the uranium ore into each of the different chemical elements that were known at the time, and measured the radioactivity of each fraction.",
	"topic_id": null,
	"sub_cat_id": null,
	"id": null,
	"answer": "stream the radioactivity"
}, {
	"category_id": null,
	"question": "_______________ had carried a sample of radium in his pocket and as a result he suffered a high localised dose which resulted in a radiation burn [6].",
	"topic_id": null,
	"sub_cat_id": null,
	"id": null,
	"answer": "Henri Becquerel"
}, {
	"category_id": null,
	"question": "_________________, working in Canada and England, showed that radioactive decay can be described by a simple equation (a linear first degree derivative equation, now called first order kinetics), implying that a given radioactive substance has a characteristic \"half-life\" (the time taken for the amount of radioactivity present in a source to diminish by half).",
	"topic_id": null,
	"sub_cat_id": null,
	"id": null,
	"answer": "Ernest Rutherford"
}, {
	"category_id": null,
	"question": "Ernest Rutherford, working in Canada and England, showed that _________________ can be described by a simple equation (a linear first degree derivative equation, now called first order kinetics), implying that a given radioactive substance has a characteristic \"half-life\" (the time taken for the amount of radioactivity present in a source to diminish by half).",
	"topic_id": null,
	"sub_cat_id": null,
	"id": null,
	"answer": "radioactive decay"
}, {
	"category_id": null,
	"question": "Ernest Rutherford, working in Canada and England, showed that radioactive decay can be described by a simple equation (a linear first degree derivative equation, now called ____________________), implying that a given radioactive substance has a characteristic \"half-life\" (the time taken for the amount of radioactivity present in a source to diminish by half).",
	"topic_id": null,
	"sub_cat_id": null,
	"id": null,
	"answer": "first order kinetics"
}, {
	"id": null,
	"question": "_______ is one of the oldest academic disciplines, perhaps the oldest through its inclusion of astronomy.",
	"topic_id": null,
	"category_id": null,
	"sub_cat_id": null,
	"answer": "Physics"
}, {
	"id": null,
	"question": "Over the last two millennia, physics was a part of natural philosophy along with chemistry, biology, and certain branches of mathematics, but during the scientific revolution in the 17th century, the natural sciences emerged as unique research programs in their own right.",
	"topic_id": null,
	"category_id": null,
	"sub_cat_id": null,
	"answer": "Physics"
}, {
	"id": null,
	"question": "_______ intersects with many interdisciplinary areas of research, such as biophysics and quantum chemistry, and the boundaries of physics are not rigidly defined.",
	"topic_id": null,
	"category_id": null,
	"sub_cat_id": null,
	"answer": "Physics"
}, {
	"id": null,
	"question": "Physics is one of the oldest academic disciplines, perhaps the oldest through its inclusion of astronomy.",
	"topic_id": null,
	"category_id": null,
	"sub_cat_id": null,
	"answer": "physics"
}, {
	"id": null,
	"question": "Over the last two millennia, _______ was a part of natural philosophy along with chemistry, biology, and certain branches of mathematics, but during the scientific revolution in the 17th century, the natural sciences emerged as unique research programs in their own right.",
	"topic_id": null,
	"category_id": null,
	"sub_cat_id": null,
	"answer": "physics"
}, {
	"id": null,
	"question": "Physics intersects with many interdisciplinary areas of research, such as bio_______ and quantum chemistry, and the boundaries of _______ are not rigidly defined.",
	"topic_id": null,
	"category_id": null,
	"sub_cat_id": null,
	"answer": "physics"
}, {
	"id": null,
	"question": "Over the last two millennia, physics was a part of natural philosophy along with chemistry, biology, and certain branches of mathematics, but during the scientific revolution in the 17th century, ____________________ emerged as unique research programs in their own right.",
	"topic_id": null,
	"category_id": null,
	"sub_cat_id": null,
	"answer": "the natural sciences"
}, {
	"id": null,
	"question": "Physics intersects with many interdisciplinary areas of research, such as biophysics and quantum chemistry, and the boundaries of physics are not rigidly defined.",
	"topic_id": null,
	"category_id": null,
	"sub_cat_id": null,
	"answer": "the natural sciences"
}, {
	"id": null,
	"question": "_______ also makes significant contributions through advances in new technologies that arise from theoretical breakthroughs.",
	"topic_id": null,
	"category_id": null,
	"sub_cat_id": null,
	"answer": "Physics"
}, {
	"id": null,
	"question": "For example, advances in the understanding of electromagnetism or nuclear physics led directly to the development of new products that have dramatically transformed modern-day society, such as television, computers, domestic appliances, and nuclear weapons;[6] advances in thermodynamics led to the development of industrialization, and _____________________ inspired the development of calculus.",
	"topic_id": null,
	"category_id": null,
	"sub_cat_id": null,
	"answer": "advances in mechanics"
}, {
	"id": null,
	"question": "_________ is the oldest of the natural sciences.",
	"topic_id": null,
	"category_id": null,
	"sub_cat_id": null,
	"answer": "Astronomy"
}, {
	"id": null,
	"question": "__________________________ dating back to beyond 3000\u00a0BCE, such as the Sumerians, ancient Egyptians, and the Indus Valley Civilization, all had a predictive knowledge and a basic understanding of the motions of the Sun, Moon, and stars.",
	"topic_id": null,
	"category_id": null,
	"sub_cat_id": null,
	"answer": "The earliest civilizations"
}, {
	"id": null,
	"question": "According to Asger Aaboe, the origins of Western astronomy can be found in Mesopotamia, and all Western efforts in the exact sciences are descended from late Babylonian astronomy.",
	"topic_id": null,
	"category_id": null,
	"sub_cat_id": null,
	"answer": "Egyptian astronomers"
}, {
	"id": null,
	"question": "____________________ left monuments showing knowledge of the constellations and the motions of the celestial bodies,[11] while Greek poet Homer wrote of various celestial objects in his Iliad and Odyssey; later Greek astronomers provided names, which are still used today, for most constellations visible from the northern hemisphere.",
	"topic_id": null,
	"category_id": null,
	"sub_cat_id": null,
	"answer": "Egyptian astronomers"
}, {
	"id": null,
	"question": "Egyptian astronomers left monuments showing knowledge of the constellations and the motions of the celestial bodies,[11] while ________________ wrote of various celestial objects in his Iliad and Odyssey; later Greek astronomers provided names, which are still used today, for most constellations visible from the northern hemisphere.",
	"topic_id": null,
	"category_id": null,
	"sub_cat_id": null,
	"answer": "Greek poet Homer"
}, {
	"id": null,
	"question": "Egyptian astronomers left monuments showing knowledge of the constellations and the motions of the celestial bodies,[11] while Greek poet Homer wrote of various celestial objects in his Iliad and Odyssey; later _________________ provided names, which are still used today, for most constellations visible from the northern hemisphere.",
	"topic_id": null,
	"category_id": null,
	"sub_cat_id": null,
	"answer": "Greek astronomers"
}, {
	"id": null,
	"question": "Egyptian astronomers left monuments showing knowledge of the constellations and the motions of the celestial bodies,[11] while Greek poet Homer wrote of various celestial objects in his Iliad and Odyssey; later Greek astronomers provided _____, which are still used today, for most constellations visible from the northern hemisphere.",
	"topic_id": null,
	"category_id": null,
	"sub_cat_id": null,
	"answer": "names"
}, {
	"id": null,
	"question": "__________________ has its origins in Greece during the Archaic period, (650 BCE \u2013 480 BCE), when Pre-Socratic philosophers like Thales rejected non-naturalistic explanations for natural phenomena and proclaimed that every event had a natural cause.",
	"topic_id": null,
	"category_id": null,
	"sub_cat_id": null,
	"answer": "Natural philosophy"
}, {
	"id": null,
	"question": "They proposed ideas verified by reason and observation, and many of their hypotheses proved successful in experiment;[14] for example, atomism was found to be correct approximately 2000 years after it was first proposed by Leucippus and his pupil Democritus.",
	"topic_id": null,
	"category_id": null,
	"sub_cat_id": null,
	"answer": "Natural philosophy"
}, {
	"id": null,
	"question": "Natural philosophy has its origins in Greece during the Archaic period, (650 BCE \u2013 480 BCE), when _________________________ like Thales rejected non-naturalistic explanations for natural phenomena and proclaimed that every event had a natural cause.",
	"topic_id": null,
	"category_id": null,
	"sub_cat_id": null,
	"answer": "Pre-Socratic philosophers"
}, {
	"id": null,
	"question": "___________________ had inherited Aristotelian physics from the Greeks and during the Islamic Golden Age developed it further, especially placing emphasis on observation and a priori reasoning, developing early forms of the scientific method.",
	"topic_id": null,
	"category_id": null,
	"sub_cat_id": null,
	"answer": "Islamic scholarship"
}, {
	"id": null,
	"question": "The most notable innovations were in the field of _________________, which came from the works of many scientists like Ibn Sahl, Al-Kindi, Ibn Al-Haitham, Al-Farisi and Avicenna.",
	"topic_id": null,
	"category_id": null,
	"sub_cat_id": null,
	"answer": "Optics and vision"
}, {
	"id": null,
	"question": "Using dissections and the knowledge of previous scholars, he was able to begin to explain how light enters the eye, is focused, and is projected to the back of the eye: and built then _________'s first obscura camera hundreds of years before the modern development of photography.",
	"topic_id": null,
	"category_id": null,
	"sub_cat_id": null,
	"answer": "the world"
}, {
	"id": null,
	"question": "Indeed, the influence of Ibn al-Haytham\u2019s ____________ alongside that of Newton\u2019s work of the same title, published 700 years later.",
	"topic_id": null,
	"category_id": null,
	"sub_cat_id": null,
	"answer": "Optics ranks"
}, {
	"id": null,
	"question": "Indeed, the influence of Ibn al-Haytham\u2019s Optics ranks alongside that of ______\u2019s work of the same title, published 700 years later.",
	"topic_id": null,
	"category_id": null,
	"sub_cat_id": null,
	"answer": "Newton"
}, {
	"id": null,
	"question": "From it, later _________________ were able to build the same devices as what Ibn Al Haytham did, and understand the way light works.",
	"topic_id": null,
	"category_id": null,
	"sub_cat_id": null,
	"answer": "European scholars"
}, {
	"id": null,
	"question": "_______ became a separate science when early modern Europeans used experimental and quantitative methods to discover what are now considered to be the laws of physics.",
	"topic_id": null,
	"category_id": null,
	"sub_cat_id": null,
	"answer": "Physics"
}, {
	"id": null,
	"question": "Physics became a separate science when ______________________ used experimental and quantitative methods to discover what are now considered to be the laws of physics.",
	"topic_id": null,
	"category_id": null,
	"sub_cat_id": null,
	"answer": "early modern Europeans"
}, {
	"id": null,
	"answer": "WaterstonThermodynamics",
	"sub_cat_id": null,
	"category_id": null,
	"topic_id": null,
	"question": "Waterston Thermodynamics is a branch of physics concerned with heat and temperature and their relation to energy and work."
}, {
	"id": null,
	"answer": "These general constraints",
	"sub_cat_id": null,
	"category_id": null,
	"topic_id": null,
	"question": "_________________________ are expressed in the four laws of thermodynamics."
}, {
	"id": null,
	"answer": "Thermodynamics",
	"sub_cat_id": null,
	"category_id": null,
	"topic_id": null,
	"question": "______________ describes the bulk behavior of the body, not the microscopic behaviors of the very large numbers of its microscopic constituents, such as molecules."
}, {
	"id": null,
	"answer": "Its laws",
	"sub_cat_id": null,
	"category_id": null,
	"topic_id": null,
	"question": "________ are explained by statistical mechanics, in terms of the microscopic constituents."
}, {
	"id": null,
	"answer": "Thermodynamics",
	"sub_cat_id": null,
	"category_id": null,
	"topic_id": null,
	"question": "______________ applies to a wide variety of topics in science and engineering, especially physical chemistry, chemical engineering and mechanical engineering."
}, {
	"id": null,
	"answer": "by Joseph Black",
	"sub_cat_id": null,
	"category_id": null,
	"topic_id": null,
	"question": "Historically, the distinction between heat and temperature was studied in the 1750s _______________."
}, {
	"id": null,
	"answer": "the key",
	"sub_cat_id": null,
	"category_id": null,
	"topic_id": null,
	"question": "Characteristically thermodynamic thinking began in the work of Carnot (1824) who believed that the efficiency of heat engines was _______ that could help France win the Napoleonic Wars."
}, {
	"id": null,
	"answer": "Thermodynamics",
	"sub_cat_id": null,
	"category_id": null,
	"topic_id": null,
	"question": "______________ was later expanded to the study of energy transfers in chemical processes, such as the investigation, published in 1840, of the heats of chemical reactions[3] by Germain Hess, which was not originally explicitly concerned with the relation between energy exchanges by heat and work."
}, {
	"id": null,
	"answer": "the investigation",
	"sub_cat_id": null,
	"category_id": null,
	"topic_id": null,
	"question": "Thermodynamics was later expanded to the study of energy transfers in chemical processes, such as _________________, published in 1840, of the heats of chemical reactions[3] by Germain Hess, which was not originally explicitly concerned with the relation between energy exchanges by heat and work."
}, {
	"id": null,
	"answer": "thermodynamics",
	"sub_cat_id": null,
	"category_id": null,
	"topic_id": null,
	"question": "Historically, ______________ arose from the study of two distinct kinds of transfer of energy, as heat and as work, and the relation of those to the system's macroscopic variables of volume, pressure and temperature."
}, {
	"id": null,
	"answer": "thermodynamics",
	"sub_cat_id": null,
	"category_id": null,
	"topic_id": null,
	"question": "As it developed, ______________ began also to study transfers of matter."
}, {
	"id": null,
	"answer": "Thermodynamic equilibrium",
	"sub_cat_id": null,
	"category_id": null,
	"topic_id": null,
	"question": "_________________________ is one of the most important concepts for thermodynamics."
}, {
	"id": null,
	"answer": "Thermodynamic equilibrium",
	"sub_cat_id": null,
	"category_id": null,
	"topic_id": null,
	"question": "The temperature of a thermodynamic system is well defined, and is perhaps the most characteristic quantity of thermodynamics."
}, {
	"id": null,
	"answer": "systems",
	"sub_cat_id": null,
	"category_id": null,
	"topic_id": null,
	"question": "Many important practical engineering cases, as in heat engines or refrigerators, can be approximated as _______ consisting of many sub_______ at different temperatures and pressures."
}, {
	"id": null,
	"answer": "a physical process",
	"sub_cat_id": null,
	"category_id": null,
	"topic_id": null,
	"question": "If __________________ is too fast, the equilibrium thermodynamic variables, for example temperature, may not be well enough defined to provide a useful approximation."
}, {
	"id": null,
	"answer": "the system",
	"sub_cat_id": null,
	"category_id": null,
	"topic_id": null,
	"question": "Central to thermodynamic analysis are the definitions of __________, which is of interest, and of its surroundings."
}, {
	"id": null,
	"answer": "the system",
	"sub_cat_id": null,
	"category_id": null,
	"topic_id": null,
	"question": "The surroundings of a thermodynamic system consist of physical devices and of other thermodynamic systems that can interact with it."
}, {
	"id": null,
	"answer": "a heat bath",
	"sub_cat_id": null,
	"category_id": null,
	"topic_id": null,
	"question": "An example of a thermodynamic surrounding is ___________, which is held at a prescribed temperature, regardless of how much heat might be drawn from it."
}, {
	"id": null,
	"answer": "A thermodynamic system",
	"sub_cat_id": null,
	"category_id": null,
	"topic_id": null,
	"question": "______________________ can be defined in terms of its states."
}, {
	"id": null,
	"answer": "A thermodynamic system",
	"sub_cat_id": null,
	"category_id": null,
	"topic_id": null,
	"question": "In this way, a thermodynamic system is a macroscopic physical object, explicitly specified in terms of macroscopic physical and chemical variables that describe its macroscopic properties."
}, {
	"id": null,
	"answer": "a thermodynamic system",
	"sub_cat_id": null,
	"category_id": null,
	"topic_id": null,
	"question": "A thermodynamic system can be defined in terms of its states."
}, {
	"id": null,
	"answer": "a thermodynamic system",
	"sub_cat_id": null,
	"category_id": null,
	"topic_id": null,
	"question": "In this way, ______________________ is a macroscopic physical object, explicitly specified in terms of macroscopic physical and chemical variables that describe its macroscopic properties."
}, {
	"id": null,
	"answer": "the walls",
	"sub_cat_id": null,
	"category_id": null,
	"topic_id": null,
	"question": "The macroscopic state variables of thermodynamics have been recognized in the course of empirical work in physics and chemistry."
}, {
	"id": null,
	"answer": "the walls",
	"sub_cat_id": null,
	"category_id": null,
	"topic_id": null,
	"question": "Always associated with the material that constitutes a system, its working substance, are _________ that delimit the system, and connect it with its surroundings."
}, {
	"id": null,
	"answer": "A thermodynamic operation",
	"sub_cat_id": null,
	"category_id": null,
	"topic_id": null,
	"question": "_________________________ is an artificial physical manipulation that changes the definition of a system or its surroundings."
}, {
	"id": null,
	"answer": "A thermodynamic operation",
	"sub_cat_id": null,
	"category_id": null,
	"topic_id": null,
	"question": "_________________________ that increases the range of possible transfers usually leads to a thermodynamic process of transfer of mass or energy that changes the state of the system, and the transfer occurs in natural accord with the laws of thermodynamics."
}, {
	"id": null,
	"answer": "mass or energy",
	"sub_cat_id": null,
	"category_id": null,
	"topic_id": null,
	"question": "A thermodynamic operation that increases the range of possible transfers usually leads to a thermodynamic process of transfer of ______________ that changes the state of the system, and the transfer occurs in natural accord with the laws of thermodynamics."
}, {
	"id": null,
	"answer": "the transfer",
	"sub_cat_id": null,
	"category_id": null,
	"topic_id": null,
	"question": "A thermodynamic operation that increases the range of possible transfers usually leads to a thermodynamic process of transfer of mass or energy that changes the state of the system, and ____________ occurs in natural accord with the laws of thermodynamics."
}, {
	"id": null,
	"answer": "the operation",
	"sub_cat_id": null,
	"category_id": null,
	"topic_id": null,
	"question": "But if _____________ simply reduces the possible range of transfers, in general it does not initiate a process."
}, {
	"sub_cat_id": null,
	"topic_id": null,
	"question": "_______________ is the branch of physics that studies the mechanics of fluids (liquids, gases, and plasmas) and the forces on them.",
	"id": null,
	"answer": "Fluid mechanics",
	"category_id": null
}, {
	"sub_cat_id": null,
	"topic_id": null,
	"question": "_______________ has a wide range of applications, including for mechanical engineering, chemical engineering, geophysics, astrophysics, and biology.",
	"id": null,
	"answer": "Fluid mechanics",
	"category_id": null
}, {
	"sub_cat_id": null,
	"topic_id": null,
	"question": "_______________ can be divided into fluid statics, the study of fluids at rest; and fluid dynamics, the study of the effect of forces on fluid motion.",
	"id": null,
	"answer": "Fluid mechanics",
	"category_id": null
}, {
	"sub_cat_id": null,
	"topic_id": null,
	"question": "It is a branch of continuum mechanics, a subject which ______ matter without using the information that it is made out of atoms; that is, it ______ matter from a macroscopic viewpoint rather than from microscopic.",
	"id": null,
	"answer": "models",
	"category_id": null
}, {
	"sub_cat_id": null,
	"topic_id": null,
	"question": "_______________ can be mathematically complex, and can best be solved by numerical methods, typically using computers.",
	"id": null,
	"answer": "Fluid mechanics",
	"category_id": null
}, {
	"sub_cat_id": null,
	"topic_id": null,
	"question": "___________________, called computational fluid dynamics (CFD), is devoted to this approach to solving fluid mechanics problems.",
	"id": null,
	"answer": "A modern discipline",
	"category_id": null
}, {
	"sub_cat_id": null,
	"topic_id": null,
	"question": "The study of fluid mechanics goes back at least to the days of ancient Greece, when __________ investigated fluid statics and buoyancy and formulated his famous law known now as the __________' principle, which was published in his work On Floating Bodies \u2013 generally considered to be the first major work on fluid mechanics.",
	"id": null,
	"answer": "Archimedes",
	"category_id": null
}, {
	"sub_cat_id": null,
	"topic_id": null,
	"question": "The study of fluid mechanics goes back at least to the days of ancient Greece, when Archimedes investigated fluid statics and buoyancy and formulated ______________ known now as the Archimedes' principle, which was published in his work On Floating Bodies \u2013 generally considered to be the first major work on fluid mechanics.",
	"id": null,
	"answer": "his famous law",
	"category_id": null
}, {
	"sub_cat_id": null,
	"topic_id": null,
	"question": "The study of fluid mechanics goes back at least to the days of ancient Greece, when Archimedes investigated fluid statics and buoyancy and formulated his famous law known now as _________________________, which was published in his work On Floating Bodies \u2013 generally considered to be the first major work on fluid mechanics.",
	"id": null,
	"answer": "the Archimedes' principle",
	"category_id": null
}, {
	"sub_cat_id": null,
	"topic_id": null,
	"question": "The study of fluid mechanics goes back at least to the days of ancient Greece, when Archimedes investigated fluid statics and buoyancy and formulated his famous law known now as the Archimedes' principle, which was published in his work On _________________ generally considered to be the first major work on fluid mechanics.",
	"id": null,
	"answer": "Floating Bodies \u2013",
	"category_id": null
}, {
	"sub_cat_id": null,
	"topic_id": null,
	"question": "_____________ was further analyzed by various mathematicians (Leonhard Euler, Jean le Rond d'Alembert, Joseph Louis Lagrange, Pierre-Simon Laplace, Sim\u00e9on Denis Poisson) and viscous flow was explored by a multitude of engineers including Jean L\u00e9onard Marie Poiseuille and Gotthilf Hagen.",
	"id": null,
	"answer": "Inviscid flow",
	"category_id": null
}, {
	"sub_cat_id": null,
	"topic_id": null,
	"question": "Further mathematical justification was provided by Claude-Louis Navier and George Gabriel Stokes in the Navier\u2013Stokes equations, and _______________ were investigated (Ludwig Prandtl, Theodore von K\u00e1rm\u00e1n), while various scientists such as Osborne Reynolds, Andrey Kolmogorov, and Geoffrey Ingram Taylor advanced the understanding of fluid viscosity and turbulence.",
	"id": null,
	"answer": "boundary layers",
	"category_id": null
}, {
	"sub_cat_id": null,
	"topic_id": null,
	"question": "____________ is fundamental to hydraulics, the engineering of equipment for storing, transporting and using fluids.",
	"id": null,
	"answer": "Hydrostatics",
	"category_id": null
}, {
	"sub_cat_id": null,
	"topic_id": null,
	"question": "______________ is a subdiscipline of fluid mechanics that deals with fluid flow\u2014the natural science of fluids (liquids and gases) in motion.",
	"id": null,
	"answer": "Fluid dynamics",
	"category_id": null
}, {
	"sub_cat_id": null,
	"topic_id": null,
	"question": "______________ has a wide range of applications, including calculating forces and moments on aircraft, determining the mass flow rate of petroleum through pipelines, predicting weather patterns, understanding nebulae in interstellar space and modelling fission weapon detonation.",
	"id": null,
	"answer": "Fluid dynamics",
	"category_id": null
}, {
	"sub_cat_id": null,
	"topic_id": null,
	"question": "Some of its principles are even used in _______ engineering, where _______ is treated as a continuous fluid, and crowd dynamics.",
	"id": null,
	"answer": "traffic",
	"category_id": null
}, {
	"sub_cat_id": null,
	"topic_id": null,
	"question": "Fluid dynamics offers ____________________________ underlies these practical disciplines\u2014that embraces empirical and semi-empirical laws derived from flow measurement and used to solve practical problems.",
	"id": null,
	"answer": "a systematic structure\u2014which",
	"category_id": null
}, {
	"sub_cat_id": null,
	"topic_id": null,
	"question": "_______________ is the branch of physics that studies the mechanics of fluids (liquids, gases, and plasmas) and the forces on them.",
	"id": null,
	"answer": "Fluid mechanics",
	"category_id": null
}, {
	"sub_cat_id": null,
	"topic_id": null,
	"question": "_______________ has a wide range of applications, including for mechanical engineering, chemical engineering, geophysics, astrophysics, and biology.",
	"id": null,
	"answer": "Fluid mechanics",
	"category_id": null
}, {
	"sub_cat_id": null,
	"topic_id": null,
	"question": "_______________ can be divided into fluid statics, the study of fluids at rest; and fluid dynamics, the study of the effect of forces on fluid motion.",
	"id": null,
	"answer": "Fluid mechanics",
	"category_id": null
}, {
	"sub_cat_id": null,
	"topic_id": null,
	"question": "It is a branch of continuum mechanics, a subject which ______ matter without using the information that it is made out of atoms; that is, it ______ matter from a macroscopic viewpoint rather than from microscopic.",
	"id": null,
	"answer": "models",
	"category_id": null
}, {
	"sub_cat_id": null,
	"topic_id": null,
	"question": "_______________ can be mathematically complex, and can best be solved by numerical methods, typically using computers.",
	"id": null,
	"answer": "Fluid mechanics",
	"category_id": null
}, {
	"sub_cat_id": null,
	"topic_id": null,
	"question": "___________________, called computational fluid dynamics (CFD), is devoted to this approach to solving fluid mechanics problems.",
	"id": null,
	"answer": "A modern discipline",
	"category_id": null
}, {
	"sub_cat_id": null,
	"topic_id": null,
	"question": "The study of fluid mechanics goes back at least to the days of ancient Greece, when __________ investigated fluid statics and buoyancy and formulated his famous law known now as the __________' principle, which was published in his work On Floating Bodies \u2013 generally considered to be the first major work on fluid mechanics.",
	"id": null,
	"answer": "Archimedes",
	"category_id": null
}, {
	"sub_cat_id": null,
	"topic_id": null,
	"question": "The study of fluid mechanics goes back at least to the days of ancient Greece, when Archimedes investigated fluid statics and buoyancy and formulated ______________ known now as the Archimedes' principle, which was published in his work On Floating Bodies \u2013 generally considered to be the first major work on fluid mechanics.",
	"id": null,
	"answer": "his famous law",
	"category_id": null
}, {
	"sub_cat_id": null,
	"topic_id": null,
	"question": "The study of fluid mechanics goes back at least to the days of ancient Greece, when Archimedes investigated fluid statics and buoyancy and formulated his famous law known now as _________________________, which was published in his work On Floating Bodies \u2013 generally considered to be the first major work on fluid mechanics.",
	"id": null,
	"answer": "the Archimedes' principle",
	"category_id": null
}, {
	"sub_cat_id": null,
	"topic_id": null,
	"question": "The study of fluid mechanics goes back at least to the days of ancient Greece, when Archimedes investigated fluid statics and buoyancy and formulated his famous law known now as the Archimedes' principle, which was published in his work On _________________ generally considered to be the first major work on fluid mechanics.",
	"id": null,
	"answer": "Floating Bodies \u2013",
	"category_id": null
}, {
	"sub_cat_id": null,
	"topic_id": null,
	"question": "_____________ was further analyzed by various mathematicians (Leonhard Euler, Jean le Rond d'Alembert, Joseph Louis Lagrange, Pierre-Simon Laplace, Sim\u00e9on Denis Poisson) and viscous flow was explored by a multitude of engineers including Jean L\u00e9onard Marie Poiseuille and Gotthilf Hagen.",
	"id": null,
	"answer": "Inviscid flow",
	"category_id": null
}, {
	"sub_cat_id": null,
	"topic_id": null,
	"question": "Further mathematical justification was provided by Claude-Louis Navier and George Gabriel Stokes in the Navier\u2013Stokes equations, and _______________ were investigated (Ludwig Prandtl, Theodore von K\u00e1rm\u00e1n), while various scientists such as Osborne Reynolds, Andrey Kolmogorov, and Geoffrey Ingram Taylor advanced the understanding of fluid viscosity and turbulence.",
	"id": null,
	"answer": "boundary layers",
	"category_id": null
}, {
	"sub_cat_id": null,
	"topic_id": null,
	"question": "____________ is fundamental to hydraulics, the engineering of equipment for storing, transporting and using fluids.",
	"id": null,
	"answer": "Hydrostatics",
	"category_id": null
}, {
	"sub_cat_id": null,
	"topic_id": null,
	"question": "______________ is a subdiscipline of fluid mechanics that deals with fluid flow\u2014the natural science of fluids (liquids and gases) in motion.",
	"id": null,
	"answer": "Fluid dynamics",
	"category_id": null
}, {
	"sub_cat_id": null,
	"topic_id": null,
	"question": "______________ has a wide range of applications, including calculating forces and moments on aircraft, determining the mass flow rate of petroleum through pipelines, predicting weather patterns, understanding nebulae in interstellar space and modelling fission weapon detonation.",
	"id": null,
	"answer": "Fluid dynamics",
	"category_id": null
}, {
	"sub_cat_id": null,
	"topic_id": null,
	"question": "Some of its principles are even used in _______ engineering, where _______ is treated as a continuous fluid, and crowd dynamics.",
	"id": null,
	"answer": "traffic",
	"category_id": null
}, {
	"sub_cat_id": null,
	"topic_id": null,
	"question": "Fluid dynamics offers ____________________________ underlies these practical disciplines\u2014that embraces empirical and semi-empirical laws derived from flow measurement and used to solve practical problems.",
	"id": null,
	"answer": "a systematic structure\u2014which",
	"category_id": null
}, {
	"sub_cat_id": null,
	"topic_id": null,
	"question": "__________________ is a theory of quantum gravity.",
	"id": null,
	"answer": "Thus string theory",
	"category_id": null
}, {
	"sub_cat_id": null,
	"topic_id": null,
	"question": "_____________ is a broad and varied subject that attempts to address a number of deep questions of fundamental physics.",
	"id": null,
	"answer": "String theory",
	"category_id": null
}, {
	"sub_cat_id": null,
	"topic_id": null,
	"question": "_____________ has been applied to a variety of problems in black hole physics, early universe cosmology, nuclear physics, and condensed matter physics, and it has stimulated a number of major developments in pure mathematics.",
	"id": null,
	"answer": "String theory",
	"category_id": null
}, {
	"sub_cat_id": null,
	"topic_id": null,
	"question": "Because _____________ potentially provides a unified description of gravity and particle physics, it is a candidate for a theory of everything, a self-contained mathematical model that describes all fundamental forces and forms of matter.",
	"id": null,
	"answer": "string theory",
	"category_id": null
}, {
	"sub_cat_id": null,
	"topic_id": null,
	"question": "_____________ was first studied in the late 1960s as a theory of the strong nuclear force, before being abandoned in favor of quantum chromodynamics.",
	"id": null,
	"answer": "String theory",
	"category_id": null
}, {
	"sub_cat_id": null,
	"topic_id": null,
	"question": "Subsequently, it was realized that ___________________ that made string theory unsuitable as a theory of nuclear physics made it a promising candidate for a quantum theory of gravity.",
	"id": null,
	"answer": "the very properties",
	"category_id": null
}, {
	"sub_cat_id": null,
	"topic_id": null,
	"question": "It later developed into __________________, which posits a connection called supersymmetry between bosons and the class of particles called fermions.",
	"id": null,
	"answer": "superstring theory",
	"category_id": null
}, {
	"sub_cat_id": null,
	"topic_id": null,
	"question": "In late 1997, _________ discovered an important relationship called the AdS/CFT correspondence, which relates string theory to another type of physical theory called a quantum field theory.",
	"id": null,
	"answer": "theorists",
	"category_id": null
}, {
	"sub_cat_id": null,
	"topic_id": null,
	"question": "In late 1997, theorists discovered an important relationship called the AdS/CFT correspondence, which relates _____________ to another type of physical theory called a quantum field theory.",
	"id": null,
	"answer": "string theory",
	"category_id": null
}, {
	"sub_cat_id": null,
	"topic_id": null,
	"question": "One of the challenges of string theory is that _______________ does not yet have a satisfactory definition in all circumstances.",
	"id": null,
	"answer": "the full theory",
	"category_id": null
}, {
	"sub_cat_id": null,
	"topic_id": null,
	"question": "Another issue is that __________ is thought to describe an enormous landscape of possible universes, and this has complicated efforts to develop theories of particle physics based on string theory.",
	"id": null,
	"answer": "the theory",
	"category_id": null
}, {
	"sub_cat_id": null,
	"topic_id": null,
	"question": "____________ have led some in the community to criticize these approaches to physics and question the value of continued research on string theory unification.",
	"id": null,
	"answer": "These issues",
	"category_id": null
}, {
	"sub_cat_id": null,
	"topic_id": null,
	"question": "In the twentieth century, __________________________ emerged for formulating the laws of physics.",
	"id": null,
	"answer": "two theoretical frameworks",
	"category_id": null
}, {
	"sub_cat_id": null,
	"topic_id": null,
	"question": "One of these frameworks was Albert Einstein's general theory of relativity, ________ that explains the force of gravity and the structure of space and time.",
	"id": null,
	"answer": "a theory",
	"category_id": null
}, {
	"sub_cat_id": null,
	"topic_id": null,
	"question": "_________ was quantum mechanics, a radically different formalism for describing physical phenomena using probability.",
	"id": null,
	"answer": "The other",
	"category_id": null
}, {
	"sub_cat_id": null,
	"topic_id": null,
	"question": "By the late 1970s, ____________________ had proven to be sufficient to explain most of the observed features of the universe, from elementary particles to atoms to the evolution of stars and the universe as a whole.",
	"id": null,
	"answer": "these two frameworks",
	"category_id": null
}, {
	"sub_cat_id": null,
	"answer": "Biology",
	"category_id": null,
	"question": "_______ is a natural science concerned with the study of life and living organisms, including their structure, function, growth, evolution, distribution, identification and taxonomy.",
	"id": null,
	"topic_id": null
}, {
	"sub_cat_id": null,
	"answer": "Biology",
	"category_id": null,
	"question": "Modern biology is a vast and eclectic field, composed of many branches and subdisciplines.",
	"id": null,
	"topic_id": null
}, {
	"sub_cat_id": null,
	"answer": "biology",
	"category_id": null,
	"question": "In general, _______ recognizes the cell as the basic unit of life, genes as the basic unit of heredity, and evolution as the engine that propels the synthesis and creation of new species.",
	"id": null,
	"topic_id": null
}, {
	"sub_cat_id": null,
	"answer": "the engine",
	"category_id": null,
	"question": "In general, biology recognizes the cell as the basic unit of life, genes as the basic unit of heredity, and evolution as __________ that propels the synthesis and creation of new species.",
	"id": null,
	"topic_id": null
}, {
	"sub_cat_id": null,
	"answer": "all the organisms",
	"category_id": null,
	"question": "It is also understood today that _________________ survive by consuming and transforming energy and by regulating their internal environment to maintain a stable and vital condition.",
	"id": null,
	"topic_id": null
}, {
	"sub_cat_id": null,
	"answer": "The term biology",
	"category_id": null,
	"question": "________________ is derived from the Greek word \u03b2\u03af\u03bf\u03c2, bios, \"life\" and the suffix -\u03bb\u03bf\u03b3\u03af\u03b1, -logia, \"study of.",
	"id": null,
	"topic_id": null
}, {
	"sub_cat_id": null,
	"answer": "The term biology",
	"category_id": null,
	"question": "The Latin-language form of the term first appeared in 1736 when Swedish scientist Carl Linnaeus (Carl von Linn\u00e9) used biologi in his Bibliotheca botanica.",
	"id": null,
	"topic_id": null
}, {
	"sub_cat_id": null,
	"answer": "Philosophiae",
	"category_id": null,
	"question": "It was used again in 1766 in a work entitled ____________ naturalis sive physicae: tomus III, continens geologian, biologian, phytologian generalis, by Michael Christoph Hanov, a disciple of Christian Wolff.",
	"id": null,
	"topic_id": null
}, {
	"sub_cat_id": null,
	"answer": "Karl Friedrich Burdach",
	"category_id": null,
	"question": "______________________ used the term in 1800 in a more restricted sense of the study of human beings from a morphological, physiological and psychological perspective (Prop\u00e4deutik zum Studien der gesammten Heilkunst).",
	"id": null,
	"topic_id": null
}, {
	"sub_cat_id": null,
	"answer": "modern biology",
	"category_id": null,
	"question": "Although ______________ is a relatively recent development, sciences related to and included within it have been studied since ancient times.",
	"id": null,
	"topic_id": null
}, {
	"sub_cat_id": null,
	"answer": "Natural philosophy",
	"category_id": null,
	"question": "__________________ was studied as early as the ancient civilizations of Mesopotamia, Egypt, the Indian subcontinent, and China.",
	"id": null,
	"topic_id": null
}, {
	"sub_cat_id": null,
	"answer": "Especially important",
	"category_id": null,
	"question": "____________________ are his History of Animals and other works where he showed naturalist leanings, and later more empirical works that focused on biological causation and the diversity of life.",
	"id": null,
	"topic_id": null
}, {
	"sub_cat_id": null,
	"answer": "a series",
	"category_id": null,
	"question": "Aristotle's successor at the Lyceum, Theophrastus, wrote ________ of books on botany that survived as the most important contribution of antiquity to the plant sciences, even into the Middle Ages.",
	"id": null,
	"topic_id": null
}, {
	"sub_cat_id": null,
	"answer": "865\u2013925",
	"category_id": null,
	"question": "Scholars of the medieval Islamic world who wrote on biology included al-Jahiz (781\u2013869), Al-D\u012bnawar\u012b (828\u2013896), who wrote on botany,[9] and Rhazes (_______) who wrote on anatomy and physiology.",
	"id": null,
	"topic_id": null
}, {
	"sub_cat_id": null,
	"answer": "Medicine",
	"category_id": null,
	"question": "________ was especially well studied by Islamic scholars working in Greek philosopher traditions, while natural history drew heavily on Aristotelian thought, especially in upholding a fixed hierarchy of life.",
	"id": null,
	"topic_id": null
}, {
	"sub_cat_id": null,
	"answer": "natural history",
	"category_id": null,
	"question": "Medicine was especially well studied by Islamic scholars working in Greek philosopher traditions, while _______________ drew heavily on Aristotelian thought, especially in upholding a fixed hierarchy of life.",
	"id": null,
	"topic_id": null
}, {
	"sub_cat_id": null,
	"answer": "Biology",
	"category_id": null,
	"question": "_______ began to quickly develop and grow with Anton van Leeuwenhoek's dramatic improvement of the microscope.",
	"id": null,
	"topic_id": null
}, {
	"sub_cat_id": null,
	"answer": "scholars",
	"category_id": null,
	"question": "It was then that ________ discovered spermatozoa, bacteria, infusoria and the diversity of microscopic life.",
	"id": null,
	"topic_id": null
}, {
	"sub_cat_id": null,
	"answer": "Advances in microscopy",
	"category_id": null,
	"question": "______________________ also had a profound impact on biological thinking.",
	"id": null,
	"topic_id": null
}, {
	"sub_cat_id": null,
	"answer": "Schleiden and Schwann",
	"category_id": null,
	"question": "Then, in 1838, _____________________ began promoting the now universal ideas that (1) the basic unit of organisms is the cell and (2) that individual cells have all the characteristics of life, although they opposed the idea that (3) all cells come from the division of other cells.",
	"id": null,
	"topic_id": null
}, {
	"sub_cat_id": null,
	"answer": "taxonomy and classification",
	"category_id": null,
	"question": "Meanwhile, ___________________________ became the focus of natural historians.",
	"id": null,
	"topic_id": null
}, {
	"sub_cat_id": null,
	"answer": "Carl Linnaeus",
	"category_id": null,
	"question": "_____________ published a basic taxonomy for the natural world in 1735 (variations of which have been in use ever since), and in the 1750s introduced scientific names for all his species.",
	"id": null,
	"topic_id": null
}, {
	"sub_cat_id": null,
	"answer": "Carl Linnaeus",
	"category_id": null,
	"question": "Georges-Louis Leclerc, Comte de Buffon, treated species as artificial categories and living forms as malleable\u2014even suggesting the possibility of common descent.",
	"id": null,
	"topic_id": null
}, {
	"sub_cat_id": null,
	"answer": "the 1750s",
	"category_id": null,
	"question": "Carl Linnaeus published a basic taxonomy for the natural world in 1735 (variations of which have been in use ever since), and in _________ introduced scientific names for all his species.",
	"id": null,
	"topic_id": null
}, {
	"sub_cat_id": null,
	"answer": "Biology",
	"category_id": null,
	"question": "_______ is a natural science concerned with the study of life and living organisms, including their structure, function, growth, evolution, distribution, identification and taxonomy.",
	"id": null,
	"topic_id": null
}, {
	"sub_cat_id": null,
	"answer": "Biology",
	"category_id": null,
	"question": "Modern biology is a vast and eclectic field, composed of many branches and subdisciplines.",
	"id": null,
	"topic_id": null
}, {
	"sub_cat_id": null,
	"answer": "biology",
	"category_id": null,
	"question": "In general, _______ recognizes the cell as the basic unit of life, genes as the basic unit of heredity, and evolution as the engine that propels the synthesis and creation of new species.",
	"id": null,
	"topic_id": null
}, {
	"sub_cat_id": null,
	"answer": "the engine",
	"category_id": null,
	"question": "In general, biology recognizes the cell as the basic unit of life, genes as the basic unit of heredity, and evolution as __________ that propels the synthesis and creation of new species.",
	"id": null,
	"topic_id": null
}, {
	"sub_cat_id": null,
	"answer": "all the organisms",
	"category_id": null,
	"question": "It is also understood today that _________________ survive by consuming and transforming energy and by regulating their internal environment to maintain a stable and vital condition.",
	"id": null,
	"topic_id": null
}, {
	"sub_cat_id": null,
	"answer": "The term biology",
	"category_id": null,
	"question": "________________ is derived from the Greek word \u03b2\u03af\u03bf\u03c2, bios, \"life\" and the suffix -\u03bb\u03bf\u03b3\u03af\u03b1, -logia, \"study of.",
	"id": null,
	"topic_id": null
}, {
	"sub_cat_id": null,
	"answer": "The term biology",
	"category_id": null,
	"question": "The Latin-language form of the term first appeared in 1736 when Swedish scientist Carl Linnaeus (Carl von Linn\u00e9) used biologi in his Bibliotheca botanica.",
	"id": null,
	"topic_id": null
}, {
	"sub_cat_id": null,
	"answer": "Philosophiae",
	"category_id": null,
	"question": "It was used again in 1766 in a work entitled ____________ naturalis sive physicae: tomus III, continens geologian, biologian, phytologian generalis, by Michael Christoph Hanov, a disciple of Christian Wolff.",
	"id": null,
	"topic_id": null
}, {
	"sub_cat_id": null,
	"answer": "Karl Friedrich Burdach",
	"category_id": null,
	"question": "______________________ used the term in 1800 in a more restricted sense of the study of human beings from a morphological, physiological and psychological perspective (Prop\u00e4deutik zum Studien der gesammten Heilkunst).",
	"id": null,
	"topic_id": null
}, {
	"sub_cat_id": null,
	"answer": "modern biology",
	"category_id": null,
	"question": "Although ______________ is a relatively recent development, sciences related to and included within it have been studied since ancient times.",
	"id": null,
	"topic_id": null
}, {
	"sub_cat_id": null,
	"answer": "Natural philosophy",
	"category_id": null,
	"question": "__________________ was studied as early as the ancient civilizations of Mesopotamia, Egypt, the Indian subcontinent, and China.",
	"id": null,
	"topic_id": null
}, {
	"sub_cat_id": null,
	"answer": "Especially important",
	"category_id": null,
	"question": "____________________ are his History of Animals and other works where he showed naturalist leanings, and later more empirical works that focused on biological causation and the diversity of life.",
	"id": null,
	"topic_id": null
}, {
	"sub_cat_id": null,
	"answer": "a series",
	"category_id": null,
	"question": "Aristotle's successor at the Lyceum, Theophrastus, wrote ________ of books on botany that survived as the most important contribution of antiquity to the plant sciences, even into the Middle Ages.",
	"id": null,
	"topic_id": null
}, {
	"sub_cat_id": null,
	"answer": "865\u2013925",
	"category_id": null,
	"question": "Scholars of the medieval Islamic world who wrote on biology included al-Jahiz (781\u2013869), Al-D\u012bnawar\u012b (828\u2013896), who wrote on botany,[9] and Rhazes (_______) who wrote on anatomy and physiology.",
	"id": null,
	"topic_id": null
}, {
	"sub_cat_id": null,
	"answer": "Medicine",
	"category_id": null,
	"question": "________ was especially well studied by Islamic scholars working in Greek philosopher traditions, while natural history drew heavily on Aristotelian thought, especially in upholding a fixed hierarchy of life.",
	"id": null,
	"topic_id": null
}, {
	"sub_cat_id": null,
	"answer": "natural history",
	"category_id": null,
	"question": "Medicine was especially well studied by Islamic scholars working in Greek philosopher traditions, while _______________ drew heavily on Aristotelian thought, especially in upholding a fixed hierarchy of life.",
	"id": null,
	"topic_id": null
}, {
	"sub_cat_id": null,
	"answer": "Biology",
	"category_id": null,
	"question": "_______ began to quickly develop and grow with Anton van Leeuwenhoek's dramatic improvement of the microscope.",
	"id": null,
	"topic_id": null
}, {
	"sub_cat_id": null,
	"answer": "scholars",
	"category_id": null,
	"question": "It was then that ________ discovered spermatozoa, bacteria, infusoria and the diversity of microscopic life.",
	"id": null,
	"topic_id": null
}, {
	"sub_cat_id": null,
	"answer": "Advances in microscopy",
	"category_id": null,
	"question": "______________________ also had a profound impact on biological thinking.",
	"id": null,
	"topic_id": null
}, {
	"sub_cat_id": null,
	"answer": "Schleiden and Schwann",
	"category_id": null,
	"question": "Then, in 1838, _____________________ began promoting the now universal ideas that (1) the basic unit of organisms is the cell and (2) that individual cells have all the characteristics of life, although they opposed the idea that (3) all cells come from the division of other cells.",
	"id": null,
	"topic_id": null
}, {
	"sub_cat_id": null,
	"answer": "taxonomy and classification",
	"category_id": null,
	"question": "Meanwhile, ___________________________ became the focus of natural historians.",
	"id": null,
	"topic_id": null
}, {
	"sub_cat_id": null,
	"answer": "Carl Linnaeus",
	"category_id": null,
	"question": "_____________ published a basic taxonomy for the natural world in 1735 (variations of which have been in use ever since), and in the 1750s introduced scientific names for all his species.",
	"id": null,
	"topic_id": null
}, {
	"sub_cat_id": null,
	"answer": "Carl Linnaeus",
	"category_id": null,
	"question": "Georges-Louis Leclerc, Comte de Buffon, treated species as artificial categories and living forms as malleable\u2014even suggesting the possibility of common descent.",
	"id": null,
	"topic_id": null
}, {
	"sub_cat_id": null,
	"answer": "the 1750s",
	"category_id": null,
	"question": "Carl Linnaeus published a basic taxonomy for the natural world in 1735 (variations of which have been in use ever since), and in _________ introduced scientific names for all his species.",
	"id": null,
	"topic_id": null
}, {
	"sub_cat_id": null,
	"answer": "Biology",
	"category_id": null,
	"question": "_______ is a natural science concerned with the study of life and living organisms, including their structure, function, growth, evolution, distribution, identification and taxonomy.",
	"id": null,
	"topic_id": null
}, {
	"sub_cat_id": null,
	"answer": "Biology",
	"category_id": null,
	"question": "Modern biology is a vast and eclectic field, composed of many branches and subdisciplines.",
	"id": null,
	"topic_id": null
}, {
	"sub_cat_id": null,
	"answer": "biology",
	"category_id": null,
	"question": "In general, _______ recognizes the cell as the basic unit of life, genes as the basic unit of heredity, and evolution as the engine that propels the synthesis and creation of new species.",
	"id": null,
	"topic_id": null
}, {
	"sub_cat_id": null,
	"answer": "the engine",
	"category_id": null,
	"question": "In general, biology recognizes the cell as the basic unit of life, genes as the basic unit of heredity, and evolution as __________ that propels the synthesis and creation of new species.",
	"id": null,
	"topic_id": null
}, {
	"sub_cat_id": null,
	"answer": "all the organisms",
	"category_id": null,
	"question": "It is also understood today that _________________ survive by consuming and transforming energy and by regulating their internal environment to maintain a stable and vital condition.",
	"id": null,
	"topic_id": null
}, {
	"sub_cat_id": null,
	"answer": "The term biology",
	"category_id": null,
	"question": "________________ is derived from the Greek word \u03b2\u03af\u03bf\u03c2, bios, \"life\" and the suffix -\u03bb\u03bf\u03b3\u03af\u03b1, -logia, \"study of.",
	"id": null,
	"topic_id": null
}, {
	"sub_cat_id": null,
	"answer": "The term biology",
	"category_id": null,
	"question": "The Latin-language form of the term first appeared in 1736 when Swedish scientist Carl Linnaeus (Carl von Linn\u00e9) used biologi in his Bibliotheca botanica.",
	"id": null,
	"topic_id": null
}, {
	"sub_cat_id": null,
	"answer": "Philosophiae",
	"category_id": null,
	"question": "It was used again in 1766 in a work entitled ____________ naturalis sive physicae: tomus III, continens geologian, biologian, phytologian generalis, by Michael Christoph Hanov, a disciple of Christian Wolff.",
	"id": null,
	"topic_id": null
}, {
	"sub_cat_id": null,
	"answer": "Karl Friedrich Burdach",
	"category_id": null,
	"question": "______________________ used the term in 1800 in a more restricted sense of the study of human beings from a morphological, physiological and psychological perspective (Prop\u00e4deutik zum Studien der gesammten Heilkunst).",
	"id": null,
	"topic_id": null
}, {
	"sub_cat_id": null,
	"answer": "modern biology",
	"category_id": null,
	"question": "Although ______________ is a relatively recent development, sciences related to and included within it have been studied since ancient times.",
	"id": null,
	"topic_id": null
}, {
	"sub_cat_id": null,
	"answer": "Natural philosophy",
	"category_id": null,
	"question": "__________________ was studied as early as the ancient civilizations of Mesopotamia, Egypt, the Indian subcontinent, and China.",
	"id": null,
	"topic_id": null
}, {
	"sub_cat_id": null,
	"answer": "Especially important",
	"category_id": null,
	"question": "____________________ are his History of Animals and other works where he showed naturalist leanings, and later more empirical works that focused on biological causation and the diversity of life.",
	"id": null,
	"topic_id": null
}, {
	"sub_cat_id": null,
	"answer": "a series",
	"category_id": null,
	"question": "Aristotle's successor at the Lyceum, Theophrastus, wrote ________ of books on botany that survived as the most important contribution of antiquity to the plant sciences, even into the Middle Ages.",
	"id": null,
	"topic_id": null
}, {
	"sub_cat_id": null,
	"answer": "865\u2013925",
	"category_id": null,
	"question": "Scholars of the medieval Islamic world who wrote on biology included al-Jahiz (781\u2013869), Al-D\u012bnawar\u012b (828\u2013896), who wrote on botany,[9] and Rhazes (_______) who wrote on anatomy and physiology.",
	"id": null,
	"topic_id": null
}, {
	"sub_cat_id": null,
	"answer": "Medicine",
	"category_id": null,
	"question": "________ was especially well studied by Islamic scholars working in Greek philosopher traditions, while natural history drew heavily on Aristotelian thought, especially in upholding a fixed hierarchy of life.",
	"id": null,
	"topic_id": null
}, {
	"sub_cat_id": null,
	"answer": "natural history",
	"category_id": null,
	"question": "Medicine was especially well studied by Islamic scholars working in Greek philosopher traditions, while _______________ drew heavily on Aristotelian thought, especially in upholding a fixed hierarchy of life.",
	"id": null,
	"topic_id": null
}, {
	"sub_cat_id": null,
	"answer": "Biology",
	"category_id": null,
	"question": "_______ began to quickly develop and grow with Anton van Leeuwenhoek's dramatic improvement of the microscope.",
	"id": null,
	"topic_id": null
}, {
	"sub_cat_id": null,
	"answer": "scholars",
	"category_id": null,
	"question": "It was then that ________ discovered spermatozoa, bacteria, infusoria and the diversity of microscopic life.",
	"id": null,
	"topic_id": null
}, {
	"sub_cat_id": null,
	"answer": "Advances in microscopy",
	"category_id": null,
	"question": "______________________ also had a profound impact on biological thinking.",
	"id": null,
	"topic_id": null
}, {
	"sub_cat_id": null,
	"answer": "Schleiden and Schwann",
	"category_id": null,
	"question": "Then, in 1838, _____________________ began promoting the now universal ideas that (1) the basic unit of organisms is the cell and (2) that individual cells have all the characteristics of life, although they opposed the idea that (3) all cells come from the division of other cells.",
	"id": null,
	"topic_id": null
}, {
	"sub_cat_id": null,
	"answer": "taxonomy and classification",
	"category_id": null,
	"question": "Meanwhile, ___________________________ became the focus of natural historians.",
	"id": null,
	"topic_id": null
}, {
	"sub_cat_id": null,
	"answer": "Carl Linnaeus",
	"category_id": null,
	"question": "_____________ published a basic taxonomy for the natural world in 1735 (variations of which have been in use ever since), and in the 1750s introduced scientific names for all his species.",
	"id": null,
	"topic_id": null
}, {
	"sub_cat_id": null,
	"answer": "Carl Linnaeus",
	"category_id": null,
	"question": "Georges-Louis Leclerc, Comte de Buffon, treated species as artificial categories and living forms as malleable\u2014even suggesting the possibility of common descent.",
	"id": null,
	"topic_id": null
}, {
	"sub_cat_id": null,
	"answer": "the 1750s",
	"category_id": null,
	"question": "Carl Linnaeus published a basic taxonomy for the natural world in 1735 (variations of which have been in use ever since), and in _________ introduced scientific names for all his species.",
	"id": null,
	"topic_id": null
}, {
	"sub_cat_id": null,
	"answer": "an earth science",
	"category_id": null,
	"question": "Earth, the rocks of which it is composed, and the processes by which they change.",
	"id": null,
	"topic_id": null
}, {
	"sub_cat_id": null,
	"answer": "Geology",
	"category_id": null,
	"question": "_______ can also refer generally to the study of the solid features of any celestial body (such as the geology of the Moon or Mars).",
	"id": null,
	"topic_id": null
}, {
	"sub_cat_id": null,
	"answer": "Geology",
	"category_id": null,
	"question": "_______ gives insight into the history of the Earth by providing the primary evidence for plate tectonics, the evolutionary history of life, and past climates.",
	"id": null,
	"topic_id": null
}, {
	"sub_cat_id": null,
	"answer": "Geology",
	"category_id": null,
	"question": "_______ is important for mineral and hydrocarbon exploration and exploitation, evaluating water resources, understanding of natural hazards, the remediation of environmental problems, and for providing insights into past climate change.",
	"id": null,
	"topic_id": null
}, {
	"sub_cat_id": null,
	"answer": "Geology",
	"category_id": null,
	"question": "_______ also plays a role in geotechnical engineering and is a major academic discipline.",
	"id": null,
	"topic_id": null
}, {
	"sub_cat_id": null,
	"answer": "These",
	"category_id": null,
	"question": "_____ typically fall into one of two categories: rock and unconsolidated material.",
	"id": null,
	"topic_id": null
}, {
	"sub_cat_id": null,
	"answer": "The rock cycle",
	"category_id": null,
	"question": "______________ is an important concept in geology which illustrates the relationships between these three types of rock, and magma.",
	"id": null,
	"topic_id": null
}, {
	"sub_cat_id": null,
	"answer": "a rock",
	"category_id": null,
	"question": "When ______ crystallizes from melt (magma and/or lava), it is an igneous rock.",
	"id": null,
	"topic_id": null
}, {
	"sub_cat_id": null,
	"answer": "This rock",
	"category_id": null,
	"question": "_________ can be weathered and eroded, and then redeposited and lithified into a sedimentary rock, or be turned into a metamorphic rock due to heat and pressure that change the mineral content of the rock which gives it a characteristic fabric.",
	"id": null,
	"topic_id": null
}, {
	"sub_cat_id": null,
	"answer": "the rock",
	"category_id": null,
	"question": "This rock can be weathered and eroded, and then redeposited and lithified into a sedimentary rock, or be turned into a metamorphic rock due to heat and pressure that change the mineral content of ________ which gives it a characteristic fabric.",
	"id": null,
	"topic_id": null
}, {
	"sub_cat_id": null,
	"answer": "The sedimentary rock",
	"category_id": null,
	"question": "____________________ can then be subsequently turned into a metamorphic rock due to heat and pressure and is then weathered, eroded, deposited, and lithified, ultimately becoming a sedimentary rock.",
	"id": null,
	"topic_id": null
}, {
	"sub_cat_id": null,
	"answer": "lithified",
	"category_id": null,
	"question": "The sedimentary rock can then be subsequently turned into a metamorphic rock due to heat and pressure and is then weathered, eroded, deposited, and _________, ultimately becoming a sedimentary rock.",
	"id": null,
	"topic_id": null
}, {
	"sub_cat_id": null,
	"answer": "Sedimentary rock",
	"category_id": null,
	"question": "________________ may also be re-eroded and redeposited, and metamorphic rock may also undergo additional metamorphism.",
	"id": null,
	"topic_id": null
}, {
	"sub_cat_id": null,
	"answer": "metamorphic rock",
	"category_id": null,
	"question": "Sedimentary rock may also be re-eroded and redeposited, and ________________ may also undergo additional metamorphism.",
	"id": null,
	"topic_id": null
}, {
	"sub_cat_id": null,
	"answer": "a new magma",
	"category_id": null,
	"question": "All three types of rocks may be re-melted; when this happens, ___________ is formed, from which an igneous rock may once again crystallize.",
	"id": null,
	"topic_id": null
}, {
	"sub_cat_id": null,
	"answer": "an igneous rock",
	"category_id": null,
	"question": "All three types of rocks may be re-melted; when this happens, a new magma is formed, from which _______________ may once again crystallize.",
	"id": null,
	"topic_id": null
}, {
	"sub_cat_id": null,
	"answer": "Geologists",
	"category_id": null,
	"question": "__________ also study unlithified material, which typically comes from more recent deposits.",
	"id": null,
	"topic_id": null
}, {
	"sub_cat_id": null,
	"answer": "unlithified material",
	"category_id": null,
	"question": "Geologists also study ____________________, which typically comes from more recent deposits.",
	"id": null,
	"topic_id": null
}, {
	"sub_cat_id": null,
	"answer": "These materials",
	"category_id": null,
	"question": "_______________ are superficial deposits which lie above the bedrock.",
	"id": null,
	"topic_id": null
}, {
	"sub_cat_id": null,
	"answer": "These materials",
	"category_id": null,
	"question": "Because of this, the study of such material is often known as Quaternary geology, after the recent Quaternary Period.",
	"id": null,
	"topic_id": null
}, {
	"sub_cat_id": null,
	"answer": "mantle convection currents",
	"category_id": null,
	"question": "There is an intimate coupling between the movement of the plates on the surface and the convection of the mantle: oceanic plate motions and __________________________ always move in the same direction, because the oceanic lithosphere is the rigid upper thermal boundary layer of the convecting mantle.",
	"id": null,
	"topic_id": null
}, {
	"sub_cat_id": null,
	"answer": "the oceanic lithosphere",
	"category_id": null,
	"question": "There is an intimate coupling between the movement of the plates on the surface and the convection of the mantle: oceanic plate motions and mantle convection currents always move in the same direction, because _______________________ is the rigid upper thermal boundary layer of the convecting mantle.",
	"id": null,
	"topic_id": null
}, {
	"sub_cat_id": null,
	"answer": "subducting slabs",
	"category_id": null,
	"question": "On this diagram, ________________ are in blue, and continental margins and a few plate boundaries are in red.",
	"id": null,
	"topic_id": null
}, {
	"category_id": null,
	"sub_cat_id": null,
	"topic_id": null,
	"answer": "researchers",
	"id": null,
	"question": "The intellectual origins of materials science stem from the Enlightenment, when ___________ began to use analytical thinking from chemistry, physics, and engineering to understand ancient, phenomenological observations in metallurgy and mineralogy."
}, {
	"category_id": null,
	"sub_cat_id": null,
	"topic_id": null,
	"answer": "researchers",
	"id": null,
	"question": "Materials science still incorporates elements of physics, chemistry, and engineering."
}, {
	"category_id": null,
	"sub_cat_id": null,
	"topic_id": null,
	"answer": "the field",
	"id": null,
	"question": "As such, _________ was long thought of[by whom?"
}, {
	"category_id": null,
	"sub_cat_id": null,
	"topic_id": null,
	"answer": "materials science",
	"id": null,
	"question": "In recent years,[when?"
}, {
	"category_id": null,
	"sub_cat_id": null,
	"topic_id": null,
	"answer": "humans",
	"id": null,
	"question": "Many of the most pressing scientific problems ______ currently face are due to the limitations of the materials that are available and, as a result, breakthroughs in materials science are likely to have a significant impact on the future of technology."
}, {
	"category_id": null,
	"sub_cat_id": null,
	"topic_id": null,
	"answer": "the materials",
	"id": null,
	"question": "Many of the most pressing scientific problems humans currently face are due to the limitations of _____________ that are available and, as a result, breakthroughs in materials science are likely to have a significant impact on the future of technology."
}, {
	"category_id": null,
	"sub_cat_id": null,
	"topic_id": null,
	"answer": "Materials scientists",
	"id": null,
	"question": "____________________ emphasize understanding how the history of a material (its processing) influences its structure, and thus the material's properties and performance."
}, {
	"category_id": null,
	"sub_cat_id": null,
	"topic_id": null,
	"answer": "This paradigm",
	"id": null,
	"question": "_____________ is used to advance understanding in a variety of research areas, including nanotechnology, biomaterials, and metallurgy."
}, {
	"category_id": null,
	"sub_cat_id": null,
	"topic_id": null,
	"answer": "Such investigations",
	"id": null,
	"question": "___________________ are key to understanding, for example, the causes of various aviation accidents."
}, {
	"category_id": null,
	"sub_cat_id": null,
	"topic_id": null,
	"answer": "materials science",
	"id": null,
	"question": "Originally deriving from the manufacture of ceramics and its putative derivative metallurgy, _________________ is one of the oldest forms of engineering and applied science."
}, {
	"category_id": null,
	"sub_cat_id": null,
	"topic_id": null,
	"answer": "space vehicles",
	"id": null,
	"question": "Important elements of modern materials science are a product of the space race: the understanding and engineering of the metallic alloys, and silica and carbon materials, used in the construction of ______________ enabling the exploration of space."
}, {
	"category_id": null,
	"sub_cat_id": null,
	"topic_id": null,
	"answer": "Materials science",
	"id": null,
	"question": "_________________ has driven, and been driven by, the development of revolutionary technologies such as plastics, semiconductors, and biomaterials."
}, {
	"category_id": null,
	"sub_cat_id": null,
	"topic_id": null,
	"answer": "A material",
	"id": null,
	"question": "__________ is defined as a substance (most often a solid, but other condensed phases can be included) that is intended to be used for certain applications."
}, {
	"category_id": null,
	"sub_cat_id": null,
	"topic_id": null,
	"answer": "A material",
	"id": null,
	"question": "There are a myriad of materials around us\u2014they can be found in anything from buildings to spacecraft."
}, {
	"category_id": null,
	"sub_cat_id": null,
	"topic_id": null,
	"answer": "certain applications.[6] There",
	"id": null,
	"question": "A material is defined as a substance (most often a solid, but other condensed phases can be included) that is intended to be used for certain applications."
}, {
	"category_id": null,
	"sub_cat_id": null,
	"topic_id": null,
	"answer": "Materials",
	"id": null,
	"question": "_________ can generally be divided into two classes: crystalline and non-crystalline."
}, {
	"category_id": null,
	"sub_cat_id": null,
	"topic_id": null,
	"answer": "a materials scientist",
	"id": null,
	"question": "Once _____________________ knows about this structure-property correlation, he/she can then go on to study the relative performance of a material in a certain application."
}, {
	"category_id": null,
	"sub_cat_id": null,
	"topic_id": null,
	"answer": "he/she",
	"id": null,
	"question": "Once a materials scientist knows about this structure-property correlation, ______ can then go on to study the relative performance of a material in a certain application."
}, {
	"category_id": null,
	"id": null,
	"topic_id": null,
	"sub_cat_id": null,
	"question": "____________ needs additional citations for verification.",
	"answer": "This article"
}, {
	"category_id": null,
	"id": null,
	"topic_id": null,
	"sub_cat_id": null,
	"question": "Please help improve this article by adding _________ to reliable sources.",
	"answer": "citations"
}, {
	"category_id": null,
	"id": null,
	"topic_id": null,
	"sub_cat_id": null,
	"question": "____________ is the applied science devoted to the study of food.",
	"answer": "Food science"
}, {
	"category_id": null,
	"id": null,
	"topic_id": null,
	"sub_cat_id": null,
	"question": "Activities of food scientists include the development of new food products, design of processes to produce these foods, choice of packaging materials, shelf-life studies, sensory evaluation of products using panels or potential consumers, as well as microbiological and chemical testing.",
	"answer": "Food scientists"
}, {
	"category_id": null,
	"id": null,
	"topic_id": null,
	"sub_cat_id": null,
	"question": "_______________ may study more fundamental phenomena that are directly linked to the production of food products and its properties.",
	"answer": "Food scientists"
}, {
	"category_id": null,
	"id": null,
	"topic_id": null,
	"sub_cat_id": null,
	"question": "____________ brings together multiple scientific disciplines.",
	"answer": "Food science"
}, {
	"category_id": null,
	"id": null,
	"topic_id": null,
	"sub_cat_id": null,
	"question": "______________ is the study of chemical processes and interactions of all biological and non-biological components of foods.",
	"answer": "Food chemistry"
}, {
	"category_id": null,
	"id": null,
	"topic_id": null,
	"sub_cat_id": null,
	"question": "The biological substances include such items as meat, poultry, lettuce, beer, and milk as examples.",
	"answer": "Food chemistry"
}, {
	"category_id": null,
	"id": null,
	"topic_id": null,
	"sub_cat_id": null,
	"question": "_______________ also encompasses how products change under certain food processing techniques and ways either to enhance or to prevent them from happening.",
	"answer": "This discipline"
}, {
	"category_id": null,
	"id": null,
	"topic_id": null,
	"sub_cat_id": null,
	"question": "_______________________ is the study of both physical and chemical interactions in foods in terms of physical and chemical principles applied to food systems, as well as the application of physicochemical techniques and instrumentation for the study and analysis of foods.",
	"answer": "Food physical chemistry"
}, {
	"category_id": null,
	"id": null,
	"topic_id": null,
	"sub_cat_id": null,
	"question": "Food engineering is ________________________ used to manufacture food.",
	"answer": "the industrial processes"
}, {
	"category_id": null,
	"id": null,
	"topic_id": null,
	"sub_cat_id": null,
	"question": "Food microbiology is the study of __________________ that inhabit, create, or contaminate food, including the study of microorganisms causing food spoilage.",
	"answer": "the microorganisms"
}, {
	"category_id": null,
	"id": null,
	"topic_id": null,
	"sub_cat_id": null,
	"question": "Good\" bacteria, however, such as probiotics, are becoming increasingly important in food science.",
	"answer": "the microorganisms"
}, {
	"category_id": null,
	"id": null,
	"topic_id": null,
	"sub_cat_id": null,
	"question": "In addition, microorganisms are essential for the production of foods such as cheese, yogurt, bread, beer, wine and, other fermented foods.",
	"answer": "the microorganisms"
}, {
	"category_id": null,
	"id": null,
	"topic_id": null,
	"sub_cat_id": null,
	"question": "Food microbiology is the study of the ______________ that inhabit, create, or contaminate food, including the study of ______________ causing food spoilage.",
	"answer": "microorganisms"
}, {
	"category_id": null,
	"id": null,
	"topic_id": null,
	"sub_cat_id": null,
	"question": "In addition, ______________ are essential for the production of foods such as cheese, yogurt, bread, beer, wine and, other fermented foods.",
	"answer": "microorganisms"
}, {
	"category_id": null,
	"id": null,
	"topic_id": null,
	"sub_cat_id": null,
	"question": "______________ is packaging of food to preserve food after it has been processed and contain it through distribution.",
	"answer": "Food packaging"
}, {
	"category_id": null,
	"id": null,
	"topic_id": null,
	"sub_cat_id": null,
	"question": "__________________ is to provide physical and barrier protection for food.",
	"answer": "Its main objective"
}, {
	"category_id": null,
	"id": null,
	"topic_id": null,
	"sub_cat_id": null,
	"question": "______________ is mostly done by using packaging machines.",
	"answer": "Food packaging"
}, {
	"category_id": null,
	"id": null,
	"topic_id": null,
	"sub_cat_id": null,
	"question": "_______________ is the technological aspects.",
	"answer": "Food technology"
}, {
	"category_id": null,
	"id": null,
	"topic_id": null,
	"sub_cat_id": null,
	"question": "______________\u2019s development in 1810 of the canning process was a decisive event.",
	"answer": "Nicolas Appert"
}, {
	"category_id": null,
	"id": null,
	"topic_id": null,
	"sub_cat_id": null,
	"question": "___________ wasn\u2019t called canning then and Appert did not really know the principle on which his process worked, but canning has had a major impact on food preservation techniques.",
	"answer": "The process"
}, {
	"category_id": null,
	"id": null,
	"topic_id": null,
	"sub_cat_id": null,
	"question": "The process wasn\u2019t called canning then and ______ did not really know the principle on which his process worked, but canning has had a major impact on food preservation techniques.",
	"answer": "Appert"
}, {
	"category_id": null,
	"id": null,
	"topic_id": null,
	"sub_cat_id": null,
	"question": "The process wasn\u2019t called _______ then and Appert did not really know the principle on which his process worked, but _______ has had a major impact on food preservation techniques.",
	"answer": "canning"
}, {
	"category_id": null,
	"id": null,
	"topic_id": null,
	"sub_cat_id": null,
	"question": "________________ is the study of how consumers' senses perceive food.",
	"answer": "Sensory analysis"
}, {
	"category_id": null,
	"id": null,
	"topic_id": null,
	"sub_cat_id": null,
	"question": "_____ maintains more than 50 sites across Australia and biological control research stations in France and Mexico.",
	"answer": "CSIRO"
}, {
	"answer": "Food chemistry",
	"id": null,
	"category_id": null,
	"question": "______________ is the study of chemical processes and interactions of all biological and non-biological components of foods.",
	"sub_cat_id": null,
	"topic_id": null
}, {
	"answer": "Food chemistry",
	"id": null,
	"category_id": null,
	"question": "The biological substances include such items as meat, poultry, lettuce, beer, and milk as examples.",
	"sub_cat_id": null,
	"topic_id": null
}, {
	"answer": "This discipline",
	"id": null,
	"category_id": null,
	"question": "_______________ also encompasses how products change under certain food processing techniques and ways either to enhance or to prevent them from happening.",
	"sub_cat_id": null,
	"topic_id": null
}, {
	"answer": "microorganisms",
	"id": null,
	"category_id": null,
	"question": "An example of enhancing a process would be to encourage fermentation of dairy products with ______________ that convert lactose to lactic acid; an example of preventing a process would be stopping the browning on the surface of freshly cut Red Delicious apples using lemon juice or other acidulated water.",
	"sub_cat_id": null,
	"topic_id": null
}, {
	"answer": "a process",
	"id": null,
	"category_id": null,
	"question": "An example of enhancing _________ would be to encourage fermentation of dairy products with microorganisms that convert lactose to lactic acid; an example of preventing _________ would be stopping the browning on the surface of freshly cut Red Delicious apples using lemon juice or other acidulated water.",
	"sub_cat_id": null,
	"topic_id": null
}, {
	"answer": "Red Delicious apples",
	"id": null,
	"category_id": null,
	"question": "An example of enhancing a process would be to encourage fermentation of dairy products with microorganisms that convert lactose to lactic acid; an example of preventing a process would be stopping the browning on the surface of freshly cut ____________________ using lemon juice or other acidulated water.",
	"sub_cat_id": null,
	"topic_id": null
}, {
	"answer": "the United Kingdom",
	"id": null,
	"category_id": null,
	"question": "For example, Davy published Elements of Agricultural Chemistry, in a Course of Lectures for the Board of Agriculture (1813) in __________________ which would serve as a foundation for the profession worldwide, going into a fifth edition.",
	"sub_cat_id": null,
	"topic_id": null
}, {
	"answer": "Carl Wilhelm Scheele",
	"id": null,
	"category_id": null,
	"question": "Earlier work included that by ____________________ who isolated malic acid from apples in 1785.",
	"sub_cat_id": null,
	"topic_id": null
}, {
	"answer": "analytical methods",
	"id": null,
	"category_id": null,
	"question": "In 1874 the Society of Public Analysts was formed, with the aim of applying __________________ to the benefit of the public.",
	"sub_cat_id": null,
	"topic_id": null
}, {
	"answer": "analytical methods",
	"id": null,
	"category_id": null,
	"question": "Its early experiments were based on bread, milk and wine.",
	"sub_cat_id": null,
	"topic_id": null
}, {
	"answer": "contamination issues",
	"id": null,
	"category_id": null,
	"question": "It was also out of concern for the quality of the food supply, mainly food adulteration and ____________________ that would first stem from intentional contamination to later with chemical food additives by the 1950s.",
	"sub_cat_id": null,
	"topic_id": null
}, {
	"answer": "Food chemistry concepts",
	"id": null,
	"category_id": null,
	"question": "_______________________ are often drawn from rheology, theories of transport phenomena, physical and chemical thermodynamics, chemical bonds and interaction forces, quantum mechanics and reaction kinetics, biopolymer science, colloidal interactions, nucleation, glass transitions and freezing/disordered or noncrystalline solids, and thus has Food Physical Chemistry as a foundation area.",
	"sub_cat_id": null,
	"topic_id": null
}, {
	"answer": "water",
	"id": null,
	"category_id": null,
	"question": "A major component of food is _____, which can encompass anywhere from 50% in meat products to 95% in lettuce, cabbage, and tomato products.",
	"sub_cat_id": null,
	"topic_id": null
}, {
	"answer": "water activity",
	"id": null,
	"category_id": null,
	"question": "One way this is measured in food is by ______________ which is very important in the shelf life of many foods during processing.",
	"sub_cat_id": null,
	"topic_id": null
}, {
	"answer": "a monosaccharide",
	"id": null,
	"category_id": null,
	"question": "The simplest version of a carbohydrate is ________________ which possesses the properties of carbon, hydrogen, and oxygen in a 1:2:1 ratio under a general formula of CnH2nOn where n is a minimum of 3.",
	"sub_cat_id": null,
	"topic_id": null
}, {
	"answer": "Glucose",
	"id": null,
	"category_id": null,
	"question": "_______ is an example of a monosaccharide as is fructose.",
	"sub_cat_id": null,
	"topic_id": null
}, {
	"answer": "Sugar content",
	"id": null,
	"category_id": null,
	"question": "_____________ is commonly measured in degrees brix.",
	"sub_cat_id": null,
	"topic_id": null
}, {
	"answer": "The term lipid",
	"id": null,
	"category_id": null,
	"question": "______________ comprises a diverse range of molecules and to some extent is a catchall for relatively water-insoluble or nonpolar compounds of biological origin, including waxes, fatty acids (including essential fatty acids), fatty-acid derived phospholipids, sphingolipids, glycolipids and terpenoids, such as retinoids and steroids.",
	"sub_cat_id": null,
	"topic_id": null
}, {
	"answer": "Some lipids",
	"id": null,
	"category_id": null,
	"question": "___________ are linear aliphatic molecules, while others have ring structures.",
	"sub_cat_id": null,
	"topic_id": null
}, {
	"answer": "others",
	"id": null,
	"category_id": null,
	"question": "Some lipids are linear aliphatic molecules, while ______ have ring structures.",
	"sub_cat_id": null,
	"topic_id": null
}, {
	"answer": "Food chemistry",
	"id": null,
	"category_id": null,
	"question": "______________ is the study of chemical processes and interactions of all biological and non-biological components of foods.",
	"sub_cat_id": null,
	"topic_id": null
}, {
	"answer": "Food chemistry",
	"id": null,
	"category_id": null,
	"question": "The biological substances include such items as meat, poultry, lettuce, beer, and milk as examples.",
	"sub_cat_id": null,
	"topic_id": null
}, {
	"answer": "This discipline",
	"id": null,
	"category_id": null,
	"question": "_______________ also encompasses how products change under certain food processing techniques and ways either to enhance or to prevent them from happening.",
	"sub_cat_id": null,
	"topic_id": null
}, {
	"answer": "microorganisms",
	"id": null,
	"category_id": null,
	"question": "An example of enhancing a process would be to encourage fermentation of dairy products with ______________ that convert lactose to lactic acid; an example of preventing a process would be stopping the browning on the surface of freshly cut Red Delicious apples using lemon juice or other acidulated water.",
	"sub_cat_id": null,
	"topic_id": null
}, {
	"answer": "a process",
	"id": null,
	"category_id": null,
	"question": "An example of enhancing _________ would be to encourage fermentation of dairy products with microorganisms that convert lactose to lactic acid; an example of preventing _________ would be stopping the browning on the surface of freshly cut Red Delicious apples using lemon juice or other acidulated water.",
	"sub_cat_id": null,
	"topic_id": null
}, {
	"answer": "Red Delicious apples",
	"id": null,
	"category_id": null,
	"question": "An example of enhancing a process would be to encourage fermentation of dairy products with microorganisms that convert lactose to lactic acid; an example of preventing a process would be stopping the browning on the surface of freshly cut ____________________ using lemon juice or other acidulated water.",
	"sub_cat_id": null,
	"topic_id": null
}, {
	"answer": "the United Kingdom",
	"id": null,
	"category_id": null,
	"question": "For example, Davy published Elements of Agricultural Chemistry, in a Course of Lectures for the Board of Agriculture (1813) in __________________ which would serve as a foundation for the profession worldwide, going into a fifth edition.",
	"sub_cat_id": null,
	"topic_id": null
}, {
	"answer": "Carl Wilhelm Scheele",
	"id": null,
	"category_id": null,
	"question": "Earlier work included that by ____________________ who isolated malic acid from apples in 1785.",
	"sub_cat_id": null,
	"topic_id": null
}, {
	"answer": "analytical methods",
	"id": null,
	"category_id": null,
	"question": "In 1874 the Society of Public Analysts was formed, with the aim of applying __________________ to the benefit of the public.",
	"sub_cat_id": null,
	"topic_id": null
}, {
	"answer": "analytical methods",
	"id": null,
	"category_id": null,
	"question": "Its early experiments were based on bread, milk and wine.",
	"sub_cat_id": null,
	"topic_id": null
}, {
	"answer": "contamination issues",
	"id": null,
	"category_id": null,
	"question": "It was also out of concern for the quality of the food supply, mainly food adulteration and ____________________ that would first stem from intentional contamination to later with chemical food additives by the 1950s.",
	"sub_cat_id": null,
	"topic_id": null
}, {
	"answer": "Food chemistry concepts",
	"id": null,
	"category_id": null,
	"question": "_______________________ are often drawn from rheology, theories of transport phenomena, physical and chemical thermodynamics, chemical bonds and interaction forces, quantum mechanics and reaction kinetics, biopolymer science, colloidal interactions, nucleation, glass transitions and freezing/disordered or noncrystalline solids, and thus has Food Physical Chemistry as a foundation area.",
	"sub_cat_id": null,
	"topic_id": null
}, {
	"answer": "water",
	"id": null,
	"category_id": null,
	"question": "A major component of food is _____, which can encompass anywhere from 50% in meat products to 95% in lettuce, cabbage, and tomato products.",
	"sub_cat_id": null,
	"topic_id": null
}, {
	"answer": "water activity",
	"id": null,
	"category_id": null,
	"question": "One way this is measured in food is by ______________ which is very important in the shelf life of many foods during processing.",
	"sub_cat_id": null,
	"topic_id": null
}, {
	"answer": "a monosaccharide",
	"id": null,
	"category_id": null,
	"question": "The simplest version of a carbohydrate is ________________ which possesses the properties of carbon, hydrogen, and oxygen in a 1:2:1 ratio under a general formula of CnH2nOn where n is a minimum of 3.",
	"sub_cat_id": null,
	"topic_id": null
}, {
	"answer": "Glucose",
	"id": null,
	"category_id": null,
	"question": "_______ is an example of a monosaccharide as is fructose.",
	"sub_cat_id": null,
	"topic_id": null
}, {
	"answer": "Sugar content",
	"id": null,
	"category_id": null,
	"question": "_____________ is commonly measured in degrees brix.",
	"sub_cat_id": null,
	"topic_id": null
}, {
	"answer": "The term lipid",
	"id": null,
	"category_id": null,
	"question": "______________ comprises a diverse range of molecules and to some extent is a catchall for relatively water-insoluble or nonpolar compounds of biological origin, including waxes, fatty acids (including essential fatty acids), fatty-acid derived phospholipids, sphingolipids, glycolipids and terpenoids, such as retinoids and steroids.",
	"sub_cat_id": null,
	"topic_id": null
}, {
	"answer": "Some lipids",
	"id": null,
	"category_id": null,
	"question": "___________ are linear aliphatic molecules, while others have ring structures.",
	"sub_cat_id": null,
	"topic_id": null
}, {
	"answer": "others",
	"id": null,
	"category_id": null,
	"question": "Some lipids are linear aliphatic molecules, while ______ have ring structures.",
	"sub_cat_id": null,
	"topic_id": null
}, {
	"answer": "This article",
	"id": null,
	"category_id": null,
	"question": "____________ is about nutrition in general.",
	"sub_cat_id": null,
	"topic_id": null
}, {
	"answer": "Nutrition",
	"id": null,
	"category_id": null,
	"question": "_________ is the science that interprets the interaction of nutrients and other substances in food (e.",
	"sub_cat_id": null,
	"topic_id": null
}, {
	"answer": "the science",
	"id": null,
	"category_id": null,
	"question": "Nutrition is ___________ that interprets the interaction of nutrients and other substances in food (e.",
	"sub_cat_id": null,
	"topic_id": null
}, {
	"answer": "what it eats",
	"id": null,
	"category_id": null,
	"question": "The diet of an organism is ____________, which is largely determined by the availability, the processing and palatability of foods.",
	"sub_cat_id": null,
	"topic_id": null
}, {
	"answer": "health professionals",
	"id": null,
	"category_id": null,
	"question": "Registered dietitian nutritionists (RDs or RDNs)[2] are ____________________ qualified to provide safe, evidence-based dietary advice which includes a review of what is eaten, a thorough review of nutritional health, and a personalized nutritional treatment plan.",
	"sub_cat_id": null,
	"topic_id": null
}, {
	"answer": "health professionals",
	"id": null,
	"category_id": null,
	"question": "Certified Clinical Nutritionists or CCNs, are trained ____________________ who also offer dietary advice on the role of nutrition in chronic disease, including possible prevention or remediation by addressing nutritional deficiencies before resorting to drugs.",
	"sub_cat_id": null,
	"topic_id": null
}, {
	"answer": "health professionals",
	"id": null,
	"category_id": null,
	"question": "Government regulation especially in terms of licensing, is currently less universal for the CCN than that of RD or RDN.",
	"sub_cat_id": null,
	"topic_id": null
}, {
	"answer": "regulation",
	"id": null,
	"category_id": null,
	"question": "Certified Clinical Nutritionists or CCNs, are trained health professionals who also offer dietary advice on the role of nutrition in chronic disease, including possible prevention or remediation by addressing nutritional deficiencies before resorting to drugs.",
	"sub_cat_id": null,
	"topic_id": null
}, {
	"answer": "regulation",
	"id": null,
	"category_id": null,
	"question": "Government __________ especially in terms of licensing, is currently less universal for the CCN than that of RD or RDN.",
	"sub_cat_id": null,
	"topic_id": null
}, {
	"answer": "potential CNS candidate",
	"id": null,
	"category_id": null,
	"question": "In order to become board certified, _______________________ must pass an examination, much like Registered Dieticians.",
	"sub_cat_id": null,
	"topic_id": null
}, {
	"answer": "The first",
	"id": null,
	"category_id": null,
	"question": "_________ recorded dietary advice, carved into a Babylonian stone tablet in about 2500 BC, cautioned those with pain inside to avoid eating onions for three days.",
	"sub_cat_id": null,
	"topic_id": null
}, {
	"answer": "those",
	"id": null,
	"category_id": null,
	"question": "The first recorded dietary advice, carved into a Babylonian stone tablet in about 2500 BC, cautioned _____ with pain inside to avoid eating onions for three days.",
	"sub_cat_id": null,
	"topic_id": null
}, {
	"answer": "Scurvy",
	"id": null,
	"category_id": null,
	"question": "______, later found to be a vitamin C deficiency, was first described in 1500 BC in the Ebers Papyrus.",
	"sub_cat_id": null,
	"topic_id": null
}, {
	"answer": "The first",
	"id": null,
	"category_id": null,
	"question": "_________ recorded nutritional experiment with human subjects is found in the Bible's Book of Daniel.",
	"sub_cat_id": null,
	"topic_id": null
}, {
	"answer": "Cato the Elder",
	"id": null,
	"category_id": null,
	"question": "In the 2nd century BC, ______________ believed that cabbage (or the urine of cabbage-eaters) could cure digestive diseases, ulcers, warts, and intoxication.",
	"sub_cat_id": null,
	"topic_id": null
}, {
	"answer": "The states",
	"id": null,
	"category_id": null,
	"question": "__________ are made up of pairs of attributes (hot and moist, cold and moist, hot and dry, and cold and dry), which are made of four humours: blood, phlegm, green (or yellow) bile, and black bile (the bodily form of the elements).",
	"sub_cat_id": null,
	"topic_id": null
}, {
	"answer": "Galen",
	"id": null,
	"category_id": null,
	"question": "_____ thought that for a person to have gout, kidney stones, or arthritis was scandalous, which Gratzer likens to Samuel Butler's Erehwon (1872) where sickness is a crime.",
	"sub_cat_id": null,
	"topic_id": null
}, {
	"answer": "Paracelsus",
	"id": null,
	"category_id": null,
	"question": "In the 1500s, __________ was probably the first to criticize Galen publicly.",
	"sub_cat_id": null,
	"topic_id": null
}, {
	"answer": "Paracelsus",
	"id": null,
	"category_id": null,
	"question": "Also in the 16th century, scientist and artist Leonardo da Vinci compared metabolism to a burning candle.",
	"sub_cat_id": null,
	"topic_id": null
}, {
	"answer": "metabolism",
	"id": null,
	"category_id": null,
	"question": "In the 1500s, Paracelsus was probably the first to criticize Galen publicly.",
	"sub_cat_id": null,
	"topic_id": null
}, {
	"answer": "metabolism",
	"id": null,
	"category_id": null,
	"question": "Also in the 16th century, scientist and artist Leonardo da Vinci compared __________ to a burning candle.",
	"sub_cat_id": null,
	"topic_id": null
}, {
	"answer": "Leonardo",
	"id": null,
	"category_id": null,
	"question": "________ did not publish his works on this subject, but he was not afraid of thinking for himself and he definitely disagreed with Galen.",
	"sub_cat_id": null,
	"topic_id": null
}, {
	"answer": "Leonardo",
	"id": null,
	"category_id": null,
	"question": "Ultimately, 16th century works of Andreas Vesalius, sometimes called the father of modern medicine, overturned Galen's ideas.",
	"sub_cat_id": null,
	"topic_id": null
}, {
	"answer": "Leonardo",
	"id": null,
	"category_id": null,
	"question": "He was followed by piercing thought amalgamated with the era's mysticism and religion sometimes fueled by the mechanics of Newton and Galileo.",
	"sub_cat_id": null,
	"topic_id": null
}, {
	"sub_cat_id": null,
	"topic_id": null,
	"answer": "Electromagnetism",
	"question": "________________ is a branch of physics which involves the study of the electromagnetic force, a type of physical interaction that occurs between electrically charged particles.",
	"category_id": null,
	"id": null
}, {
	"sub_cat_id": null,
	"topic_id": null,
	"answer": "The electromagnetic force",
	"question": "_________________________ usually shows electromagnetic fields, such as electric fields, magnetic fields, and light.",
	"category_id": null,
	"id": null
}, {
	"sub_cat_id": null,
	"topic_id": null,
	"answer": "The electromagnetic force",
	"question": "_________________________ is one of the four fundamental interactions in nature.",
	"category_id": null,
	"id": null
}, {
	"sub_cat_id": null,
	"topic_id": null,
	"answer": "The word electromagnetism",
	"question": "_________________________ is a compound form of two Greek terms, \u1f24\u03bb\u03b5\u03ba\u03c4\u03c1\u03bf\u03bd, \u0113lektron, \"amber\", and \u03bc\u03b1\u03b3\u03bd\u1fc6\u03c4\u03b9\u03c2 \u03bb\u03af\u03b8\u03bf\u03c2 magn\u0113tis lithos, which means \"magnesian stone\", a type of iron ore.",
	"category_id": null,
	"id": null
}, {
	"sub_cat_id": null,
	"topic_id": null,
	"answer": "The electromagnetic force",
	"question": "_________________________ plays a major role in determining the internal properties of most objects encountered in daily life.",
	"category_id": null,
	"id": null
}, {
	"sub_cat_id": null,
	"topic_id": null,
	"answer": "most objects",
	"question": "The electromagnetic force plays a major role in determining the internal properties of ____________ encountered in daily life.",
	"category_id": null,
	"id": null
}, {
	"sub_cat_id": null,
	"topic_id": null,
	"answer": "Ordinary matter",
	"question": "_______________ takes its form as a result of intermolecular forces between individual molecules in matter.",
	"category_id": null,
	"id": null
}, {
	"sub_cat_id": null,
	"topic_id": null,
	"answer": "atoms",
	"question": "Electrons are bound by electromagnetic wave mechanics into orbitals around atomic nuclei to form _____, which are the building blocks of molecules.",
	"category_id": null,
	"id": null
}, {
	"sub_cat_id": null,
	"topic_id": null,
	"answer": "neighboring atoms",
	"question": "This governs the processes involved in chemistry, which arise from interactions between the electrons of _________________, which are in turn determined by the interaction between electromagnetic force and the momentum of the electrons.",
	"category_id": null,
	"id": null
}, {
	"sub_cat_id": null,
	"topic_id": null,
	"answer": "electric fields",
	"question": "In classical electrodynamics, _______________ are described as electric potential and electric current.",
	"category_id": null,
	"id": null
}, {
	"sub_cat_id": null,
	"topic_id": null,
	"answer": "magnetic fields",
	"question": "In Faraday's law, _______________ are associated with electromagnetic induction and magnetism, and Maxwell's equations describe how electric and _______________ are generated and altered by each other and by charges and currents.",
	"category_id": null,
	"id": null
}, {
	"sub_cat_id": null,
	"topic_id": null,
	"answer": "by each other",
	"question": "In Faraday's law, magnetic fields are associated with electromagnetic induction and magnetism, and Maxwell's equations describe how electric and magnetic fields are generated and altered _____________ and by charges and currents.",
	"category_id": null,
	"id": null
}, {
	"sub_cat_id": null,
	"topic_id": null,
	"answer": "electromagnetism",
	"question": "Although ________________ is considered one of the four fundamental forces, at high energy the weak force and ________________ are unified.",
	"category_id": null,
	"id": null
}, {
	"sub_cat_id": null,
	"topic_id": null,
	"answer": "electricity and magnetism",
	"question": "Originally, _________________________ were thought of as two separate forces.",
	"category_id": null,
	"id": null
}, {
	"sub_cat_id": null,
	"topic_id": null,
	"answer": "by one force",
	"question": "This view changed, however, with the publication of James Clerk Maxwell's 1873 A Treatise on Electricity and Magnetism in which the interactions of positive and negative charges were shown to be regulated ____________.",
	"category_id": null,
	"id": null
}, {
	"sub_cat_id": null,
	"topic_id": null,
	"answer": "Electric charges",
	"question": "________________ attract or repel one another with a force inversely proportional to the square of the distance between them: unlike charges attract, like ones repel.",
	"category_id": null,
	"id": null
}, {
	"sub_cat_id": null,
	"topic_id": null,
	"answer": "every north pole",
	"question": "Magnetic poles (or states of polarization at individual points) attract or repel one another in a similar way and always come in pairs: ________________ is yoked to a south pole.",
	"category_id": null,
	"id": null
}, {
	"sub_cat_id": null,
	"topic_id": null,
	"answer": "A current",
	"question": "_________ is induced in a loop of wire when it is moved toward or away from a magnetic field, or a magnet is moved towards or away from it; the direction of current depends on that of the movement.",
	"category_id": null,
	"id": null
}, {
	"sub_cat_id": null,
	"topic_id": null,
	"answer": "Hans Christian \u00d8rsted",
	"question": "While preparing for an evening lecture on 21 April 1820, _____________________ made a surprising observation.",
	"category_id": null,
	"id": null
}, {
	"sub_cat_id": null,
	"category_id": null,
	"id": null,
	"topic_id": null,
	"question": "Astrophysics is the branch of astronomy that employs the principles of physics and chemistry \"to ascertain the nature of the heavenly bodies, rather than their positions or motions in space.",
	"answer": "the objects"
}, {
	"sub_cat_id": null,
	"category_id": null,
	"id": null,
	"topic_id": null,
	"question": "Among ___________ studied are the Sun, other stars, galaxies, extrasolar planets, the interstellar medium and the cosmic microwave background.",
	"answer": "the objects"
}, {
	"sub_cat_id": null,
	"category_id": null,
	"id": null,
	"topic_id": null,
	"question": "Their emissions are examined across all parts of the electromagnetic spectrum, and the properties examined include luminosity, density, temperature, and chemical composition.",
	"answer": "the objects"
}, {
	"sub_cat_id": null,
	"category_id": null,
	"id": null,
	"topic_id": null,
	"question": "Among the objects studied are the Sun, other stars, galaxies, extrasolar planets, the interstellar medium and the cosmic microwave background.",
	"answer": "Their emissions"
}, {
	"sub_cat_id": null,
	"category_id": null,
	"id": null,
	"topic_id": null,
	"question": "_______________ are examined across all parts of the electromagnetic spectrum, and the properties examined include luminosity, density, temperature, and chemical composition.",
	"answer": "Their emissions"
}, {
	"sub_cat_id": null,
	"category_id": null,
	"id": null,
	"topic_id": null,
	"question": "Because astrophysics is a very broad subject, _______________ typically apply many disciplines of physics, including mechanics, electromagnetism, statistical mechanics, thermodynamics, quantum mechanics, relativity, nuclear and particle physics, and atomic and molecular physics.",
	"answer": "astrophysicists"
}, {
	"sub_cat_id": null,
	"category_id": null,
	"id": null,
	"topic_id": null,
	"question": "Although _________ is as ancient as recorded history itself, it was long separated from the study of terrestrial physics.",
	"answer": "astronomy"
}, {
	"sub_cat_id": null,
	"category_id": null,
	"id": null,
	"topic_id": null,
	"question": "In the Aristotelian worldview, bodies in the sky appeared to be unchanging spheres whose only motion was uniform motion in a circle, while the earthly world was the realm which underwent growth and decay and in which ______________ was in a straight line and ended when the moving object reached its goal.",
	"answer": "natural motion"
}, {
	"sub_cat_id": null,
	"category_id": null,
	"id": null,
	"topic_id": null,
	"question": "In the Aristotelian worldview, bodies in the sky appeared to be unchanging spheres whose only motion was uniform motion in a circle, while the earthly world was _________ which underwent growth and decay and in which natural motion was in a straight line and ended when the moving object reached its goal.",
	"answer": "the realm"
}, {
	"sub_cat_id": null,
	"category_id": null,
	"id": null,
	"topic_id": null,
	"question": "In the Aristotelian worldview, bodies in the sky appeared to be unchanging spheres whose only motion was uniform motion in a circle, while the earthly world was the realm which underwent growth and decay and in which natural motion was in a straight line and ended when _________________ reached its goal.",
	"answer": "the moving object"
}, {
	"sub_cat_id": null,
	"category_id": null,
	"id": null,
	"topic_id": null,
	"question": "Among _____ who extended the study of solar and stellar spectra was Norman Lockyer, who in 1868 detected bright, as well as dark, lines in solar spectra.",
	"answer": "those"
}, {
	"sub_cat_id": null,
	"category_id": null,
	"id": null,
	"topic_id": null,
	"question": "Among those who extended the study of solar and stellar spectra was ______________, who in 1868 detected bright, as well as dark, lines in solar spectra.",
	"answer": "Norman Lockyer"
}, {
	"sub_cat_id": null,
	"category_id": null,
	"id": null,
	"topic_id": null,
	"question": "He thus claimed the line represented _____________, which was called helium, after the Greek Helios, the Sun personified.",
	"answer": "a new element"
}, {
	"sub_cat_id": null,
	"category_id": null,
	"id": null,
	"topic_id": null,
	"question": "In 1885, Edward C.",
	"answer": "Edward C. Pickering"
}, {
	"sub_cat_id": null,
	"category_id": null,
	"id": null,
	"topic_id": null,
	"question": "Pickering undertook an ambitious program of stellar spectral classification at Harvard College Observatory, in which a team of woman computers, notably Williamina Fleming, Antonia Maury, and Annie Jump Cannon, classified the spectra recorded on photographic plates.",
	"answer": "Edward C. Pickering"
}, {
	"sub_cat_id": null,
	"category_id": null,
	"id": null,
	"topic_id": null,
	"question": "Pickering undertook an ambitious program of stellar spectral classification at Harvard College Observatory, in which a team of woman computers, notably Williamina Fleming, Antonia Maury, and Annie Jump Cannon, classified ___________ recorded on photographic plates.",
	"answer": "the spectra"
}, {
	"sub_cat_id": null,
	"category_id": null,
	"id": null,
	"topic_id": null,
	"question": "In 1925 Cecilia Helena Payne (later Cecilia Payne-Gaposchkin) wrote an influential doctoral dissertation at Radcliffe College, in which she applied ionization theory to stellar atmospheres to relate ____________________ to the temperature of stars.",
	"answer": "the spectral classes"
}, {
	"sub_cat_id": null,
	"category_id": null,
	"id": null,
	"topic_id": null,
	"question": "Most significantly, she discovered that hydrogen and helium were the principal components of stars.",
	"answer": "the spectral classes"
}, {
	"sub_cat_id": null,
	"category_id": null,
	"id": null,
	"topic_id": null,
	"question": "______________ was so unexpected that her dissertation readers convinced her to modify the conclusion before publication.",
	"answer": "This discovery"
}, {
	"sub_cat_id": null,
	"category_id": null,
	"id": null,
	"topic_id": null,
	"question": "However, later ________ confirmed her discovery.",
	"answer": "research"
}, {
	"sub_cat_id": null,
	"category_id": null,
	"id": null,
	"topic_id": null,
	"question": "_______________________ is a division of the astronomical science that is concerned with recording data, in contrast with theoretical astrophysics, which is mainly concerned with finding out the measurable implications of physical models.",
	"answer": "Observational astronomy"
}, {
	"sub_cat_id": null,
	"category_id": null,
	"id": null,
	"topic_id": null,
	"question": "Observational astronomy is a division of ________________________ that is concerned with recording data, in contrast with theoretical astrophysics, which is mainly concerned with finding out the measurable implications of physical models.",
	"answer": "the astronomical science"
}, {
	"sub_cat_id": null,
	"category_id": null,
	"id": null,
	"topic_id": null,
	"question": "Observational astronomy is a division of the astronomical science that is concerned ___________________, in contrast with theoretical astrophysics, which is mainly concerned with finding out the measurable implications of physical models.",
	"answer": "with recording data"
}, {
	"sub_cat_id": null,
	"category_id": null,
	"id": null,
	"topic_id": null,
	"question": "Observational astronomy is a division of the astronomical science that is concerned with recording data, in contrast with ________________________, which is mainly concerned with finding out the measurable implications of physical models.",
	"answer": "theoretical astrophysics"
}, {
	"sub_cat_id": null,
	"category_id": null,
	"id": null,
	"topic_id": null,
	"question": "It is ____________ of observing celestial objects by using telescopes and other astronomical apparatus.",
	"answer": "the practice"
}, {
	"sub_cat_id": null,
	"category_id": null,
	"id": null,
	"topic_id": null,
	"question": "Example ______________ are radio waves, usually emitted by cold objects such as interstellar gas and dust clouds; the cosmic microwave background radiation which is the redshifted light from the Big Bang; pulsars, which were first detected at microwave frequencies.",
	"answer": "areas of study"
}, {
	"sub_cat_id": null,
	"category_id": null,
	"id": null,
	"topic_id": null,
	"question": "Example areas of study are radio waves, usually emitted _______________ such as interstellar gas and dust clouds; the cosmic microwave background radiation which is the redshifted light from the Big Bang; pulsars, which were first detected at microwave frequencies.",
	"answer": "by cold objects"
}, {
	"sub_cat_id": null,
	"category_id": null,
	"id": null,
	"topic_id": null,
	"question": "Example areas of study are radio waves, usually emitted by cold objects such as interstellar gas and dust clouds; the cosmic microwave background radiation which is the redshifted light from the Big Bang; _______, which were first detected at microwave frequencies.",
	"answer": "pulsars"
}, {
	"sub_cat_id": null,
	"category_id": null,
	"id": null,
	"topic_id": null,
	"question": "_____________________ are usually made with telescopes similar to the familiar optical telescopes.",
	"answer": "Infrared observations"
}, {
	"sub_cat_id": null,
	"category_id": null,
	"id": null,
	"topic_id": null,
	"question": "Astrophysics is the branch of astronomy that employs the principles of physics and chemistry \"to ascertain the nature of the heavenly bodies, rather than their positions or motions in space.",
	"answer": "the objects"
}, {
	"sub_cat_id": null,
	"category_id": null,
	"id": null,
	"topic_id": null,
	"question": "Among ___________ studied are the Sun, other stars, galaxies, extrasolar planets, the interstellar medium and the cosmic microwave background.",
	"answer": "the objects"
}, {
	"sub_cat_id": null,
	"category_id": null,
	"id": null,
	"topic_id": null,
	"question": "Their emissions are examined across all parts of the electromagnetic spectrum, and the properties examined include luminosity, density, temperature, and chemical composition.",
	"answer": "the objects"
}, {
	"sub_cat_id": null,
	"category_id": null,
	"id": null,
	"topic_id": null,
	"question": "Among the objects studied are the Sun, other stars, galaxies, extrasolar planets, the interstellar medium and the cosmic microwave background.",
	"answer": "Their emissions"
}, {
	"sub_cat_id": null,
	"category_id": null,
	"id": null,
	"topic_id": null,
	"question": "_______________ are examined across all parts of the electromagnetic spectrum, and the properties examined include luminosity, density, temperature, and chemical composition.",
	"answer": "Their emissions"
}, {
	"sub_cat_id": null,
	"category_id": null,
	"id": null,
	"topic_id": null,
	"question": "Because astrophysics is a very broad subject, _______________ typically apply many disciplines of physics, including mechanics, electromagnetism, statistical mechanics, thermodynamics, quantum mechanics, relativity, nuclear and particle physics, and atomic and molecular physics.",
	"answer": "astrophysicists"
}, {
	"sub_cat_id": null,
	"category_id": null,
	"id": null,
	"topic_id": null,
	"question": "Although _________ is as ancient as recorded history itself, it was long separated from the study of terrestrial physics.",
	"answer": "astronomy"
}, {
	"sub_cat_id": null,
	"category_id": null,
	"id": null,
	"topic_id": null,
	"question": "In the Aristotelian worldview, bodies in the sky appeared to be unchanging spheres whose only motion was uniform motion in a circle, while the earthly world was the realm which underwent growth and decay and in which ______________ was in a straight line and ended when the moving object reached its goal.",
	"answer": "natural motion"
}, {
	"sub_cat_id": null,
	"category_id": null,
	"id": null,
	"topic_id": null,
	"question": "In the Aristotelian worldview, bodies in the sky appeared to be unchanging spheres whose only motion was uniform motion in a circle, while the earthly world was _________ which underwent growth and decay and in which natural motion was in a straight line and ended when the moving object reached its goal.",
	"answer": "the realm"
}, {
	"sub_cat_id": null,
	"category_id": null,
	"id": null,
	"topic_id": null,
	"question": "In the Aristotelian worldview, bodies in the sky appeared to be unchanging spheres whose only motion was uniform motion in a circle, while the earthly world was the realm which underwent growth and decay and in which natural motion was in a straight line and ended when _________________ reached its goal.",
	"answer": "the moving object"
}, {
	"sub_cat_id": null,
	"category_id": null,
	"id": null,
	"topic_id": null,
	"question": "Among _____ who extended the study of solar and stellar spectra was Norman Lockyer, who in 1868 detected bright, as well as dark, lines in solar spectra.",
	"answer": "those"
}, {
	"sub_cat_id": null,
	"category_id": null,
	"id": null,
	"topic_id": null,
	"question": "Among those who extended the study of solar and stellar spectra was ______________, who in 1868 detected bright, as well as dark, lines in solar spectra.",
	"answer": "Norman Lockyer"
}, {
	"sub_cat_id": null,
	"category_id": null,
	"id": null,
	"topic_id": null,
	"question": "He thus claimed the line represented _____________, which was called helium, after the Greek Helios, the Sun personified.",
	"answer": "a new element"
}, {
	"sub_cat_id": null,
	"category_id": null,
	"id": null,
	"topic_id": null,
	"question": "In 1885, Edward C.",
	"answer": "Edward C. Pickering"
}, {
	"sub_cat_id": null,
	"category_id": null,
	"id": null,
	"topic_id": null,
	"question": "Pickering undertook an ambitious program of stellar spectral classification at Harvard College Observatory, in which a team of woman computers, notably Williamina Fleming, Antonia Maury, and Annie Jump Cannon, classified the spectra recorded on photographic plates.",
	"answer": "Edward C. Pickering"
}, {
	"sub_cat_id": null,
	"category_id": null,
	"id": null,
	"topic_id": null,
	"question": "Pickering undertook an ambitious program of stellar spectral classification at Harvard College Observatory, in which a team of woman computers, notably Williamina Fleming, Antonia Maury, and Annie Jump Cannon, classified ___________ recorded on photographic plates.",
	"answer": "the spectra"
}, {
	"sub_cat_id": null,
	"category_id": null,
	"id": null,
	"topic_id": null,
	"question": "In 1925 Cecilia Helena Payne (later Cecilia Payne-Gaposchkin) wrote an influential doctoral dissertation at Radcliffe College, in which she applied ionization theory to stellar atmospheres to relate ____________________ to the temperature of stars.",
	"answer": "the spectral classes"
}, {
	"sub_cat_id": null,
	"category_id": null,
	"id": null,
	"topic_id": null,
	"question": "Most significantly, she discovered that hydrogen and helium were the principal components of stars.",
	"answer": "the spectral classes"
}, {
	"sub_cat_id": null,
	"category_id": null,
	"id": null,
	"topic_id": null,
	"question": "______________ was so unexpected that her dissertation readers convinced her to modify the conclusion before publication.",
	"answer": "This discovery"
}, {
	"sub_cat_id": null,
	"category_id": null,
	"id": null,
	"topic_id": null,
	"question": "However, later ________ confirmed her discovery.",
	"answer": "research"
}, {
	"sub_cat_id": null,
	"category_id": null,
	"id": null,
	"topic_id": null,
	"question": "_______________________ is a division of the astronomical science that is concerned with recording data, in contrast with theoretical astrophysics, which is mainly concerned with finding out the measurable implications of physical models.",
	"answer": "Observational astronomy"
}, {
	"sub_cat_id": null,
	"category_id": null,
	"id": null,
	"topic_id": null,
	"question": "Observational astronomy is a division of ________________________ that is concerned with recording data, in contrast with theoretical astrophysics, which is mainly concerned with finding out the measurable implications of physical models.",
	"answer": "the astronomical science"
}, {
	"sub_cat_id": null,
	"category_id": null,
	"id": null,
	"topic_id": null,
	"question": "Observational astronomy is a division of the astronomical science that is concerned ___________________, in contrast with theoretical astrophysics, which is mainly concerned with finding out the measurable implications of physical models.",
	"answer": "with recording data"
}, {
	"sub_cat_id": null,
	"category_id": null,
	"id": null,
	"topic_id": null,
	"question": "Observational astronomy is a division of the astronomical science that is concerned with recording data, in contrast with ________________________, which is mainly concerned with finding out the measurable implications of physical models.",
	"answer": "theoretical astrophysics"
}, {
	"sub_cat_id": null,
	"category_id": null,
	"id": null,
	"topic_id": null,
	"question": "It is ____________ of observing celestial objects by using telescopes and other astronomical apparatus.",
	"answer": "the practice"
}, {
	"sub_cat_id": null,
	"category_id": null,
	"id": null,
	"topic_id": null,
	"question": "Example ______________ are radio waves, usually emitted by cold objects such as interstellar gas and dust clouds; the cosmic microwave background radiation which is the redshifted light from the Big Bang; pulsars, which were first detected at microwave frequencies.",
	"answer": "areas of study"
}, {
	"sub_cat_id": null,
	"category_id": null,
	"id": null,
	"topic_id": null,
	"question": "Example areas of study are radio waves, usually emitted _______________ such as interstellar gas and dust clouds; the cosmic microwave background radiation which is the redshifted light from the Big Bang; pulsars, which were first detected at microwave frequencies.",
	"answer": "by cold objects"
}, {
	"sub_cat_id": null,
	"category_id": null,
	"id": null,
	"topic_id": null,
	"question": "Example areas of study are radio waves, usually emitted by cold objects such as interstellar gas and dust clouds; the cosmic microwave background radiation which is the redshifted light from the Big Bang; _______, which were first detected at microwave frequencies.",
	"answer": "pulsars"
}, {
	"sub_cat_id": null,
	"category_id": null,
	"id": null,
	"topic_id": null,
	"question": "_____________________ are usually made with telescopes similar to the familiar optical telescopes.",
	"answer": "Infrared observations"
}, {
	"sub_cat_id": null,
	"category_id": null,
	"id": null,
	"topic_id": null,
	"question": "Ecology (from Greek: \u03bf\u1f36\u03ba\u03bf\u03c2, \"house\", or \"environment\"; ______________________ is the scientific analysis and study of interactions among organisms and their environment.",
	"answer": "-\u03bb\u03bf\u03b3\u03af\u03b1, \"study of\"[A])"
}, {
	"sub_cat_id": null,
	"category_id": null,
	"id": null,
	"topic_id": null,
	"question": "__________ are composed of dynamically interacting parts including organisms, the communities they make up, and the non-living components of their environment.",
	"answer": "Ecosystems"
}, {
	"sub_cat_id": null,
	"category_id": null,
	"id": null,
	"topic_id": null,
	"question": "Ecosystems are composed of dynamically interacting parts including _________, the communities they make up, and the non-living components of their environment.",
	"answer": "organisms"
}, {
	"sub_cat_id": null,
	"category_id": null,
	"id": null,
	"topic_id": null,
	"question": "_______________ are sustained by organisms with specific life history traits, and the variety of organisms is called biodiversity.",
	"answer": "These processes"
}, {
	"sub_cat_id": null,
	"category_id": null,
	"id": null,
	"topic_id": null,
	"question": "____________, which refers to the varieties of species, genes, and ecosystems, enhances certain ecosystem services.",
	"answer": "Biodiversity"
}, {
	"sub_cat_id": null,
	"category_id": null,
	"id": null,
	"topic_id": null,
	"question": "_______ is not synonymous with environment, environmentalism, natural history, or environmental science.",
	"answer": "Ecology"
}, {
	"sub_cat_id": null,
	"category_id": null,
	"id": null,
	"topic_id": null,
	"question": "_______ is a human science as well.",
	"answer": "Ecology"
}, {
	"sub_cat_id": null,
	"category_id": null,
	"id": null,
	"topic_id": null,
	"question": "Organisms (including ______) and resources compose ecosystems which, in turn, maintain biophysical feedback mechanisms that moderate processes acting on living (biotic) and non-living (abiotic) components of the planet.",
	"answer": "humans"
}, {
	"sub_cat_id": null,
	"category_id": null,
	"id": null,
	"topic_id": null,
	"question": "__________ sustain life-supporting functions and produce natural capital like biomass production (food, fuel, fiber, and medicine), the regulation of climate, global biogeochemical cycles, water filtration, soil formation, erosion control, flood protection, and many other natural features of scientific, historical, economic, or intrinsic value.",
	"answer": "Ecosystems"
}, {
	"sub_cat_id": null,
	"category_id": null,
	"id": null,
	"topic_id": null,
	"question": "__________________ is derivative of established currents in philosophy, particularly from ethics and politics.",
	"answer": "Ecological thought"
}, {
	"sub_cat_id": null,
	"category_id": null,
	"id": null,
	"topic_id": null,
	"question": "Ancient Greek philosophers such as Hippocrates and Aristotle laid the foundations of ecology in their studies on natural history.",
	"answer": "Ecological thought"
}, {
	"sub_cat_id": null,
	"category_id": null,
	"id": null,
	"topic_id": null,
	"question": "______________ became a much more rigorous science in the late 19th century.",
	"answer": "Modern ecology"
}, {
	"sub_cat_id": null,
	"category_id": null,
	"id": null,
	"topic_id": null,
	"question": "_____________________ relating to adaptation and natural selection became the cornerstones of modern ecological theory.",
	"answer": "Evolutionary concepts"
}, {
	"sub_cat_id": null,
	"category_id": null,
	"id": null,
	"topic_id": null,
	"question": "__________, for example, contain abiotic resources and interacting life forms (i.",
	"answer": "Ecosystems"
}, {
	"sub_cat_id": null,
	"category_id": null,
	"id": null,
	"topic_id": null,
	"question": "Ecosystems, for example, contain abiotic resources and interacting life forms (i.",
	"answer": "populations"
}, {
	"sub_cat_id": null,
	"category_id": null,
	"id": null,
	"topic_id": null,
	"question": "__________ are dynamic, they do not always follow a linear successional path, but they are always changing, sometimes rapidly and sometimes so slowly that it can take thousands of years for ecological processes to bring about certain successional stages of a forest.",
	"answer": "Ecosystems"
}, {
	"sub_cat_id": null,
	"category_id": null,
	"id": null,
	"topic_id": null,
	"question": "___________________ can vary greatly, from tiny to vast.",
	"answer": "An ecosystem's area"
}, {
	"sub_cat_id": null,
	"category_id": null,
	"id": null,
	"topic_id": null,
	"question": "_____________ is of little consequence to the classification of a forest ecosystem, but critically relevant to organisms living in and on it.",
	"answer": "A single tree"
}, {
	"sub_cat_id": null,
	"category_id": null,
	"id": null,
	"topic_id": null,
	"question": "Several generations of an aphid population can exist over the lifespan of a single leaf.",
	"answer": "A single tree"
}, {
	"sub_cat_id": null,
	"category_id": null,
	"id": null,
	"topic_id": null,
	"question": "________________ must first be arrayed into different levels of organization.",
	"answer": "System behaviors"
}, {
	"sub_cat_id": null,
	"category_id": null,
	"id": null,
	"topic_id": null,
	"question": "_________ corresponding to higher levels occur at slow rates.",
	"answer": "Behaviors"
}, {
	"sub_cat_id": null,
	"category_id": null,
	"id": null,
	"topic_id": null,
	"question": "For example, _______________ leaves respond rapidly to momentary changes in light intensity, CO2 concentration, and the like.",
	"answer": "individual tree"
}, {
	"sub_cat_id": null,
	"category_id": null,
	"id": null,
	"topic_id": null,
	"question": "For example, ______________________ respond rapidly to momentary changes in light intensity, CO2 concentration, and the like.",
	"answer": "individual tree leaves"
}, {
	"sub_cat_id": null,
	"category_id": null,
	"id": null,
	"topic_id": null,
	"question": "Astrophysics is the branch of astronomy that employs the principles of physics and chemistry \"to ascertain the nature of the heavenly bodies, rather than their positions or motions in space.",
	"answer": "the objects"
}, {
	"sub_cat_id": null,
	"category_id": null,
	"id": null,
	"topic_id": null,
	"question": "Among ___________ studied are the Sun, other stars, galaxies, extrasolar planets, the interstellar medium and the cosmic microwave background.",
	"answer": "the objects"
}, {
	"sub_cat_id": null,
	"category_id": null,
	"id": null,
	"topic_id": null,
	"question": "Their emissions are examined across all parts of the electromagnetic spectrum, and the properties examined include luminosity, density, temperature, and chemical composition.",
	"answer": "the objects"
}, {
	"sub_cat_id": null,
	"category_id": null,
	"id": null,
	"topic_id": null,
	"question": "Among the objects studied are the Sun, other stars, galaxies, extrasolar planets, the interstellar medium and the cosmic microwave background.",
	"answer": "Their emissions"
}, {
	"sub_cat_id": null,
	"category_id": null,
	"id": null,
	"topic_id": null,
	"question": "_______________ are examined across all parts of the electromagnetic spectrum, and the properties examined include luminosity, density, temperature, and chemical composition.",
	"answer": "Their emissions"
}, {
	"sub_cat_id": null,
	"category_id": null,
	"id": null,
	"topic_id": null,
	"question": "Because astrophysics is a very broad subject, _______________ typically apply many disciplines of physics, including mechanics, electromagnetism, statistical mechanics, thermodynamics, quantum mechanics, relativity, nuclear and particle physics, and atomic and molecular physics.",
	"answer": "astrophysicists"
}, {
	"sub_cat_id": null,
	"category_id": null,
	"id": null,
	"topic_id": null,
	"question": "Although _________ is as ancient as recorded history itself, it was long separated from the study of terrestrial physics.",
	"answer": "astronomy"
}, {
	"sub_cat_id": null,
	"category_id": null,
	"id": null,
	"topic_id": null,
	"question": "In the Aristotelian worldview, bodies in the sky appeared to be unchanging spheres whose only motion was uniform motion in a circle, while the earthly world was the realm which underwent growth and decay and in which ______________ was in a straight line and ended when the moving object reached its goal.",
	"answer": "natural motion"
}, {
	"sub_cat_id": null,
	"category_id": null,
	"id": null,
	"topic_id": null,
	"question": "In the Aristotelian worldview, bodies in the sky appeared to be unchanging spheres whose only motion was uniform motion in a circle, while the earthly world was _________ which underwent growth and decay and in which natural motion was in a straight line and ended when the moving object reached its goal.",
	"answer": "the realm"
}, {
	"sub_cat_id": null,
	"category_id": null,
	"id": null,
	"topic_id": null,
	"question": "In the Aristotelian worldview, bodies in the sky appeared to be unchanging spheres whose only motion was uniform motion in a circle, while the earthly world was the realm which underwent growth and decay and in which natural motion was in a straight line and ended when _________________ reached its goal.",
	"answer": "the moving object"
}, {
	"sub_cat_id": null,
	"category_id": null,
	"id": null,
	"topic_id": null,
	"question": "Among _____ who extended the study of solar and stellar spectra was Norman Lockyer, who in 1868 detected bright, as well as dark, lines in solar spectra.",
	"answer": "those"
}, {
	"sub_cat_id": null,
	"category_id": null,
	"id": null,
	"topic_id": null,
	"question": "Among those who extended the study of solar and stellar spectra was ______________, who in 1868 detected bright, as well as dark, lines in solar spectra.",
	"answer": "Norman Lockyer"
}, {
	"sub_cat_id": null,
	"category_id": null,
	"id": null,
	"topic_id": null,
	"question": "He thus claimed the line represented _____________, which was called helium, after the Greek Helios, the Sun personified.",
	"answer": "a new element"
}, {
	"sub_cat_id": null,
	"category_id": null,
	"id": null,
	"topic_id": null,
	"question": "In 1885, Edward C.",
	"answer": "Edward C. Pickering"
}, {
	"sub_cat_id": null,
	"category_id": null,
	"id": null,
	"topic_id": null,
	"question": "Pickering undertook an ambitious program of stellar spectral classification at Harvard College Observatory, in which a team of woman computers, notably Williamina Fleming, Antonia Maury, and Annie Jump Cannon, classified the spectra recorded on photographic plates.",
	"answer": "Edward C. Pickering"
}, {
	"sub_cat_id": null,
	"category_id": null,
	"id": null,
	"topic_id": null,
	"question": "Pickering undertook an ambitious program of stellar spectral classification at Harvard College Observatory, in which a team of woman computers, notably Williamina Fleming, Antonia Maury, and Annie Jump Cannon, classified ___________ recorded on photographic plates.",
	"answer": "the spectra"
}, {
	"sub_cat_id": null,
	"category_id": null,
	"id": null,
	"topic_id": null,
	"question": "In 1925 Cecilia Helena Payne (later Cecilia Payne-Gaposchkin) wrote an influential doctoral dissertation at Radcliffe College, in which she applied ionization theory to stellar atmospheres to relate ____________________ to the temperature of stars.",
	"answer": "the spectral classes"
}, {
	"sub_cat_id": null,
	"category_id": null,
	"id": null,
	"topic_id": null,
	"question": "Most significantly, she discovered that hydrogen and helium were the principal components of stars.",
	"answer": "the spectral classes"
}, {
	"sub_cat_id": null,
	"category_id": null,
	"id": null,
	"topic_id": null,
	"question": "______________ was so unexpected that her dissertation readers convinced her to modify the conclusion before publication.",
	"answer": "This discovery"
}, {
	"sub_cat_id": null,
	"category_id": null,
	"id": null,
	"topic_id": null,
	"question": "However, later ________ confirmed her discovery.",
	"answer": "research"
}, {
	"sub_cat_id": null,
	"category_id": null,
	"id": null,
	"topic_id": null,
	"question": "_______________________ is a division of the astronomical science that is concerned with recording data, in contrast with theoretical astrophysics, which is mainly concerned with finding out the measurable implications of physical models.",
	"answer": "Observational astronomy"
}, {
	"sub_cat_id": null,
	"category_id": null,
	"id": null,
	"topic_id": null,
	"question": "Observational astronomy is a division of ________________________ that is concerned with recording data, in contrast with theoretical astrophysics, which is mainly concerned with finding out the measurable implications of physical models.",
	"answer": "the astronomical science"
}, {
	"sub_cat_id": null,
	"category_id": null,
	"id": null,
	"topic_id": null,
	"question": "Observational astronomy is a division of the astronomical science that is concerned ___________________, in contrast with theoretical astrophysics, which is mainly concerned with finding out the measurable implications of physical models.",
	"answer": "with recording data"
}, {
	"sub_cat_id": null,
	"category_id": null,
	"id": null,
	"topic_id": null,
	"question": "Observational astronomy is a division of the astronomical science that is concerned with recording data, in contrast with ________________________, which is mainly concerned with finding out the measurable implications of physical models.",
	"answer": "theoretical astrophysics"
}, {
	"sub_cat_id": null,
	"category_id": null,
	"id": null,
	"topic_id": null,
	"question": "It is ____________ of observing celestial objects by using telescopes and other astronomical apparatus.",
	"answer": "the practice"
}, {
	"sub_cat_id": null,
	"category_id": null,
	"id": null,
	"topic_id": null,
	"question": "Example ______________ are radio waves, usually emitted by cold objects such as interstellar gas and dust clouds; the cosmic microwave background radiation which is the redshifted light from the Big Bang; pulsars, which were first detected at microwave frequencies.",
	"answer": "areas of study"
}, {
	"sub_cat_id": null,
	"category_id": null,
	"id": null,
	"topic_id": null,
	"question": "Example areas of study are radio waves, usually emitted _______________ such as interstellar gas and dust clouds; the cosmic microwave background radiation which is the redshifted light from the Big Bang; pulsars, which were first detected at microwave frequencies.",
	"answer": "by cold objects"
}, {
	"sub_cat_id": null,
	"category_id": null,
	"id": null,
	"topic_id": null,
	"question": "Example areas of study are radio waves, usually emitted by cold objects such as interstellar gas and dust clouds; the cosmic microwave background radiation which is the redshifted light from the Big Bang; _______, which were first detected at microwave frequencies.",
	"answer": "pulsars"
}, {
	"sub_cat_id": null,
	"category_id": null,
	"id": null,
	"topic_id": null,
	"question": "_____________________ are usually made with telescopes similar to the familiar optical telescopes.",
	"answer": "Infrared observations"
}, {
	"sub_cat_id": null,
	"category_id": null,
	"id": null,
	"topic_id": null,
	"question": "Ecology (from Greek: \u03bf\u1f36\u03ba\u03bf\u03c2, \"house\", or \"environment\"; ______________________ is the scientific analysis and study of interactions among organisms and their environment.",
	"answer": "-\u03bb\u03bf\u03b3\u03af\u03b1, \"study of\"[A])"
}, {
	"sub_cat_id": null,
	"category_id": null,
	"id": null,
	"topic_id": null,
	"question": "__________ are composed of dynamically interacting parts including organisms, the communities they make up, and the non-living components of their environment.",
	"answer": "Ecosystems"
}, {
	"sub_cat_id": null,
	"category_id": null,
	"id": null,
	"topic_id": null,
	"question": "Ecosystems are composed of dynamically interacting parts including _________, the communities they make up, and the non-living components of their environment.",
	"answer": "organisms"
}, {
	"sub_cat_id": null,
	"category_id": null,
	"id": null,
	"topic_id": null,
	"question": "_______________ are sustained by organisms with specific life history traits, and the variety of organisms is called biodiversity.",
	"answer": "These processes"
}, {
	"sub_cat_id": null,
	"category_id": null,
	"id": null,
	"topic_id": null,
	"question": "____________, which refers to the varieties of species, genes, and ecosystems, enhances certain ecosystem services.",
	"answer": "Biodiversity"
}, {
	"sub_cat_id": null,
	"category_id": null,
	"id": null,
	"topic_id": null,
	"question": "_______ is not synonymous with environment, environmentalism, natural history, or environmental science.",
	"answer": "Ecology"
}, {
	"sub_cat_id": null,
	"category_id": null,
	"id": null,
	"topic_id": null,
	"question": "_______ is a human science as well.",
	"answer": "Ecology"
}, {
	"sub_cat_id": null,
	"category_id": null,
	"id": null,
	"topic_id": null,
	"question": "Organisms (including ______) and resources compose ecosystems which, in turn, maintain biophysical feedback mechanisms that moderate processes acting on living (biotic) and non-living (abiotic) components of the planet.",
	"answer": "humans"
}, {
	"sub_cat_id": null,
	"category_id": null,
	"id": null,
	"topic_id": null,
	"question": "__________ sustain life-supporting functions and produce natural capital like biomass production (food, fuel, fiber, and medicine), the regulation of climate, global biogeochemical cycles, water filtration, soil formation, erosion control, flood protection, and many other natural features of scientific, historical, economic, or intrinsic value.",
	"answer": "Ecosystems"
}, {
	"sub_cat_id": null,
	"category_id": null,
	"id": null,
	"topic_id": null,
	"question": "__________________ is derivative of established currents in philosophy, particularly from ethics and politics.",
	"answer": "Ecological thought"
}, {
	"sub_cat_id": null,
	"category_id": null,
	"id": null,
	"topic_id": null,
	"question": "Ancient Greek philosophers such as Hippocrates and Aristotle laid the foundations of ecology in their studies on natural history.",
	"answer": "Ecological thought"
}, {
	"sub_cat_id": null,
	"category_id": null,
	"id": null,
	"topic_id": null,
	"question": "______________ became a much more rigorous science in the late 19th century.",
	"answer": "Modern ecology"
}, {
	"sub_cat_id": null,
	"category_id": null,
	"id": null,
	"topic_id": null,
	"question": "_____________________ relating to adaptation and natural selection became the cornerstones of modern ecological theory.",
	"answer": "Evolutionary concepts"
}, {
	"sub_cat_id": null,
	"category_id": null,
	"id": null,
	"topic_id": null,
	"question": "__________, for example, contain abiotic resources and interacting life forms (i.",
	"answer": "Ecosystems"
}, {
	"sub_cat_id": null,
	"category_id": null,
	"id": null,
	"topic_id": null,
	"question": "Ecosystems, for example, contain abiotic resources and interacting life forms (i.",
	"answer": "populations"
}, {
	"sub_cat_id": null,
	"category_id": null,
	"id": null,
	"topic_id": null,
	"question": "__________ are dynamic, they do not always follow a linear successional path, but they are always changing, sometimes rapidly and sometimes so slowly that it can take thousands of years for ecological processes to bring about certain successional stages of a forest.",
	"answer": "Ecosystems"
}, {
	"sub_cat_id": null,
	"category_id": null,
	"id": null,
	"topic_id": null,
	"question": "___________________ can vary greatly, from tiny to vast.",
	"answer": "An ecosystem's area"
}, {
	"sub_cat_id": null,
	"category_id": null,
	"id": null,
	"topic_id": null,
	"question": "_____________ is of little consequence to the classification of a forest ecosystem, but critically relevant to organisms living in and on it.",
	"answer": "A single tree"
}, {
	"sub_cat_id": null,
	"category_id": null,
	"id": null,
	"topic_id": null,
	"question": "Several generations of an aphid population can exist over the lifespan of a single leaf.",
	"answer": "A single tree"
}, {
	"sub_cat_id": null,
	"category_id": null,
	"id": null,
	"topic_id": null,
	"question": "________________ must first be arrayed into different levels of organization.",
	"answer": "System behaviors"
}, {
	"sub_cat_id": null,
	"category_id": null,
	"id": null,
	"topic_id": null,
	"question": "_________ corresponding to higher levels occur at slow rates.",
	"answer": "Behaviors"
}, {
	"sub_cat_id": null,
	"category_id": null,
	"id": null,
	"topic_id": null,
	"question": "For example, _______________ leaves respond rapidly to momentary changes in light intensity, CO2 concentration, and the like.",
	"answer": "individual tree"
}, {
	"sub_cat_id": null,
	"category_id": null,
	"id": null,
	"topic_id": null,
	"question": "For example, ______________________ respond rapidly to momentary changes in light intensity, CO2 concentration, and the like.",
	"answer": "individual tree leaves"
}, {
	"sub_cat_id": null,
	"category_id": null,
	"id": null,
	"topic_id": null,
	"question": "_________ is the scientific study of the movement, distribution, and quality of water on Earth and other planets, including the hydrologic cycle, water resources and environmental watershed sustainability.",
	"answer": "Hydrology"
}, {
	"sub_cat_id": null,
	"category_id": null,
	"id": null,
	"topic_id": null,
	"question": "_________ subdivides into surface water hydrology, groundwater hydrology (hydrogeology), and marine hydrology.",
	"answer": "Hydrology"
}, {
	"sub_cat_id": null,
	"category_id": null,
	"id": null,
	"topic_id": null,
	"question": "Domains of hydrology include hydrometeorology, surface hydrology, hydrogeology, drainage-basin management and _____ quality, where _____ plays the central role.",
	"answer": "water"
}, {
	"sub_cat_id": null,
	"category_id": null,
	"id": null,
	"topic_id": null,
	"question": "_________ has been a subject of investigation and engineering for millennia.",
	"answer": "Hydrology"
}, {
	"sub_cat_id": null,
	"category_id": null,
	"id": null,
	"topic_id": null,
	"question": "__________________ were protected from flooding with high earthen walls.",
	"answer": "Mesopotamian towns"
}, {
	"sub_cat_id": null,
	"category_id": null,
	"id": null,
	"topic_id": null,
	"question": "_________ were built by the Greeks and Ancient Romans, while the history of China shows they built irrigation and flood control works.",
	"answer": "Aqueducts"
}, {
	"sub_cat_id": null,
	"category_id": null,
	"id": null,
	"topic_id": null,
	"question": "_____________________ used hydrology to build complex irrigation works in Sri Lanka, also known for invention of the Valve Pit which allowed construction of large reservoirs, anicuts and canals which still function.",
	"answer": "The ancient Sinhalese"
}, {
	"sub_cat_id": null,
	"category_id": null,
	"id": null,
	"topic_id": null,
	"question": "The ancient Sinhalese used hydrology to build complex irrigation works in Sri Lanka, also known for invention of _____________ which allowed construction of large reservoirs, anicuts and canals which still function.",
	"answer": "the Valve Pit"
}, {
	"sub_cat_id": null,
	"category_id": null,
	"id": null,
	"topic_id": null,
	"question": "The ancient Sinhalese used hydrology to build complex irrigation works in Sri Lanka, also known for invention of the Valve Pit which allowed construction of large reservoirs, __________________ which still function.",
	"answer": "anicuts and canals"
}, {
	"sub_cat_id": null,
	"category_id": null,
	"id": null,
	"topic_id": null,
	"question": "It was not until the 17th century that ____________________ began to be quantified.",
	"answer": "hydrologic variables"
}, {
	"sub_cat_id": null,
	"category_id": null,
	"id": null,
	"topic_id": null,
	"question": "By measuring rainfall, runoff, and drainage area, ________ showed that rainfall was sufficient to account for flow of the Seine.",
	"answer": "Perrault"
}, {
	"sub_cat_id": null,
	"category_id": null,
	"id": null,
	"topic_id": null,
	"question": "By measuring ________, runoff, and drainage area, Perrault showed that ________ was sufficient to account for flow of the Seine.",
	"answer": "rainfall"
}, {
	"sub_cat_id": null,
	"category_id": null,
	"id": null,
	"topic_id": null,
	"question": "______ showed that the evaporation from the Mediterranean Sea was sufficient to account for the outflow of rivers flowing into the sea.",
	"answer": "Halley"
}, {
	"sub_cat_id": null,
	"category_id": null,
	"id": null,
	"topic_id": null,
	"question": "________________ saw development in groundwater hydrology, including Darcy's law, the Dupuit-Thiem well formula, and Hagen-Poiseuille's capillary flow equation.",
	"answer": "The 19th century"
}, {
	"sub_cat_id": null,
	"category_id": null,
	"id": null,
	"topic_id": null,
	"question": "_________________ began to replace empiricism in the 20th century, while governmental agencies began their own hydrological research programs.",
	"answer": "Rational analyses"
}, {
	"sub_cat_id": null,
	"category_id": null,
	"id": null,
	"topic_id": null,
	"question": "Rational analyses began to replace empiricism in the 20th century, while _____________________ began their own hydrological research programs.",
	"answer": "governmental agencies"
}, {
	"sub_cat_id": null,
	"category_id": null,
	"id": null,
	"topic_id": null,
	"question": "________________________ were Leroy Sherman's unit hydrograph, the infiltration theory of Robert E.",
	"answer": "Of particular importance"
}, {
	"sub_cat_id": null,
	"category_id": null,
	"id": null,
	"topic_id": null,
	"question": "Horton, and C.",
	"answer": "Of particular importance"
}, {
	"sub_cat_id": null,
	"category_id": null,
	"id": null,
	"topic_id": null,
	"question": "V.",
	"answer": "Of particular importance"
}, {
	"sub_cat_id": null,
	"category_id": null,
	"id": null,
	"topic_id": null,
	"question": "Theis's aquifer test/equation describing well hydraulics.",
	"answer": "Of particular importance"
}, {
	"sub_cat_id": null,
	"category_id": null,
	"id": null,
	"topic_id": null,
	"question": "Since the 1950s, _________ has been approached with a more theoretical basis than in the past, facilitated by advances in the physical understanding of hydrological processes and by the advent of computers and especially geographic information systems (GIS).",
	"answer": "hydrology"
}, {
	"sub_cat_id": null,
	"category_id": null,
	"id": null,
	"topic_id": null,
	"question": "__________________ is the study of the chemical characteristics of water.",
	"answer": "Chemical hydrology"
}, {
	"sub_cat_id": null,
	"category_id": null,
	"id": null,
	"topic_id": null,
	"question": "____________ is the study of interactions between organisms and the hydrologic cycle.",
	"answer": "Ecohydrology"
}, {
	"sub_cat_id": null,
	"category_id": null,
	"id": null,
	"topic_id": null,
	"question": "____________ is the study of the presence and movement of groundwater.",
	"answer": "Hydrogeology"
}, {
	"sub_cat_id": null,
	"category_id": null,
	"id": null,
	"topic_id": null,
	"question": "_________________ is the study of the isotopic signatures of water.",
	"answer": "Isotope hydrology"
}, {
	"sub_cat_id": null,
	"category_id": null,
	"id": null,
	"topic_id": null,
	"question": "_________________ is the study of hydrologic processes that operate at or near Earth's surface.",
	"answer": "Surface hydrology"
}, {
	"sub_cat_id": null,
	"category_id": null,
	"id": null,
	"topic_id": null,
	"question": "____________ is the more general study of water in the oceans and estuaries.",
	"answer": "Oceanography"
}, {
	"sub_cat_id": null,
	"category_id": null,
	"id": null,
	"topic_id": null,
	"question": "_________ is the study of lakes.",
	"answer": "Limnology"
}, {
	"sub_cat_id": null,
	"category_id": null,
	"id": null,
	"topic_id": null,
	"question": "_______________ are sources of water that are useful or potentially useful.",
	"answer": "Water resources"
}, {
	"sub_cat_id": null,
	"category_id": null,
	"id": null,
	"topic_id": null,
	"question": "Water resources are sources of _____ that are useful or potentially useful.",
	"answer": "water"
}, {
	"sub_cat_id": null,
	"category_id": null,
	"id": null,
	"topic_id": null,
	"question": "_________ studies the availability of those resources, but usually not their uses.",
	"answer": "Hydrology"
}, {
	"question": "Zoology (/z o\u028a \u02c8 \u0252 l \u0259 d\u0292 i/, zoh-OL-luh-jee) or animal _______ is the branch of _______ that relates to the animal kingdom, including the structure, embryology, evolution, classification, habits, and distribution of all animals, both living and extinct, and how they interact with their ecosystems.",
	"topic_id": null,
	"id": null,
	"category_id": null,
	"answer": "biology",
	"sub_cat_id": null
}, {
	"question": "________ is derived from Ancient Greek \u03b6\u1ff7\u03bf\u03bd, z\u014dion, i.",
	"topic_id": null,
	"id": null,
	"category_id": null,
	"answer": "The term",
	"sub_cat_id": null
}, {
	"question": "Although the concept of zoology as a single coherent field arose much later, _______________________ emerged from natural history reaching back to the works of Aristotle and Galen in the ancient Greco-Roman world.",
	"topic_id": null,
	"id": null,
	"category_id": null,
	"answer": "the zoological sciences",
	"sub_cat_id": null
}, {
	"question": "_________________ was further developed in the Middle Ages by Muslim physicians and scholars such as Albertus Magnus.",
	"topic_id": null,
	"id": null,
	"category_id": null,
	"answer": "This ancient work",
	"sub_cat_id": null
}, {
	"question": "During the Renaissance and early modern period, zoological thought was revolutionized in Europe by a renewed interest in empiricism and the discovery of many novel organisms.",
	"topic_id": null,
	"id": null,
	"category_id": null,
	"answer": "This ancient work",
	"sub_cat_id": null
}, {
	"question": "This ancient work was further developed in the Middle Ages by Muslim physicians and scholars such as Albertus Magnus.",
	"topic_id": null,
	"id": null,
	"category_id": null,
	"answer": "zoological thought",
	"sub_cat_id": null
}, {
	"question": "During the Renaissance and early modern period, __________________ was revolutionized in Europe by a renewed interest in empiricism and the discovery of many novel organisms.",
	"topic_id": null,
	"id": null,
	"category_id": null,
	"answer": "zoological thought",
	"sub_cat_id": null
}, {
	"question": "__________ revealed the previously unknown world of microorganisms, laying the groundwork for cell theory.",
	"topic_id": null,
	"id": null,
	"category_id": null,
	"answer": "Microscopy",
	"sub_cat_id": null
}, {
	"question": "The growing importance of natural theology, partly a response to the rise of mechanical philosophy, encouraged the growth of natural history (although it entrenched the argument from design).",
	"topic_id": null,
	"id": null,
	"category_id": null,
	"answer": "Microscopy",
	"sub_cat_id": null
}, {
	"question": "Over the 18th and 19th centuries, _______ became an increasingly professional scientific discipline.",
	"topic_id": null,
	"id": null,
	"category_id": null,
	"answer": "zoology",
	"sub_cat_id": null
}, {
	"question": "___________ began to reject essentialism and consider the importance of extinction and the mutability of species.",
	"topic_id": null,
	"id": null,
	"category_id": null,
	"answer": "Naturalists",
	"sub_cat_id": null
}, {
	"question": "___________ provided a new perspective on the fundamental basis of life.",
	"topic_id": null,
	"id": null,
	"category_id": null,
	"answer": "Cell theory",
	"sub_cat_id": null
}, {
	"question": "______ gave new direction to morphology and physiology, by uniting them in a common biological theory: the theory of organic evolution.",
	"topic_id": null,
	"id": null,
	"category_id": null,
	"answer": "Darwin",
	"sub_cat_id": null
}, {
	"question": "__________ was a reconstruction of the classification of animals upon a genealogical basis, fresh investigation of the development of animals, and early attempts to determine their genetic relationships.",
	"topic_id": null,
	"id": null,
	"category_id": null,
	"answer": "The result",
	"sub_cat_id": null
}, {
	"question": "Anatomy and cell biology are ___________ that are closely related, and can be categorized under \"structural\" studies.",
	"topic_id": null,
	"id": null,
	"category_id": null,
	"answer": "two studies",
	"sub_cat_id": null
}, {
	"question": "_____________________ have traditionally been divided into plant physiology and animal physiology, but some principles of physiology are universal, no matter what particular organism is being studied.",
	"topic_id": null,
	"id": null,
	"category_id": null,
	"answer": "Physiological studies",
	"sub_cat_id": null
}, {
	"question": "_____________________ is concerned with the origin and descent of species, as well as their change over time, and includes scientists from many taxonomically oriented disciplines.",
	"topic_id": null,
	"id": null,
	"category_id": null,
	"answer": "Evolutionary research",
	"sub_cat_id": null
}, {
	"question": "For example, it generally involves __________ who have special training in particular organisms such as mammalogy, ornithology, herpetology, or entomology, but use those organisms as systems to answer general questions about evolution.",
	"topic_id": null,
	"id": null,
	"category_id": null,
	"answer": "scientists",
	"sub_cat_id": null
}, {
	"question": "____________________ is partly based on paleontology, which uses the fossil record to answer questions about the mode and tempo of evolution,[11] and partly on the developments in areas such as population genetics [12] and evolutionary theory.",
	"topic_id": null,
	"id": null,
	"category_id": null,
	"answer": "Evolutionary biology",
	"sub_cat_id": null
}, {
	"question": "Evolutionary biology is partly based on ____________, which uses the fossil record to answer questions about the mode and tempo of evolution,[11] and partly on the developments in areas such as population genetics [12] and evolutionary theory.",
	"topic_id": null,
	"id": null,
	"category_id": null,
	"answer": "paleontology",
	"sub_cat_id": null
}, {
	"question": "In the 1980s, _____________________ re-entered evolutionary biology from its initial exclusion from the modern synthesis through the study of evolutionary _____________________.",
	"topic_id": null,
	"id": null,
	"category_id": null,
	"answer": "developmental biology",
	"sub_cat_id": null
}, {
	"question": "Related fields often considered part of evolutionary biology are phylogenetics, systematics, and taxonomy.",
	"topic_id": null,
	"id": null,
	"category_id": null,
	"answer": "developmental biology",
	"sub_cat_id": null
}, {
	"question": "Zoology (/z o\u028a \u02c8 \u0252 l \u0259 d\u0292 i/, zoh-OL-luh-jee) or animal _______ is the branch of _______ that relates to the animal kingdom, including the structure, embryology, evolution, classification, habits, and distribution of all animals, both living and extinct, and how they interact with their ecosystems.",
	"topic_id": null,
	"id": null,
	"category_id": null,
	"answer": "biology",
	"sub_cat_id": null
}, {
	"question": "________ is derived from Ancient Greek \u03b6\u1ff7\u03bf\u03bd, z\u014dion, i.",
	"topic_id": null,
	"id": null,
	"category_id": null,
	"answer": "The term",
	"sub_cat_id": null
}, {
	"question": "Although the concept of zoology as a single coherent field arose much later, _______________________ emerged from natural history reaching back to the works of Aristotle and Galen in the ancient Greco-Roman world.",
	"topic_id": null,
	"id": null,
	"category_id": null,
	"answer": "the zoological sciences",
	"sub_cat_id": null
}, {
	"question": "_________________ was further developed in the Middle Ages by Muslim physicians and scholars such as Albertus Magnus.",
	"topic_id": null,
	"id": null,
	"category_id": null,
	"answer": "This ancient work",
	"sub_cat_id": null
}, {
	"question": "During the Renaissance and early modern period, zoological thought was revolutionized in Europe by a renewed interest in empiricism and the discovery of many novel organisms.",
	"topic_id": null,
	"id": null,
	"category_id": null,
	"answer": "This ancient work",
	"sub_cat_id": null
}, {
	"question": "This ancient work was further developed in the Middle Ages by Muslim physicians and scholars such as Albertus Magnus.",
	"topic_id": null,
	"id": null,
	"category_id": null,
	"answer": "zoological thought",
	"sub_cat_id": null
}, {
	"question": "During the Renaissance and early modern period, __________________ was revolutionized in Europe by a renewed interest in empiricism and the discovery of many novel organisms.",
	"topic_id": null,
	"id": null,
	"category_id": null,
	"answer": "zoological thought",
	"sub_cat_id": null
}, {
	"question": "__________ revealed the previously unknown world of microorganisms, laying the groundwork for cell theory.",
	"topic_id": null,
	"id": null,
	"category_id": null,
	"answer": "Microscopy",
	"sub_cat_id": null
}, {
	"question": "The growing importance of natural theology, partly a response to the rise of mechanical philosophy, encouraged the growth of natural history (although it entrenched the argument from design).",
	"topic_id": null,
	"id": null,
	"category_id": null,
	"answer": "Microscopy",
	"sub_cat_id": null
}, {
	"question": "Over the 18th and 19th centuries, _______ became an increasingly professional scientific discipline.",
	"topic_id": null,
	"id": null,
	"category_id": null,
	"answer": "zoology",
	"sub_cat_id": null
}, {
	"question": "___________ began to reject essentialism and consider the importance of extinction and the mutability of species.",
	"topic_id": null,
	"id": null,
	"category_id": null,
	"answer": "Naturalists",
	"sub_cat_id": null
}, {
	"question": "___________ provided a new perspective on the fundamental basis of life.",
	"topic_id": null,
	"id": null,
	"category_id": null,
	"answer": "Cell theory",
	"sub_cat_id": null
}, {
	"question": "______ gave new direction to morphology and physiology, by uniting them in a common biological theory: the theory of organic evolution.",
	"topic_id": null,
	"id": null,
	"category_id": null,
	"answer": "Darwin",
	"sub_cat_id": null
}, {
	"question": "__________ was a reconstruction of the classification of animals upon a genealogical basis, fresh investigation of the development of animals, and early attempts to determine their genetic relationships.",
	"topic_id": null,
	"id": null,
	"category_id": null,
	"answer": "The result",
	"sub_cat_id": null
}, {
	"question": "Anatomy and cell biology are ___________ that are closely related, and can be categorized under \"structural\" studies.",
	"topic_id": null,
	"id": null,
	"category_id": null,
	"answer": "two studies",
	"sub_cat_id": null
}, {
	"question": "_____________________ have traditionally been divided into plant physiology and animal physiology, but some principles of physiology are universal, no matter what particular organism is being studied.",
	"topic_id": null,
	"id": null,
	"category_id": null,
	"answer": "Physiological studies",
	"sub_cat_id": null
}, {
	"question": "_____________________ is concerned with the origin and descent of species, as well as their change over time, and includes scientists from many taxonomically oriented disciplines.",
	"topic_id": null,
	"id": null,
	"category_id": null,
	"answer": "Evolutionary research",
	"sub_cat_id": null
}, {
	"question": "For example, it generally involves __________ who have special training in particular organisms such as mammalogy, ornithology, herpetology, or entomology, but use those organisms as systems to answer general questions about evolution.",
	"topic_id": null,
	"id": null,
	"category_id": null,
	"answer": "scientists",
	"sub_cat_id": null
}, {
	"question": "____________________ is partly based on paleontology, which uses the fossil record to answer questions about the mode and tempo of evolution,[11] and partly on the developments in areas such as population genetics [12] and evolutionary theory.",
	"topic_id": null,
	"id": null,
	"category_id": null,
	"answer": "Evolutionary biology",
	"sub_cat_id": null
}, {
	"question": "Evolutionary biology is partly based on ____________, which uses the fossil record to answer questions about the mode and tempo of evolution,[11] and partly on the developments in areas such as population genetics [12] and evolutionary theory.",
	"topic_id": null,
	"id": null,
	"category_id": null,
	"answer": "paleontology",
	"sub_cat_id": null
}, {
	"question": "In the 1980s, _____________________ re-entered evolutionary biology from its initial exclusion from the modern synthesis through the study of evolutionary _____________________.",
	"topic_id": null,
	"id": null,
	"category_id": null,
	"answer": "developmental biology",
	"sub_cat_id": null
}, {
	"question": "Related fields often considered part of evolutionary biology are phylogenetics, systematics, and taxonomy.",
	"topic_id": null,
	"id": null,
	"category_id": null,
	"answer": "developmental biology",
	"sub_cat_id": null
}, {
	"question": "__________________________ possess membrane-bound cell organelles and include fungi and protists, whereas prokaryotic organisms\u2014all of which are microorganisms\u2014are conventionally classified as lacking membrane-bound organelles and include eubacteria and archaebacteria.",
	"topic_id": null,
	"id": null,
	"category_id": null,
	"answer": "Eukaryotic micro-organisms",
	"sub_cat_id": null
}, {
	"question": "Eukaryotic micro-organisms possess membrane-bound cell organelles and include __________________, whereas prokaryotic organisms\u2014all of which are microorganisms\u2014are conventionally classified as lacking membrane-bound organelles and include eubacteria and archaebacteria.",
	"topic_id": null,
	"id": null,
	"category_id": null,
	"answer": "fungi and protists",
	"sub_cat_id": null
}, {
	"question": "Eukaryotic micro-organisms possess membrane-bound cell organelles and include fungi and protists, whereas prokaryotic organisms\u2014all of which are __________________ conventionally classified as lacking membrane-bound organelles and include eubacteria and archaebacteria.",
	"topic_id": null,
	"id": null,
	"category_id": null,
	"answer": "microorganisms\u2014are",
	"sub_cat_id": null
}, {
	"question": "_______________ traditionally relied on culture, staining, and microscopy.",
	"topic_id": null,
	"id": null,
	"category_id": null,
	"answer": "Microbiologists",
	"sub_cat_id": null
}, {
	"question": "However, less than 1% of __________________ present in common environments can be cultured in isolation using current means.",
	"topic_id": null,
	"id": null,
	"category_id": null,
	"answer": "the microorganisms",
	"sub_cat_id": null
}, {
	"question": "Microbiologists often rely on extraction or detection of nucleic acid, either DNA or RNA sequences.",
	"topic_id": null,
	"id": null,
	"category_id": null,
	"answer": "the microorganisms",
	"sub_cat_id": null
}, {
	"question": "However, less than 1% of the microorganisms present in common environments can be cultured in isolation using current means.",
	"topic_id": null,
	"id": null,
	"category_id": null,
	"answer": "Microbiologists",
	"sub_cat_id": null
}, {
	"question": "_______________ often rely on extraction or detection of nucleic acid, either DNA or RNA sequences.",
	"topic_id": null,
	"id": null,
	"category_id": null,
	"answer": "Microbiologists",
	"sub_cat_id": null
}, {
	"question": "_______ have been variably classified as organisms,[3] as they have been considered either as very simple microorganisms or very complex molecules.",
	"topic_id": null,
	"id": null,
	"category_id": null,
	"answer": "Viruses",
	"sub_cat_id": null
}, {
	"question": "Prions, never considered microorganisms, have been investigated ______________, however, as the clinical effects traced to them were originally presumed due to chronic viral infections, and virologists took search\u2014discovering \"infectious proteins\".",
	"topic_id": null,
	"id": null,
	"category_id": null,
	"answer": "by virologists",
	"sub_cat_id": null
}, {
	"question": "Prions, never considered microorganisms, have been investigated by virologists, however, as ____________________ traced to them were originally presumed due to chronic viral infections, and virologists took search\u2014discovering \"infectious proteins\".",
	"topic_id": null,
	"id": null,
	"category_id": null,
	"answer": "the clinical effects",
	"sub_cat_id": null
}, {
	"question": "Prions, never considered microorganisms, have been investigated by ___________, however, as the clinical effects traced to them were originally presumed due to chronic viral infections, and ___________ took search\u2014discovering \"infectious proteins\".",
	"topic_id": null,
	"id": null,
	"category_id": null,
	"answer": "virologists",
	"sub_cat_id": null
}, {
	"question": "As an application of microbiology, ____________________ is often introduced with medical principles of immunology as microbiology and immunology.",
	"topic_id": null,
	"id": null,
	"category_id": null,
	"answer": "medical microbiology",
	"sub_cat_id": null
}, {
	"question": "The branches of microbiology can be classified into pure and applied sciences.",
	"topic_id": null,
	"id": null,
	"category_id": null,
	"answer": "Microbiology",
	"sub_cat_id": null
}, {
	"question": "____________ can be also classified based on taxonomy, in the cases of bacteriology, mycology, protozoology, and phycology.",
	"topic_id": null,
	"id": null,
	"category_id": null,
	"answer": "Microbiology",
	"sub_cat_id": null
}, {
	"question": "There is ____________________ between the specific branches of microbiology with each other and with other disciplines, and certain aspects of these branches can extend beyond the traditional scope of microbiology.",
	"topic_id": null,
	"id": null,
	"category_id": null,
	"answer": "considerable overlap",
	"sub_cat_id": null
}, {
	"question": "__________ have also exploited their knowledge of microbes to produce biotechnologically important enzymes such as Taq polymerase, reporter genes for use in other genetic systems and novel molecular biology techniques such as the yeast two-hybrid system.",
	"topic_id": null,
	"id": null,
	"category_id": null,
	"answer": "Scientists",
	"sub_cat_id": null
}, {
	"question": "Scientists have also exploited their knowledge of ________ to produce biotechnologically important enzymes such as Taq polymerase, reporter genes for use in other genetic systems and novel molecular biology techniques such as the yeast two-hybrid system.",
	"topic_id": null,
	"id": null,
	"category_id": null,
	"answer": "microbes",
	"sub_cat_id": null
}, {
	"question": "________ can be used for the industrial production of amino acids.",
	"topic_id": null,
	"id": null,
	"category_id": null,
	"answer": "Bacteria",
	"sub_cat_id": null
}, {
	"question": "__________________________ is one of the most important bacterial species with an annual production of more than two million tons of amino acids, mainly L-glutamate and L-lysine.",
	"topic_id": null,
	"id": null,
	"category_id": null,
	"answer": "Corynebacterium glutamicum",
	"sub_cat_id": null
}, {
	"question": "Since some bacteria have the ability to synthesize antibiotics, they are used for medicinal purposes, such as Streptomyces to make aminoglycoside antibiotics.",
	"topic_id": null,
	"id": null,
	"category_id": null,
	"answer": "Corynebacterium glutamicum",
	"sub_cat_id": null
}, {
	"question": "Corynebacterium glutamicum is one of the most important bacterial species with an annual production of more than two million tons of amino acids, mainly L-glutamate and L-lysine.",
	"topic_id": null,
	"id": null,
	"category_id": null,
	"answer": "some bacteria",
	"sub_cat_id": null
}, {
	"question": "Since _____________ have the ability to synthesize antibiotics, they are used for medicinal purposes, such as Streptomyces to make aminoglycoside antibiotics.",
	"topic_id": null,
	"id": null,
	"category_id": null,
	"answer": "some bacteria",
	"sub_cat_id": null
}, {
	"question": "A variety of biopolymers, such as polysaccharides, polyesters, and polyamides, are produced _________________.",
	"topic_id": null,
	"id": null,
	"category_id": null,
	"answer": "by microorganisms",
	"sub_cat_id": null
}, {
	"question": "______________ are beneficial for microbial biodegradation or bioremediation of domestic, agricultural and industrial wastes and subsurface pollution in soils, sediments and marine environments.",
	"topic_id": null,
	"id": null,
	"category_id": null,
	"answer": "Microorganisms",
	"sub_cat_id": null
}, {
	"question": "Since _____ typically have multiple pollutant types, the most effective approach to microbial biodegradation is to use a mixture of bacterial and fungal species and strains, each specific to the biodegradation of one or more types of contaminants.",
	"topic_id": null,
	"id": null,
	"category_id": null,
	"answer": "sites",
	"sub_cat_id": null
}, {
	"question": "_______________________________ are known to confer various benefits to their human and animal hosts health including aiding digestion, production of beneficial vitamins and amino acids, and suppression of pathogenic microbes.",
	"topic_id": null,
	"id": null,
	"category_id": null,
	"answer": "Symbiotic microbial communities",
	"sub_cat_id": null
}, {
	"question": "____________ may be conferred by consuming fermented foods, probiotics (bacteria potentially beneficial to the digestive system) and/or prebiotics (substances consumed to promote the growth of probiotic microorganisms).",
	"topic_id": null,
	"id": null,
	"category_id": null,
	"answer": "Some benefit",
	"sub_cat_id": null
}, {
	"question": "The ways the microbiome influences human and animal health, as well as methods to influence the microbiome are active areas of research.",
	"topic_id": null,
	"id": null,
	"category_id": null,
	"answer": "Some benefit",
	"sub_cat_id": null
}, {
	"question": "Zoology (/z o\u028a \u02c8 \u0252 l \u0259 d\u0292 i/, zoh-OL-luh-jee) or animal _______ is the branch of _______ that relates to the animal kingdom, including the structure, embryology, evolution, classification, habits, and distribution of all animals, both living and extinct, and how they interact with their ecosystems.",
	"topic_id": null,
	"id": null,
	"category_id": null,
	"answer": "biology",
	"sub_cat_id": null
}, {
	"question": "________ is derived from Ancient Greek \u03b6\u1ff7\u03bf\u03bd, z\u014dion, i.",
	"topic_id": null,
	"id": null,
	"category_id": null,
	"answer": "The term",
	"sub_cat_id": null
}, {
	"question": "Although the concept of zoology as a single coherent field arose much later, _______________________ emerged from natural history reaching back to the works of Aristotle and Galen in the ancient Greco-Roman world.",
	"topic_id": null,
	"id": null,
	"category_id": null,
	"answer": "the zoological sciences",
	"sub_cat_id": null
}, {
	"question": "_________________ was further developed in the Middle Ages by Muslim physicians and scholars such as Albertus Magnus.",
	"topic_id": null,
	"id": null,
	"category_id": null,
	"answer": "This ancient work",
	"sub_cat_id": null
}, {
	"question": "During the Renaissance and early modern period, zoological thought was revolutionized in Europe by a renewed interest in empiricism and the discovery of many novel organisms.",
	"topic_id": null,
	"id": null,
	"category_id": null,
	"answer": "This ancient work",
	"sub_cat_id": null
}, {
	"question": "This ancient work was further developed in the Middle Ages by Muslim physicians and scholars such as Albertus Magnus.",
	"topic_id": null,
	"id": null,
	"category_id": null,
	"answer": "zoological thought",
	"sub_cat_id": null
}, {
	"question": "During the Renaissance and early modern period, __________________ was revolutionized in Europe by a renewed interest in empiricism and the discovery of many novel organisms.",
	"topic_id": null,
	"id": null,
	"category_id": null,
	"answer": "zoological thought",
	"sub_cat_id": null
}, {
	"question": "__________ revealed the previously unknown world of microorganisms, laying the groundwork for cell theory.",
	"topic_id": null,
	"id": null,
	"category_id": null,
	"answer": "Microscopy",
	"sub_cat_id": null
}, {
	"question": "The growing importance of natural theology, partly a response to the rise of mechanical philosophy, encouraged the growth of natural history (although it entrenched the argument from design).",
	"topic_id": null,
	"id": null,
	"category_id": null,
	"answer": "Microscopy",
	"sub_cat_id": null
}, {
	"question": "Over the 18th and 19th centuries, _______ became an increasingly professional scientific discipline.",
	"topic_id": null,
	"id": null,
	"category_id": null,
	"answer": "zoology",
	"sub_cat_id": null
}, {
	"question": "___________ began to reject essentialism and consider the importance of extinction and the mutability of species.",
	"topic_id": null,
	"id": null,
	"category_id": null,
	"answer": "Naturalists",
	"sub_cat_id": null
}, {
	"question": "___________ provided a new perspective on the fundamental basis of life.",
	"topic_id": null,
	"id": null,
	"category_id": null,
	"answer": "Cell theory",
	"sub_cat_id": null
}, {
	"question": "______ gave new direction to morphology and physiology, by uniting them in a common biological theory: the theory of organic evolution.",
	"topic_id": null,
	"id": null,
	"category_id": null,
	"answer": "Darwin",
	"sub_cat_id": null
}, {
	"question": "__________ was a reconstruction of the classification of animals upon a genealogical basis, fresh investigation of the development of animals, and early attempts to determine their genetic relationships.",
	"topic_id": null,
	"id": null,
	"category_id": null,
	"answer": "The result",
	"sub_cat_id": null
}, {
	"question": "Anatomy and cell biology are ___________ that are closely related, and can be categorized under \"structural\" studies.",
	"topic_id": null,
	"id": null,
	"category_id": null,
	"answer": "two studies",
	"sub_cat_id": null
}, {
	"question": "_____________________ have traditionally been divided into plant physiology and animal physiology, but some principles of physiology are universal, no matter what particular organism is being studied.",
	"topic_id": null,
	"id": null,
	"category_id": null,
	"answer": "Physiological studies",
	"sub_cat_id": null
}, {
	"question": "_____________________ is concerned with the origin and descent of species, as well as their change over time, and includes scientists from many taxonomically oriented disciplines.",
	"topic_id": null,
	"id": null,
	"category_id": null,
	"answer": "Evolutionary research",
	"sub_cat_id": null
}, {
	"question": "For example, it generally involves __________ who have special training in particular organisms such as mammalogy, ornithology, herpetology, or entomology, but use those organisms as systems to answer general questions about evolution.",
	"topic_id": null,
	"id": null,
	"category_id": null,
	"answer": "scientists",
	"sub_cat_id": null
}, {
	"question": "____________________ is partly based on paleontology, which uses the fossil record to answer questions about the mode and tempo of evolution,[11] and partly on the developments in areas such as population genetics [12] and evolutionary theory.",
	"topic_id": null,
	"id": null,
	"category_id": null,
	"answer": "Evolutionary biology",
	"sub_cat_id": null
}, {
	"question": "Evolutionary biology is partly based on ____________, which uses the fossil record to answer questions about the mode and tempo of evolution,[11] and partly on the developments in areas such as population genetics [12] and evolutionary theory.",
	"topic_id": null,
	"id": null,
	"category_id": null,
	"answer": "paleontology",
	"sub_cat_id": null
}, {
	"question": "In the 1980s, _____________________ re-entered evolutionary biology from its initial exclusion from the modern synthesis through the study of evolutionary _____________________.",
	"topic_id": null,
	"id": null,
	"category_id": null,
	"answer": "developmental biology",
	"sub_cat_id": null
}, {
	"question": "Related fields often considered part of evolutionary biology are phylogenetics, systematics, and taxonomy.",
	"topic_id": null,
	"id": null,
	"category_id": null,
	"answer": "developmental biology",
	"sub_cat_id": null
}, {
	"question": "__________________________ possess membrane-bound cell organelles and include fungi and protists, whereas prokaryotic organisms\u2014all of which are microorganisms\u2014are conventionally classified as lacking membrane-bound organelles and include eubacteria and archaebacteria.",
	"topic_id": null,
	"id": null,
	"category_id": null,
	"answer": "Eukaryotic micro-organisms",
	"sub_cat_id": null
}, {
	"question": "Eukaryotic micro-organisms possess membrane-bound cell organelles and include __________________, whereas prokaryotic organisms\u2014all of which are microorganisms\u2014are conventionally classified as lacking membrane-bound organelles and include eubacteria and archaebacteria.",
	"topic_id": null,
	"id": null,
	"category_id": null,
	"answer": "fungi and protists",
	"sub_cat_id": null
}, {
	"question": "Eukaryotic micro-organisms possess membrane-bound cell organelles and include fungi and protists, whereas prokaryotic organisms\u2014all of which are __________________ conventionally classified as lacking membrane-bound organelles and include eubacteria and archaebacteria.",
	"topic_id": null,
	"id": null,
	"category_id": null,
	"answer": "microorganisms\u2014are",
	"sub_cat_id": null
}, {
	"question": "_______________ traditionally relied on culture, staining, and microscopy.",
	"topic_id": null,
	"id": null,
	"category_id": null,
	"answer": "Microbiologists",
	"sub_cat_id": null
}, {
	"question": "However, less than 1% of __________________ present in common environments can be cultured in isolation using current means.",
	"topic_id": null,
	"id": null,
	"category_id": null,
	"answer": "the microorganisms",
	"sub_cat_id": null
}, {
	"question": "Microbiologists often rely on extraction or detection of nucleic acid, either DNA or RNA sequences.",
	"topic_id": null,
	"id": null,
	"category_id": null,
	"answer": "the microorganisms",
	"sub_cat_id": null
}, {
	"question": "However, less than 1% of the microorganisms present in common environments can be cultured in isolation using current means.",
	"topic_id": null,
	"id": null,
	"category_id": null,
	"answer": "Microbiologists",
	"sub_cat_id": null
}, {
	"question": "_______________ often rely on extraction or detection of nucleic acid, either DNA or RNA sequences.",
	"topic_id": null,
	"id": null,
	"category_id": null,
	"answer": "Microbiologists",
	"sub_cat_id": null
}, {
	"question": "_______ have been variably classified as organisms,[3] as they have been considered either as very simple microorganisms or very complex molecules.",
	"topic_id": null,
	"id": null,
	"category_id": null,
	"answer": "Viruses",
	"sub_cat_id": null
}, {
	"question": "Prions, never considered microorganisms, have been investigated ______________, however, as the clinical effects traced to them were originally presumed due to chronic viral infections, and virologists took search\u2014discovering \"infectious proteins\".",
	"topic_id": null,
	"id": null,
	"category_id": null,
	"answer": "by virologists",
	"sub_cat_id": null
}, {
	"question": "Prions, never considered microorganisms, have been investigated by virologists, however, as ____________________ traced to them were originally presumed due to chronic viral infections, and virologists took search\u2014discovering \"infectious proteins\".",
	"topic_id": null,
	"id": null,
	"category_id": null,
	"answer": "the clinical effects",
	"sub_cat_id": null
}, {
	"question": "Prions, never considered microorganisms, have been investigated by ___________, however, as the clinical effects traced to them were originally presumed due to chronic viral infections, and ___________ took search\u2014discovering \"infectious proteins\".",
	"topic_id": null,
	"id": null,
	"category_id": null,
	"answer": "virologists",
	"sub_cat_id": null
}, {
	"question": "As an application of microbiology, ____________________ is often introduced with medical principles of immunology as microbiology and immunology.",
	"topic_id": null,
	"id": null,
	"category_id": null,
	"answer": "medical microbiology",
	"sub_cat_id": null
}, {
	"question": "The branches of microbiology can be classified into pure and applied sciences.",
	"topic_id": null,
	"id": null,
	"category_id": null,
	"answer": "Microbiology",
	"sub_cat_id": null
}, {
	"question": "____________ can be also classified based on taxonomy, in the cases of bacteriology, mycology, protozoology, and phycology.",
	"topic_id": null,
	"id": null,
	"category_id": null,
	"answer": "Microbiology",
	"sub_cat_id": null
}, {
	"question": "There is ____________________ between the specific branches of microbiology with each other and with other disciplines, and certain aspects of these branches can extend beyond the traditional scope of microbiology.",
	"topic_id": null,
	"id": null,
	"category_id": null,
	"answer": "considerable overlap",
	"sub_cat_id": null
}, {
	"question": "__________ have also exploited their knowledge of microbes to produce biotechnologically important enzymes such as Taq polymerase, reporter genes for use in other genetic systems and novel molecular biology techniques such as the yeast two-hybrid system.",
	"topic_id": null,
	"id": null,
	"category_id": null,
	"answer": "Scientists",
	"sub_cat_id": null
}, {
	"question": "Scientists have also exploited their knowledge of ________ to produce biotechnologically important enzymes such as Taq polymerase, reporter genes for use in other genetic systems and novel molecular biology techniques such as the yeast two-hybrid system.",
	"topic_id": null,
	"id": null,
	"category_id": null,
	"answer": "microbes",
	"sub_cat_id": null
}, {
	"question": "________ can be used for the industrial production of amino acids.",
	"topic_id": null,
	"id": null,
	"category_id": null,
	"answer": "Bacteria",
	"sub_cat_id": null
}, {
	"question": "__________________________ is one of the most important bacterial species with an annual production of more than two million tons of amino acids, mainly L-glutamate and L-lysine.",
	"topic_id": null,
	"id": null,
	"category_id": null,
	"answer": "Corynebacterium glutamicum",
	"sub_cat_id": null
}, {
	"question": "Since some bacteria have the ability to synthesize antibiotics, they are used for medicinal purposes, such as Streptomyces to make aminoglycoside antibiotics.",
	"topic_id": null,
	"id": null,
	"category_id": null,
	"answer": "Corynebacterium glutamicum",
	"sub_cat_id": null
}, {
	"question": "Corynebacterium glutamicum is one of the most important bacterial species with an annual production of more than two million tons of amino acids, mainly L-glutamate and L-lysine.",
	"topic_id": null,
	"id": null,
	"category_id": null,
	"answer": "some bacteria",
	"sub_cat_id": null
}, {
	"question": "Since _____________ have the ability to synthesize antibiotics, they are used for medicinal purposes, such as Streptomyces to make aminoglycoside antibiotics.",
	"topic_id": null,
	"id": null,
	"category_id": null,
	"answer": "some bacteria",
	"sub_cat_id": null
}, {
	"question": "A variety of biopolymers, such as polysaccharides, polyesters, and polyamides, are produced _________________.",
	"topic_id": null,
	"id": null,
	"category_id": null,
	"answer": "by microorganisms",
	"sub_cat_id": null
}, {
	"question": "______________ are beneficial for microbial biodegradation or bioremediation of domestic, agricultural and industrial wastes and subsurface pollution in soils, sediments and marine environments.",
	"topic_id": null,
	"id": null,
	"category_id": null,
	"answer": "Microorganisms",
	"sub_cat_id": null
}, {
	"question": "Since _____ typically have multiple pollutant types, the most effective approach to microbial biodegradation is to use a mixture of bacterial and fungal species and strains, each specific to the biodegradation of one or more types of contaminants.",
	"topic_id": null,
	"id": null,
	"category_id": null,
	"answer": "sites",
	"sub_cat_id": null
}, {
	"question": "_______________________________ are known to confer various benefits to their human and animal hosts health including aiding digestion, production of beneficial vitamins and amino acids, and suppression of pathogenic microbes.",
	"topic_id": null,
	"id": null,
	"category_id": null,
	"answer": "Symbiotic microbial communities",
	"sub_cat_id": null
}, {
	"question": "____________ may be conferred by consuming fermented foods, probiotics (bacteria potentially beneficial to the digestive system) and/or prebiotics (substances consumed to promote the growth of probiotic microorganisms).",
	"topic_id": null,
	"id": null,
	"category_id": null,
	"answer": "Some benefit",
	"sub_cat_id": null
}, {
	"question": "The ways the microbiome influences human and animal health, as well as methods to influence the microbiome are active areas of research.",
	"topic_id": null,
	"id": null,
	"category_id": null,
	"answer": "Some benefit",
	"sub_cat_id": null
}, {
	"question": "____________ is the scientific study of the nervous system.",
	"topic_id": null,
	"id": null,
	"category_id": null,
	"answer": "Neuroscience",
	"sub_cat_id": null
}, {
	"question": "Traditionally, neuroscience has been seen as a branch of biology.",
	"topic_id": null,
	"id": null,
	"category_id": null,
	"answer": "Neuroscience",
	"sub_cat_id": null
}, {
	"question": "Neuroscience is the scientific study of the nervous system.",
	"topic_id": null,
	"id": null,
	"category_id": null,
	"answer": "neuroscience",
	"sub_cat_id": null
}, {
	"question": "Traditionally, ____________ has been seen as a branch of biology.",
	"topic_id": null,
	"id": null,
	"category_id": null,
	"answer": "neuroscience",
	"sub_cat_id": null
}, {
	"question": "However, it is currently ____________________________ that collaborates with other fields such as chemistry, cognitive science, computer science, engineering, linguistics, mathematics, medicine (including neurology), genetics, and allied disciplines including philosophy, physics, and psychology.",
	"topic_id": null,
	"id": null,
	"category_id": null,
	"answer": "an interdisciplinary science",
	"sub_cat_id": null
}, {
	"question": "_____________________ is usually used interchangeably with the term neuroscience, although the former refers specifically to the biology of the nervous system, whereas the latter refers to the entire science of the nervous system.",
	"topic_id": null,
	"id": null,
	"category_id": null,
	"answer": "The term neurobiology",
	"sub_cat_id": null
}, {
	"question": "The scope of neuroscience has broadened to include ____________________ used to study the molecular, cellular, developmental, structural, functional, evolutionary, computational, and medical aspects of the nervous system.",
	"topic_id": null,
	"id": null,
	"category_id": null,
	"answer": "different approaches",
	"sub_cat_id": null
}, {
	"question": "The techniques used __________________ have also expanded enormously, from molecular and cellular studies of individual nerve cells to imaging of sensory and motor tasks in the brain.",
	"topic_id": null,
	"id": null,
	"category_id": null,
	"answer": "by neuroscientists",
	"sub_cat_id": null
}, {
	"question": "As a result of the increasing number of __________ who study the nervous system, several prominent neuroscience organizations have been formed to provide a forum to all neuro__________ and educators.",
	"topic_id": null,
	"id": null,
	"category_id": null,
	"answer": "scientists",
	"sub_cat_id": null
}, {
	"question": "Evidence of trepanation, the surgical practice of either drilling or scraping ______ into the skull with the purpose of curing headaches or mental disorders or relieving cranial pressure, being performed on patients dates back to Neolithic times and has been found in various cultures throughout the world.",
	"topic_id": null,
	"id": null,
	"category_id": null,
	"answer": "a hole",
	"sub_cat_id": null
}, {
	"question": "_______________________, the surgical practice of either drilling or scraping a hole into the skull with the purpose of curing headaches or mental disorders or relieving cranial pressure, being performed on patients dates back to Neolithic times and has been found in various cultures throughout the world.",
	"topic_id": null,
	"id": null,
	"category_id": null,
	"answer": "Evidence of trepanation",
	"sub_cat_id": null
}, {
	"question": "___________ dating back to 1700\u00a0BC indicated that the Egyptians had some knowledge about symptoms of brain damage.",
	"topic_id": null,
	"id": null,
	"category_id": null,
	"answer": "Manuscripts",
	"sub_cat_id": null
}, {
	"question": "In Egypt, from the late Middle Kingdom onwards, _________ was regularly removed in preparation for mummification.",
	"topic_id": null,
	"id": null,
	"category_id": null,
	"answer": "the brain",
	"sub_cat_id": null
}, {
	"question": "It was believed at the time that _________ was the seat of intelligence.",
	"topic_id": null,
	"id": null,
	"category_id": null,
	"answer": "the heart",
	"sub_cat_id": null
}, {
	"question": "According to Herodotus, the first step of _____________ was to \"take a crooked piece of iron, and with it draw out the brain through the nostrils, thus getting rid of a portion, while the skull is cleared of the rest by rinsing with drugs.",
	"topic_id": null,
	"id": null,
	"category_id": null,
	"answer": "mummification",
	"sub_cat_id": null
}, {
	"question": "According to Herodotus, the first step of mummification was to \"take a crooked piece of iron, and with it draw out the brain through the nostrils, thus getting rid of a portion, while _________ is cleared of the rest by rinsing with drugs.",
	"topic_id": null,
	"id": null,
	"category_id": null,
	"answer": "the skull",
	"sub_cat_id": null
}, {
	"question": "The view that _________ was the source of consciousness was not challenged until the time of the Greek physician Hippocrates.",
	"topic_id": null,
	"id": null,
	"category_id": null,
	"answer": "the heart",
	"sub_cat_id": null
}, {
	"question": "_____ also speculated that the brain was the seat of the rational part of the soul.",
	"topic_id": null,
	"id": null,
	"category_id": null,
	"answer": "Plato",
	"sub_cat_id": null
}, {
	"question": "Aristotle, however, believed the heart was the center of intelligence and that the brain regulated the amount of heat from the heart.",
	"topic_id": null,
	"id": null,
	"category_id": null,
	"answer": "Plato",
	"sub_cat_id": null
}, {
	"question": "This view was generally accepted until the Roman physician Galen, a follower of Hippocrates and physician to Roman gladiators, observed that his patients lost their mental faculties when they had sustained damage to their brains.",
	"topic_id": null,
	"id": null,
	"category_id": null,
	"answer": "Plato",
	"sub_cat_id": null
}, {
	"question": "_____________ used a silver chromate salt to reveal the intricate structures of individual neurons.",
	"topic_id": null,
	"id": null,
	"category_id": null,
	"answer": "The procedure",
	"sub_cat_id": null
}, {
	"question": "_____________ was used by Santiago Ram\u00f3n y Cajal and led to the formation of the neuron doctrine, the hypothesis that the functional unit of the brain is the neuron.",
	"topic_id": null,
	"id": null,
	"category_id": null,
	"answer": "His technique",
	"sub_cat_id": null
}, {
	"question": "Golgi and Ram\u00f3n y Cajal shared the Nobel Prize in Physiology or Medicine in 1906 for their extensive observations, descriptions, and categorizations of neurons throughout the brain.",
	"topic_id": null,
	"id": null,
	"category_id": null,
	"answer": "His technique",
	"sub_cat_id": null
}, {
	"question": "Zoology (/z o\u028a \u02c8 \u0252 l \u0259 d\u0292 i/, zoh-OL-luh-jee) or animal _______ is the branch of _______ that relates to the animal kingdom, including the structure, embryology, evolution, classification, habits, and distribution of all animals, both living and extinct, and how they interact with their ecosystems.",
	"topic_id": null,
	"id": null,
	"category_id": null,
	"answer": "biology",
	"sub_cat_id": null
}, {
	"question": "________ is derived from Ancient Greek \u03b6\u1ff7\u03bf\u03bd, z\u014dion, i.",
	"topic_id": null,
	"id": null,
	"category_id": null,
	"answer": "The term",
	"sub_cat_id": null
}, {
	"question": "Although the concept of zoology as a single coherent field arose much later, _______________________ emerged from natural history reaching back to the works of Aristotle and Galen in the ancient Greco-Roman world.",
	"topic_id": null,
	"id": null,
	"category_id": null,
	"answer": "the zoological sciences",
	"sub_cat_id": null
}, {
	"question": "_________________ was further developed in the Middle Ages by Muslim physicians and scholars such as Albertus Magnus.",
	"topic_id": null,
	"id": null,
	"category_id": null,
	"answer": "This ancient work",
	"sub_cat_id": null
}, {
	"question": "During the Renaissance and early modern period, zoological thought was revolutionized in Europe by a renewed interest in empiricism and the discovery of many novel organisms.",
	"topic_id": null,
	"id": null,
	"category_id": null,
	"answer": "This ancient work",
	"sub_cat_id": null
}, {
	"question": "This ancient work was further developed in the Middle Ages by Muslim physicians and scholars such as Albertus Magnus.",
	"topic_id": null,
	"id": null,
	"category_id": null,
	"answer": "zoological thought",
	"sub_cat_id": null
}, {
	"question": "During the Renaissance and early modern period, __________________ was revolutionized in Europe by a renewed interest in empiricism and the discovery of many novel organisms.",
	"topic_id": null,
	"id": null,
	"category_id": null,
	"answer": "zoological thought",
	"sub_cat_id": null
}, {
	"question": "__________ revealed the previously unknown world of microorganisms, laying the groundwork for cell theory.",
	"topic_id": null,
	"id": null,
	"category_id": null,
	"answer": "Microscopy",
	"sub_cat_id": null
}, {
	"question": "The growing importance of natural theology, partly a response to the rise of mechanical philosophy, encouraged the growth of natural history (although it entrenched the argument from design).",
	"topic_id": null,
	"id": null,
	"category_id": null,
	"answer": "Microscopy",
	"sub_cat_id": null
}, {
	"question": "Over the 18th and 19th centuries, _______ became an increasingly professional scientific discipline.",
	"topic_id": null,
	"id": null,
	"category_id": null,
	"answer": "zoology",
	"sub_cat_id": null
}, {
	"question": "___________ began to reject essentialism and consider the importance of extinction and the mutability of species.",
	"topic_id": null,
	"id": null,
	"category_id": null,
	"answer": "Naturalists",
	"sub_cat_id": null
}, {
	"question": "___________ provided a new perspective on the fundamental basis of life.",
	"topic_id": null,
	"id": null,
	"category_id": null,
	"answer": "Cell theory",
	"sub_cat_id": null
}, {
	"question": "______ gave new direction to morphology and physiology, by uniting them in a common biological theory: the theory of organic evolution.",
	"topic_id": null,
	"id": null,
	"category_id": null,
	"answer": "Darwin",
	"sub_cat_id": null
}, {
	"question": "__________ was a reconstruction of the classification of animals upon a genealogical basis, fresh investigation of the development of animals, and early attempts to determine their genetic relationships.",
	"topic_id": null,
	"id": null,
	"category_id": null,
	"answer": "The result",
	"sub_cat_id": null
}, {
	"question": "Anatomy and cell biology are ___________ that are closely related, and can be categorized under \"structural\" studies.",
	"topic_id": null,
	"id": null,
	"category_id": null,
	"answer": "two studies",
	"sub_cat_id": null
}, {
	"question": "_____________________ have traditionally been divided into plant physiology and animal physiology, but some principles of physiology are universal, no matter what particular organism is being studied.",
	"topic_id": null,
	"id": null,
	"category_id": null,
	"answer": "Physiological studies",
	"sub_cat_id": null
}, {
	"question": "_____________________ is concerned with the origin and descent of species, as well as their change over time, and includes scientists from many taxonomically oriented disciplines.",
	"topic_id": null,
	"id": null,
	"category_id": null,
	"answer": "Evolutionary research",
	"sub_cat_id": null
}, {
	"question": "For example, it generally involves __________ who have special training in particular organisms such as mammalogy, ornithology, herpetology, or entomology, but use those organisms as systems to answer general questions about evolution.",
	"topic_id": null,
	"id": null,
	"category_id": null,
	"answer": "scientists",
	"sub_cat_id": null
}, {
	"question": "____________________ is partly based on paleontology, which uses the fossil record to answer questions about the mode and tempo of evolution,[11] and partly on the developments in areas such as population genetics [12] and evolutionary theory.",
	"topic_id": null,
	"id": null,
	"category_id": null,
	"answer": "Evolutionary biology",
	"sub_cat_id": null
}, {
	"question": "Evolutionary biology is partly based on ____________, which uses the fossil record to answer questions about the mode and tempo of evolution,[11] and partly on the developments in areas such as population genetics [12] and evolutionary theory.",
	"topic_id": null,
	"id": null,
	"category_id": null,
	"answer": "paleontology",
	"sub_cat_id": null
}, {
	"question": "In the 1980s, _____________________ re-entered evolutionary biology from its initial exclusion from the modern synthesis through the study of evolutionary _____________________.",
	"topic_id": null,
	"id": null,
	"category_id": null,
	"answer": "developmental biology",
	"sub_cat_id": null
}, {
	"question": "Related fields often considered part of evolutionary biology are phylogenetics, systematics, and taxonomy.",
	"topic_id": null,
	"id": null,
	"category_id": null,
	"answer": "developmental biology",
	"sub_cat_id": null
}, {
	"question": "__________________________ possess membrane-bound cell organelles and include fungi and protists, whereas prokaryotic organisms\u2014all of which are microorganisms\u2014are conventionally classified as lacking membrane-bound organelles and include eubacteria and archaebacteria.",
	"topic_id": null,
	"id": null,
	"category_id": null,
	"answer": "Eukaryotic micro-organisms",
	"sub_cat_id": null
}, {
	"question": "Eukaryotic micro-organisms possess membrane-bound cell organelles and include __________________, whereas prokaryotic organisms\u2014all of which are microorganisms\u2014are conventionally classified as lacking membrane-bound organelles and include eubacteria and archaebacteria.",
	"topic_id": null,
	"id": null,
	"category_id": null,
	"answer": "fungi and protists",
	"sub_cat_id": null
}, {
	"question": "Eukaryotic micro-organisms possess membrane-bound cell organelles and include fungi and protists, whereas prokaryotic organisms\u2014all of which are __________________ conventionally classified as lacking membrane-bound organelles and include eubacteria and archaebacteria.",
	"topic_id": null,
	"id": null,
	"category_id": null,
	"answer": "microorganisms\u2014are",
	"sub_cat_id": null
}, {
	"question": "_______________ traditionally relied on culture, staining, and microscopy.",
	"topic_id": null,
	"id": null,
	"category_id": null,
	"answer": "Microbiologists",
	"sub_cat_id": null
}, {
	"question": "However, less than 1% of __________________ present in common environments can be cultured in isolation using current means.",
	"topic_id": null,
	"id": null,
	"category_id": null,
	"answer": "the microorganisms",
	"sub_cat_id": null
}, {
	"question": "Microbiologists often rely on extraction or detection of nucleic acid, either DNA or RNA sequences.",
	"topic_id": null,
	"id": null,
	"category_id": null,
	"answer": "the microorganisms",
	"sub_cat_id": null
}, {
	"question": "However, less than 1% of the microorganisms present in common environments can be cultured in isolation using current means.",
	"topic_id": null,
	"id": null,
	"category_id": null,
	"answer": "Microbiologists",
	"sub_cat_id": null
}, {
	"question": "_______________ often rely on extraction or detection of nucleic acid, either DNA or RNA sequences.",
	"topic_id": null,
	"id": null,
	"category_id": null,
	"answer": "Microbiologists",
	"sub_cat_id": null
}, {
	"question": "_______ have been variably classified as organisms,[3] as they have been considered either as very simple microorganisms or very complex molecules.",
	"topic_id": null,
	"id": null,
	"category_id": null,
	"answer": "Viruses",
	"sub_cat_id": null
}, {
	"question": "Prions, never considered microorganisms, have been investigated ______________, however, as the clinical effects traced to them were originally presumed due to chronic viral infections, and virologists took search\u2014discovering \"infectious proteins\".",
	"topic_id": null,
	"id": null,
	"category_id": null,
	"answer": "by virologists",
	"sub_cat_id": null
}, {
	"question": "Prions, never considered microorganisms, have been investigated by virologists, however, as ____________________ traced to them were originally presumed due to chronic viral infections, and virologists took search\u2014discovering \"infectious proteins\".",
	"topic_id": null,
	"id": null,
	"category_id": null,
	"answer": "the clinical effects",
	"sub_cat_id": null
}, {
	"question": "Prions, never considered microorganisms, have been investigated by ___________, however, as the clinical effects traced to them were originally presumed due to chronic viral infections, and ___________ took search\u2014discovering \"infectious proteins\".",
	"topic_id": null,
	"id": null,
	"category_id": null,
	"answer": "virologists",
	"sub_cat_id": null
}, {
	"question": "As an application of microbiology, ____________________ is often introduced with medical principles of immunology as microbiology and immunology.",
	"topic_id": null,
	"id": null,
	"category_id": null,
	"answer": "medical microbiology",
	"sub_cat_id": null
}, {
	"question": "The branches of microbiology can be classified into pure and applied sciences.",
	"topic_id": null,
	"id": null,
	"category_id": null,
	"answer": "Microbiology",
	"sub_cat_id": null
}, {
	"question": "____________ can be also classified based on taxonomy, in the cases of bacteriology, mycology, protozoology, and phycology.",
	"topic_id": null,
	"id": null,
	"category_id": null,
	"answer": "Microbiology",
	"sub_cat_id": null
}, {
	"question": "There is ____________________ between the specific branches of microbiology with each other and with other disciplines, and certain aspects of these branches can extend beyond the traditional scope of microbiology.",
	"topic_id": null,
	"id": null,
	"category_id": null,
	"answer": "considerable overlap",
	"sub_cat_id": null
}, {
	"question": "__________ have also exploited their knowledge of microbes to produce biotechnologically important enzymes such as Taq polymerase, reporter genes for use in other genetic systems and novel molecular biology techniques such as the yeast two-hybrid system.",
	"topic_id": null,
	"id": null,
	"category_id": null,
	"answer": "Scientists",
	"sub_cat_id": null
}, {
	"question": "Scientists have also exploited their knowledge of ________ to produce biotechnologically important enzymes such as Taq polymerase, reporter genes for use in other genetic systems and novel molecular biology techniques such as the yeast two-hybrid system.",
	"topic_id": null,
	"id": null,
	"category_id": null,
	"answer": "microbes",
	"sub_cat_id": null
}, {
	"question": "________ can be used for the industrial production of amino acids.",
	"topic_id": null,
	"id": null,
	"category_id": null,
	"answer": "Bacteria",
	"sub_cat_id": null
}, {
	"question": "__________________________ is one of the most important bacterial species with an annual production of more than two million tons of amino acids, mainly L-glutamate and L-lysine.",
	"topic_id": null,
	"id": null,
	"category_id": null,
	"answer": "Corynebacterium glutamicum",
	"sub_cat_id": null
}, {
	"question": "Since some bacteria have the ability to synthesize antibiotics, they are used for medicinal purposes, such as Streptomyces to make aminoglycoside antibiotics.",
	"topic_id": null,
	"id": null,
	"category_id": null,
	"answer": "Corynebacterium glutamicum",
	"sub_cat_id": null
}, {
	"question": "Corynebacterium glutamicum is one of the most important bacterial species with an annual production of more than two million tons of amino acids, mainly L-glutamate and L-lysine.",
	"topic_id": null,
	"id": null,
	"category_id": null,
	"answer": "some bacteria",
	"sub_cat_id": null
}, {
	"question": "Since _____________ have the ability to synthesize antibiotics, they are used for medicinal purposes, such as Streptomyces to make aminoglycoside antibiotics.",
	"topic_id": null,
	"id": null,
	"category_id": null,
	"answer": "some bacteria",
	"sub_cat_id": null
}, {
	"question": "A variety of biopolymers, such as polysaccharides, polyesters, and polyamides, are produced _________________.",
	"topic_id": null,
	"id": null,
	"category_id": null,
	"answer": "by microorganisms",
	"sub_cat_id": null
}, {
	"question": "______________ are beneficial for microbial biodegradation or bioremediation of domestic, agricultural and industrial wastes and subsurface pollution in soils, sediments and marine environments.",
	"topic_id": null,
	"id": null,
	"category_id": null,
	"answer": "Microorganisms",
	"sub_cat_id": null
}, {
	"question": "Since _____ typically have multiple pollutant types, the most effective approach to microbial biodegradation is to use a mixture of bacterial and fungal species and strains, each specific to the biodegradation of one or more types of contaminants.",
	"topic_id": null,
	"id": null,
	"category_id": null,
	"answer": "sites",
	"sub_cat_id": null
}, {
	"question": "_______________________________ are known to confer various benefits to their human and animal hosts health including aiding digestion, production of beneficial vitamins and amino acids, and suppression of pathogenic microbes.",
	"topic_id": null,
	"id": null,
	"category_id": null,
	"answer": "Symbiotic microbial communities",
	"sub_cat_id": null
}, {
	"question": "____________ may be conferred by consuming fermented foods, probiotics (bacteria potentially beneficial to the digestive system) and/or prebiotics (substances consumed to promote the growth of probiotic microorganisms).",
	"topic_id": null,
	"id": null,
	"category_id": null,
	"answer": "Some benefit",
	"sub_cat_id": null
}, {
	"question": "The ways the microbiome influences human and animal health, as well as methods to influence the microbiome are active areas of research.",
	"topic_id": null,
	"id": null,
	"category_id": null,
	"answer": "Some benefit",
	"sub_cat_id": null
}, {
	"question": "____________ is the scientific study of the nervous system.",
	"topic_id": null,
	"id": null,
	"category_id": null,
	"answer": "Neuroscience",
	"sub_cat_id": null
}, {
	"question": "Traditionally, neuroscience has been seen as a branch of biology.",
	"topic_id": null,
	"id": null,
	"category_id": null,
	"answer": "Neuroscience",
	"sub_cat_id": null
}, {
	"question": "Neuroscience is the scientific study of the nervous system.",
	"topic_id": null,
	"id": null,
	"category_id": null,
	"answer": "neuroscience",
	"sub_cat_id": null
}, {
	"question": "Traditionally, ____________ has been seen as a branch of biology.",
	"topic_id": null,
	"id": null,
	"category_id": null,
	"answer": "neuroscience",
	"sub_cat_id": null
}, {
	"question": "However, it is currently ____________________________ that collaborates with other fields such as chemistry, cognitive science, computer science, engineering, linguistics, mathematics, medicine (including neurology), genetics, and allied disciplines including philosophy, physics, and psychology.",
	"topic_id": null,
	"id": null,
	"category_id": null,
	"answer": "an interdisciplinary science",
	"sub_cat_id": null
}, {
	"question": "_____________________ is usually used interchangeably with the term neuroscience, although the former refers specifically to the biology of the nervous system, whereas the latter refers to the entire science of the nervous system.",
	"topic_id": null,
	"id": null,
	"category_id": null,
	"answer": "The term neurobiology",
	"sub_cat_id": null
}, {
	"question": "The scope of neuroscience has broadened to include ____________________ used to study the molecular, cellular, developmental, structural, functional, evolutionary, computational, and medical aspects of the nervous system.",
	"topic_id": null,
	"id": null,
	"category_id": null,
	"answer": "different approaches",
	"sub_cat_id": null
}, {
	"question": "The techniques used __________________ have also expanded enormously, from molecular and cellular studies of individual nerve cells to imaging of sensory and motor tasks in the brain.",
	"topic_id": null,
	"id": null,
	"category_id": null,
	"answer": "by neuroscientists",
	"sub_cat_id": null
}, {
	"question": "As a result of the increasing number of __________ who study the nervous system, several prominent neuroscience organizations have been formed to provide a forum to all neuro__________ and educators.",
	"topic_id": null,
	"id": null,
	"category_id": null,
	"answer": "scientists",
	"sub_cat_id": null
}, {
	"question": "Evidence of trepanation, the surgical practice of either drilling or scraping ______ into the skull with the purpose of curing headaches or mental disorders or relieving cranial pressure, being performed on patients dates back to Neolithic times and has been found in various cultures throughout the world.",
	"topic_id": null,
	"id": null,
	"category_id": null,
	"answer": "a hole",
	"sub_cat_id": null
}, {
	"question": "_______________________, the surgical practice of either drilling or scraping a hole into the skull with the purpose of curing headaches or mental disorders or relieving cranial pressure, being performed on patients dates back to Neolithic times and has been found in various cultures throughout the world.",
	"topic_id": null,
	"id": null,
	"category_id": null,
	"answer": "Evidence of trepanation",
	"sub_cat_id": null
}, {
	"question": "___________ dating back to 1700\u00a0BC indicated that the Egyptians had some knowledge about symptoms of brain damage.",
	"topic_id": null,
	"id": null,
	"category_id": null,
	"answer": "Manuscripts",
	"sub_cat_id": null
}, {
	"question": "In Egypt, from the late Middle Kingdom onwards, _________ was regularly removed in preparation for mummification.",
	"topic_id": null,
	"id": null,
	"category_id": null,
	"answer": "the brain",
	"sub_cat_id": null
}, {
	"question": "It was believed at the time that _________ was the seat of intelligence.",
	"topic_id": null,
	"id": null,
	"category_id": null,
	"answer": "the heart",
	"sub_cat_id": null
}, {
	"question": "According to Herodotus, the first step of _____________ was to \"take a crooked piece of iron, and with it draw out the brain through the nostrils, thus getting rid of a portion, while the skull is cleared of the rest by rinsing with drugs.",
	"topic_id": null,
	"id": null,
	"category_id": null,
	"answer": "mummification",
	"sub_cat_id": null
}, {
	"question": "According to Herodotus, the first step of mummification was to \"take a crooked piece of iron, and with it draw out the brain through the nostrils, thus getting rid of a portion, while _________ is cleared of the rest by rinsing with drugs.",
	"topic_id": null,
	"id": null,
	"category_id": null,
	"answer": "the skull",
	"sub_cat_id": null
}, {
	"question": "The view that _________ was the source of consciousness was not challenged until the time of the Greek physician Hippocrates.",
	"topic_id": null,
	"id": null,
	"category_id": null,
	"answer": "the heart",
	"sub_cat_id": null
}, {
	"question": "_____ also speculated that the brain was the seat of the rational part of the soul.",
	"topic_id": null,
	"id": null,
	"category_id": null,
	"answer": "Plato",
	"sub_cat_id": null
}, {
	"question": "Aristotle, however, believed the heart was the center of intelligence and that the brain regulated the amount of heat from the heart.",
	"topic_id": null,
	"id": null,
	"category_id": null,
	"answer": "Plato",
	"sub_cat_id": null
}, {
	"question": "This view was generally accepted until the Roman physician Galen, a follower of Hippocrates and physician to Roman gladiators, observed that his patients lost their mental faculties when they had sustained damage to their brains.",
	"topic_id": null,
	"id": null,
	"category_id": null,
	"answer": "Plato",
	"sub_cat_id": null
}, {
	"question": "_____________ used a silver chromate salt to reveal the intricate structures of individual neurons.",
	"topic_id": null,
	"id": null,
	"category_id": null,
	"answer": "The procedure",
	"sub_cat_id": null
}, {
	"question": "_____________ was used by Santiago Ram\u00f3n y Cajal and led to the formation of the neuron doctrine, the hypothesis that the functional unit of the brain is the neuron.",
	"topic_id": null,
	"id": null,
	"category_id": null,
	"answer": "His technique",
	"sub_cat_id": null
}, {
	"question": "Golgi and Ram\u00f3n y Cajal shared the Nobel Prize in Physiology or Medicine in 1906 for their extensive observations, descriptions, and categorizations of neurons throughout the brain.",
	"topic_id": null,
	"id": null,
	"category_id": null,
	"answer": "His technique",
	"sub_cat_id": null
}, {
	"question": "__________ is the study of behavior and mind, embracing all aspects of conscious and unconscious experience as well as thought.",
	"topic_id": null,
	"id": null,
	"category_id": null,
	"answer": "Psychology",
	"sub_cat_id": null
}, {
	"question": "It is an academic discipline and __________________ which seeks to understand individuals and groups by establishing general principles and researching specific cases.",
	"topic_id": null,
	"id": null,
	"category_id": null,
	"answer": "an applied science",
	"sub_cat_id": null
}, {
	"question": "In this field, a professional practitioner or researcher is called a psychologist and can be classified as a social, behavioral, or cognitive scientist.",
	"topic_id": null,
	"id": null,
	"category_id": null,
	"answer": "an applied science",
	"sub_cat_id": null
}, {
	"question": "_____________ attempt to understand the role of mental functions in individual and social behavior, while also exploring the physiological and biological processes that underlie cognitive functions and behaviors.",
	"topic_id": null,
	"id": null,
	"category_id": null,
	"answer": "Psychologists",
	"sub_cat_id": null
}, {
	"question": "_____________ explore concepts such as perception, cognition, attention, emotion, intelligence, phenomenology, motivation, brain functioning, personality, behavior, and interpersonal relationships, including psychological resilience, family resilience, and other areas.",
	"topic_id": null,
	"id": null,
	"category_id": null,
	"answer": "Psychologists",
	"sub_cat_id": null
}, {
	"question": "_____________ of diverse orientations also consider the unconscious mind.",
	"topic_id": null,
	"id": null,
	"category_id": null,
	"answer": "Psychologists",
	"sub_cat_id": null
}, {
	"question": "_____________ employ empirical methods to infer causal and correlational relationships between psychosocial variables.",
	"topic_id": null,
	"id": null,
	"category_id": null,
	"answer": "Psychologists",
	"sub_cat_id": null
}, {
	"question": "__________ has been described as a \"hub science\",[4] with psychological findings linking to research and perspectives from the social sciences, natural sciences, medicine, humanities, and philosophy.",
	"topic_id": null,
	"id": null,
	"category_id": null,
	"answer": "Psychology",
	"sub_cat_id": null
}, {
	"question": "While _______________________ is often applied to the assessment and treatment of mental health problems, it is also directed towards understanding and solving problems in several spheres of human activity.",
	"topic_id": null,
	"id": null,
	"category_id": null,
	"answer": "psychological knowledge",
	"sub_cat_id": null
}, {
	"question": "Many do scientific research on a wide range of ______ related to mental processes and behavior, and typically work in university psychology departments or teach in other academic settings (e.",
	"topic_id": null,
	"id": null,
	"category_id": null,
	"answer": "topics",
	"sub_cat_id": null
}, {
	"question": "In 1890, _____________ defined psychology as \"the science of mental life, both of its phenomena and their conditions\".",
	"topic_id": null,
	"id": null,
	"category_id": null,
	"answer": "William James",
	"sub_cat_id": null
}, {
	"question": "_______________ enjoyed widespread currency for decades.",
	"topic_id": null,
	"id": null,
	"category_id": null,
	"answer": "This definition",
	"sub_cat_id": null
}, {
	"question": "Also since _____ defined it, the term more strongly connotes techniques of scientific experimentation.",
	"topic_id": null,
	"id": null,
	"category_id": null,
	"answer": "James",
	"sub_cat_id": null
}, {
	"question": "Folk psychology refers to the understanding of ordinary people, as contrasted with that of psychology professionals.",
	"topic_id": null,
	"id": null,
	"category_id": null,
	"answer": "James",
	"sub_cat_id": null
}, {
	"question": "Also since James defined it, _____________ strongly connotes techniques of scientific experimentation.",
	"topic_id": null,
	"id": null,
	"category_id": null,
	"answer": "the term more",
	"sub_cat_id": null
}, {
	"question": "__________ note that Greek philosophers, including Thales, Plato, and Aristotle (especially in his De Anima treatise),[14] addressed the workings of the mind.",
	"topic_id": null,
	"id": null,
	"category_id": null,
	"answer": "Historians",
	"sub_cat_id": null
}, {
	"question": "As early as the 4th century BC, Greek physician Hippocrates theorized that mental disorders had physical rather than supernatural causes.",
	"topic_id": null,
	"id": null,
	"category_id": null,
	"answer": "Historians",
	"sub_cat_id": null
}, {
	"question": "In China, ___________________________ grew from the philosophical works of Laozi and Confucius, and later from the doctrines of Buddhism.",
	"topic_id": null,
	"id": null,
	"category_id": null,
	"answer": "psychological understanding",
	"sub_cat_id": null
}, {
	"question": "This body of knowledge involves ________ drawn from introspection and observation, as well as techniques for focused thinking and acting.",
	"topic_id": null,
	"id": null,
	"category_id": null,
	"answer": "insights",
	"sub_cat_id": null
}, {
	"question": "This body of knowledge involves insights drawn from introspection and observation, as well as __________ for focused thinking and acting.",
	"topic_id": null,
	"id": null,
	"category_id": null,
	"answer": "techniques",
	"sub_cat_id": null
}, {
	"question": "_______________ known as The Yellow Emperor's Classic of Internal Medicine identifies the brain as the nexus of wisdom and sensation, includes theories of personality based on yin\u2013yang balance, and analyzes mental disorder in terms of physiological and social disequilibria.",
	"topic_id": null,
	"id": null,
	"category_id": null,
	"answer": "An ancient text",
	"sub_cat_id": null
}, {
	"question": "An ancient text known as The Yellow Emperor's Classic of Internal Medicine identifies the brain as the nexus of wisdom and sensation, includes _______________________ based on yin\u2013yang balance, and analyzes mental disorder in terms of physiological and social disequilibria.",
	"topic_id": null,
	"id": null,
	"category_id": null,
	"answer": "theories of personality",
	"sub_cat_id": null
}, {
	"question": "Chinese scholarship focused on _________ advanced in the Qing Dynasty with the work of Western-educated Fang Yizhi (1611\u20131671), Liu Zhi (1660\u20131730), and Wang Qingren (1768\u20131831).",
	"topic_id": null,
	"id": null,
	"category_id": null,
	"answer": "the brain",
	"sub_cat_id": null
}, {
	"question": "____________ emphasized the importance of the brain as the center of the nervous system, linked mental disorder with brain diseases, investigated the causes of dreams and insomnia, and advanced a theory of hemispheric lateralization in brain function.",
	"topic_id": null,
	"id": null,
	"category_id": null,
	"answer": "Wang Qingren",
	"sub_cat_id": null
}, {
	"sub_cat_id": null,
	"answer": "structural\u2014which",
	"question": "It is concerned particularly with the forms of biological molecules and [.",
	"category_id": null,
	"id": null,
	"topic_id": null
}, {
	"sub_cat_id": null,
	"answer": "Biochemistry",
	"question": "____________ is the study of the chemical substances and vital processes occurring in live organisms.",
	"category_id": null,
	"id": null,
	"topic_id": null
}, {
	"sub_cat_id": null,
	"answer": "Genetics",
	"question": "________ is the study of the effect of genetic differences on organisms.",
	"category_id": null,
	"id": null,
	"topic_id": null
}, {
	"sub_cat_id": null,
	"answer": "Genetic interactions (epistasis)",
	"question": "________________________________ can often confound simple interpretations of such \"knockout\" studies.",
	"category_id": null,
	"id": null,
	"topic_id": null
}, {
	"sub_cat_id": null,
	"answer": "Molecular biology",
	"question": "_________________ is the study of molecular underpinnings of the processes of replication, transcription, translation, and cell function.",
	"category_id": null,
	"id": null,
	"topic_id": null
}, {
	"sub_cat_id": null,
	"answer": "genetic material",
	"question": "The central dogma of molecular biology where ________________ is transcribed into RNA and then translated into protein, despite being an oversimplified picture of molecular biology, still provides a good starting point for understanding the field.",
	"category_id": null,
	"id": null,
	"topic_id": null
}, {
	"sub_cat_id": null,
	"answer": "This picture",
	"question": "____________, however, is undergoing revision in light of emerging novel roles for RNA.",
	"category_id": null,
	"id": null,
	"topic_id": null
}, {
	"sub_cat_id": null,
	"answer": "revision",
	"question": "This picture, however, is undergoing ________ in light of emerging novel roles for RNA.",
	"category_id": null,
	"id": null,
	"topic_id": null
}, {
	"sub_cat_id": null,
	"answer": "recently much work",
	"question": "Much of the work in molecular biology is quantitative, and __________________ has been done at the interface of molecular biology and computer science in bioinformatics and computational biology.",
	"category_id": null,
	"id": null,
	"topic_id": null
}, {
	"sub_cat_id": null,
	"answer": "molecular biologists",
	"question": "Since the late 1950s and early 1960s, ____________________ have learned to characterize, isolate, and manipulate the molecular components of cells and organisms.",
	"category_id": null,
	"id": null,
	"topic_id": null
}, {
	"sub_cat_id": null,
	"answer": "molecular biology",
	"question": "One of the most basic techniques of _________________ to study protein function is molecular cloning.",
	"category_id": null,
	"id": null,
	"topic_id": null
}, {
	"sub_cat_id": null,
	"answer": "a plasmid",
	"question": "In this technique, DNA coding for a protein of interest is cloned (using PCR and/or restriction enzymes) into _________ (known as an expression vector).",
	"category_id": null,
	"id": null,
	"topic_id": null
}, {
	"sub_cat_id": null,
	"answer": "A vector",
	"question": "________ has 3 distinctive features: an origin of replication, a multiple cloning site (MCS), and a selective marker (usually antibiotic resistance).",
	"category_id": null,
	"id": null,
	"topic_id": null
}, {
	"sub_cat_id": null,
	"answer": "This plasmid",
	"question": "____________ can be inserted into either bacterial or animal cells.",
	"category_id": null,
	"id": null,
	"topic_id": null
}, {
	"sub_cat_id": null,
	"answer": "by transformation",
	"question": "Introducing DNA into bacterial cells can be done _________________ (via uptake of naked DNA), conjugation (via cell-cell contact) or by transduction (via viral vector).",
	"category_id": null,
	"id": null,
	"topic_id": null
}, {
	"sub_cat_id": null,
	"answer": "structural\u2014which",
	"question": "It is concerned particularly with the forms of biological molecules and [.",
	"category_id": null,
	"id": null,
	"topic_id": null
}, {
	"sub_cat_id": null,
	"answer": "Biochemistry",
	"question": "____________ is the study of the chemical substances and vital processes occurring in live organisms.",
	"category_id": null,
	"id": null,
	"topic_id": null
}, {
	"sub_cat_id": null,
	"answer": "Genetics",
	"question": "________ is the study of the effect of genetic differences on organisms.",
	"category_id": null,
	"id": null,
	"topic_id": null
}, {
	"sub_cat_id": null,
	"answer": "Genetic interactions (epistasis)",
	"question": "________________________________ can often confound simple interpretations of such \"knockout\" studies.",
	"category_id": null,
	"id": null,
	"topic_id": null
}, {
	"sub_cat_id": null,
	"answer": "Molecular biology",
	"question": "_________________ is the study of molecular underpinnings of the processes of replication, transcription, translation, and cell function.",
	"category_id": null,
	"id": null,
	"topic_id": null
}, {
	"sub_cat_id": null,
	"answer": "genetic material",
	"question": "The central dogma of molecular biology where ________________ is transcribed into RNA and then translated into protein, despite being an oversimplified picture of molecular biology, still provides a good starting point for understanding the field.",
	"category_id": null,
	"id": null,
	"topic_id": null
}, {
	"sub_cat_id": null,
	"answer": "This picture",
	"question": "____________, however, is undergoing revision in light of emerging novel roles for RNA.",
	"category_id": null,
	"id": null,
	"topic_id": null
}, {
	"sub_cat_id": null,
	"answer": "revision",
	"question": "This picture, however, is undergoing ________ in light of emerging novel roles for RNA.",
	"category_id": null,
	"id": null,
	"topic_id": null
}, {
	"sub_cat_id": null,
	"answer": "recently much work",
	"question": "Much of the work in molecular biology is quantitative, and __________________ has been done at the interface of molecular biology and computer science in bioinformatics and computational biology.",
	"category_id": null,
	"id": null,
	"topic_id": null
}, {
	"sub_cat_id": null,
	"answer": "molecular biologists",
	"question": "Since the late 1950s and early 1960s, ____________________ have learned to characterize, isolate, and manipulate the molecular components of cells and organisms.",
	"category_id": null,
	"id": null,
	"topic_id": null
}, {
	"sub_cat_id": null,
	"answer": "molecular biology",
	"question": "One of the most basic techniques of _________________ to study protein function is molecular cloning.",
	"category_id": null,
	"id": null,
	"topic_id": null
}, {
	"sub_cat_id": null,
	"answer": "a plasmid",
	"question": "In this technique, DNA coding for a protein of interest is cloned (using PCR and/or restriction enzymes) into _________ (known as an expression vector).",
	"category_id": null,
	"id": null,
	"topic_id": null
}, {
	"sub_cat_id": null,
	"answer": "A vector",
	"question": "________ has 3 distinctive features: an origin of replication, a multiple cloning site (MCS), and a selective marker (usually antibiotic resistance).",
	"category_id": null,
	"id": null,
	"topic_id": null
}, {
	"sub_cat_id": null,
	"answer": "This plasmid",
	"question": "____________ can be inserted into either bacterial or animal cells.",
	"category_id": null,
	"id": null,
	"topic_id": null
}, {
	"sub_cat_id": null,
	"answer": "by transformation",
	"question": "Introducing DNA into bacterial cells can be done _________________ (via uptake of naked DNA), conjugation (via cell-cell contact) or by transduction (via viral vector).",
	"category_id": null,
	"id": null,
	"topic_id": null
}, {
	"sub_cat_id": null,
	"answer": "Electrical engineering",
	"question": "______________________ is a field of engineering that generally deals with the study and application of electricity, electronics, and electromagnetism.",
	"category_id": null,
	"id": null,
	"topic_id": null
}, {
	"sub_cat_id": null,
	"answer": "This field",
	"question": "__________ first became an identifiable occupation in the latter half of the 19th century after commercialization of the electric telegraph, the telephone, and electric power distribution and use.",
	"category_id": null,
	"id": null,
	"topic_id": null
}, {
	"sub_cat_id": null,
	"answer": "Electrical engineering",
	"question": "______________________ has now subdivided into a wide range of subfields including electronics, digital computers, power engineering, telecommunications, control systems, radio-frequency engineering, signal processing, instrumentation, and microelectronics.",
	"category_id": null,
	"id": null,
	"topic_id": null
}, {
	"sub_cat_id": null,
	"answer": "Electrical engineers",
	"question": "____________________ typically hold a degree in electrical engineering or electronic engineering.",
	"category_id": null,
	"id": null,
	"topic_id": null
}, {
	"sub_cat_id": null,
	"answer": "engineers",
	"question": "Practicing _________ may have professional certification and be members of a professional body.",
	"category_id": null,
	"id": null,
	"topic_id": null
}, {
	"sub_cat_id": null,
	"answer": "Practicing engineers",
	"question": "____________________ may have professional certification and be members of a professional body.",
	"category_id": null,
	"id": null,
	"topic_id": null
}, {
	"sub_cat_id": null,
	"answer": "Electricity",
	"question": "___________ has been a subject of scientific interest since at least the early 17th century.",
	"category_id": null,
	"id": null,
	"topic_id": null
}, {
	"sub_cat_id": null,
	"answer": "William Gilbert",
	"question": "The first electrical engineer was probably _______________ who designed the versorium: a device that detected the presence of statically charged objects.",
	"category_id": null,
	"id": null,
	"topic_id": null
}, {
	"sub_cat_id": null,
	"answer": "a device",
	"question": "The first electrical engineer was probably William Gilbert who designed the versorium: ________ that detected the presence of statically charged objects.",
	"category_id": null,
	"id": null,
	"topic_id": null
}, {
	"sub_cat_id": null,
	"answer": "1800 Volta",
	"question": "He was also the first to draw a clear distinction between magnetism and static electricity and is credited with establishing the term electricity.",
	"category_id": null,
	"id": null,
	"topic_id": null
}, {
	"sub_cat_id": null,
	"answer": "1800 Volta",
	"question": "Then in 1762 Swedish professor Johan Carl Wilcke invented, and in 1775 Alessandro Volta improved, a device (for which Volta coined the name electrophorus) that produced a static electric charge, and by __________ had developed the voltaic pile, a forerunner of the electric battery.",
	"category_id": null,
	"id": null,
	"topic_id": null
}, {
	"sub_cat_id": null,
	"answer": "James Clerk Maxwell",
	"question": "Notable developments in this century include the work of Georg Ohm, who in 1827 quantified the relationship between the electric current and potential difference in a conductor, of Michael Faraday, the discoverer of electromagnetic induction in 1831, and of ___________________, who in 1873 published a unified theory of electricity and magnetism in his treatise Electricity and Magnetism.",
	"category_id": null,
	"id": null,
	"topic_id": null
}, {
	"sub_cat_id": null,
	"answer": "efforts",
	"question": "Beginning in the 1830s, _______ were made to apply electricity to practical use in the telegraph.",
	"category_id": null,
	"id": null,
	"topic_id": null
}, {
	"sub_cat_id": null,
	"answer": "electricity",
	"question": "Beginning in the 1830s, efforts were made to apply ___________ to practical use in the telegraph.",
	"category_id": null,
	"id": null,
	"topic_id": null
}, {
	"sub_cat_id": null,
	"answer": "the world",
	"question": "By the end of the 19th century, _________ had been forever changed by the rapid communication made possible by the engineering development of land-lines, submarine cables, and, from about 1890, wireless telegraphy.",
	"category_id": null,
	"id": null,
	"topic_id": null
}, {
	"sub_cat_id": null,
	"answer": "the definitions",
	"question": "This was achieved at an international conference in Chicago in 1893.",
	"category_id": null,
	"id": null,
	"topic_id": null
}, {
	"sub_cat_id": null,
	"answer": "the definitions",
	"question": "The publication of these standards formed the basis of future advances in standardisation in various industries, and in many countries _______________ were immediately recognised in relevant legislation.",
	"category_id": null,
	"id": null,
	"topic_id": null
}, {
	"sub_cat_id": null,
	"answer": "early electrical technology",
	"question": "That's because ___________________________ was electromechanical in nature.",
	"category_id": null,
	"id": null,
	"topic_id": null
}, {
	"sub_cat_id": null,
	"answer": "Thomas Edison",
	"question": "In 1882, _____________ switched on the world's first large-scale electric power network that provided 110 volts \u2014 direct current (DC) \u2014 to 59 customers on Manhattan Island in New York City.",
	"category_id": null,
	"id": null,
	"topic_id": null
}, {
	"sub_cat_id": null,
	"answer": "Sir Charles Parsons",
	"question": "In 1884, ___________________ invented the steam turbine allowing for more efficient electric power generation.",
	"category_id": null,
	"id": null,
	"topic_id": null
}, {
	"sub_cat_id": null,
	"answer": "invisible airborne waves",
	"question": "The mathematical work of James Clerk Maxwell during the 1850s had shown the relationship of different forms of electromagnetic radiation including possibility of ________________________ (later called \"radio waves\").",
	"category_id": null,
	"id": null,
	"topic_id": null
}, {
	"sub_cat_id": null,
	"answer": "structural\u2014which",
	"question": "It is concerned particularly with the forms of biological molecules and [.",
	"category_id": null,
	"id": null,
	"topic_id": null
}, {
	"sub_cat_id": null,
	"answer": "Biochemistry",
	"question": "____________ is the study of the chemical substances and vital processes occurring in live organisms.",
	"category_id": null,
	"id": null,
	"topic_id": null
}, {
	"sub_cat_id": null,
	"answer": "Genetics",
	"question": "________ is the study of the effect of genetic differences on organisms.",
	"category_id": null,
	"id": null,
	"topic_id": null
}, {
	"sub_cat_id": null,
	"answer": "Genetic interactions (epistasis)",
	"question": "________________________________ can often confound simple interpretations of such \"knockout\" studies.",
	"category_id": null,
	"id": null,
	"topic_id": null
}, {
	"sub_cat_id": null,
	"answer": "Molecular biology",
	"question": "_________________ is the study of molecular underpinnings of the processes of replication, transcription, translation, and cell function.",
	"category_id": null,
	"id": null,
	"topic_id": null
}, {
	"sub_cat_id": null,
	"answer": "genetic material",
	"question": "The central dogma of molecular biology where ________________ is transcribed into RNA and then translated into protein, despite being an oversimplified picture of molecular biology, still provides a good starting point for understanding the field.",
	"category_id": null,
	"id": null,
	"topic_id": null
}, {
	"sub_cat_id": null,
	"answer": "This picture",
	"question": "____________, however, is undergoing revision in light of emerging novel roles for RNA.",
	"category_id": null,
	"id": null,
	"topic_id": null
}, {
	"sub_cat_id": null,
	"answer": "revision",
	"question": "This picture, however, is undergoing ________ in light of emerging novel roles for RNA.",
	"category_id": null,
	"id": null,
	"topic_id": null
}, {
	"sub_cat_id": null,
	"answer": "recently much work",
	"question": "Much of the work in molecular biology is quantitative, and __________________ has been done at the interface of molecular biology and computer science in bioinformatics and computational biology.",
	"category_id": null,
	"id": null,
	"topic_id": null
}, {
	"sub_cat_id": null,
	"answer": "molecular biologists",
	"question": "Since the late 1950s and early 1960s, ____________________ have learned to characterize, isolate, and manipulate the molecular components of cells and organisms.",
	"category_id": null,
	"id": null,
	"topic_id": null
}, {
	"sub_cat_id": null,
	"answer": "molecular biology",
	"question": "One of the most basic techniques of _________________ to study protein function is molecular cloning.",
	"category_id": null,
	"id": null,
	"topic_id": null
}, {
	"sub_cat_id": null,
	"answer": "a plasmid",
	"question": "In this technique, DNA coding for a protein of interest is cloned (using PCR and/or restriction enzymes) into _________ (known as an expression vector).",
	"category_id": null,
	"id": null,
	"topic_id": null
}, {
	"sub_cat_id": null,
	"answer": "A vector",
	"question": "________ has 3 distinctive features: an origin of replication, a multiple cloning site (MCS), and a selective marker (usually antibiotic resistance).",
	"category_id": null,
	"id": null,
	"topic_id": null
}, {
	"sub_cat_id": null,
	"answer": "This plasmid",
	"question": "____________ can be inserted into either bacterial or animal cells.",
	"category_id": null,
	"id": null,
	"topic_id": null
}, {
	"sub_cat_id": null,
	"answer": "by transformation",
	"question": "Introducing DNA into bacterial cells can be done _________________ (via uptake of naked DNA), conjugation (via cell-cell contact) or by transduction (via viral vector).",
	"category_id": null,
	"id": null,
	"topic_id": null
}, {
	"sub_cat_id": null,
	"answer": "Electrical engineering",
	"question": "______________________ is a field of engineering that generally deals with the study and application of electricity, electronics, and electromagnetism.",
	"category_id": null,
	"id": null,
	"topic_id": null
}, {
	"sub_cat_id": null,
	"answer": "This field",
	"question": "__________ first became an identifiable occupation in the latter half of the 19th century after commercialization of the electric telegraph, the telephone, and electric power distribution and use.",
	"category_id": null,
	"id": null,
	"topic_id": null
}, {
	"sub_cat_id": null,
	"answer": "Electrical engineering",
	"question": "______________________ has now subdivided into a wide range of subfields including electronics, digital computers, power engineering, telecommunications, control systems, radio-frequency engineering, signal processing, instrumentation, and microelectronics.",
	"category_id": null,
	"id": null,
	"topic_id": null
}, {
	"sub_cat_id": null,
	"answer": "Electrical engineers",
	"question": "____________________ typically hold a degree in electrical engineering or electronic engineering.",
	"category_id": null,
	"id": null,
	"topic_id": null
}, {
	"sub_cat_id": null,
	"answer": "engineers",
	"question": "Practicing _________ may have professional certification and be members of a professional body.",
	"category_id": null,
	"id": null,
	"topic_id": null
}, {
	"sub_cat_id": null,
	"answer": "Practicing engineers",
	"question": "____________________ may have professional certification and be members of a professional body.",
	"category_id": null,
	"id": null,
	"topic_id": null
}, {
	"sub_cat_id": null,
	"answer": "Electricity",
	"question": "___________ has been a subject of scientific interest since at least the early 17th century.",
	"category_id": null,
	"id": null,
	"topic_id": null
}, {
	"sub_cat_id": null,
	"answer": "William Gilbert",
	"question": "The first electrical engineer was probably _______________ who designed the versorium: a device that detected the presence of statically charged objects.",
	"category_id": null,
	"id": null,
	"topic_id": null
}, {
	"sub_cat_id": null,
	"answer": "a device",
	"question": "The first electrical engineer was probably William Gilbert who designed the versorium: ________ that detected the presence of statically charged objects.",
	"category_id": null,
	"id": null,
	"topic_id": null
}, {
	"sub_cat_id": null,
	"answer": "1800 Volta",
	"question": "He was also the first to draw a clear distinction between magnetism and static electricity and is credited with establishing the term electricity.",
	"category_id": null,
	"id": null,
	"topic_id": null
}, {
	"sub_cat_id": null,
	"answer": "1800 Volta",
	"question": "Then in 1762 Swedish professor Johan Carl Wilcke invented, and in 1775 Alessandro Volta improved, a device (for which Volta coined the name electrophorus) that produced a static electric charge, and by __________ had developed the voltaic pile, a forerunner of the electric battery.",
	"category_id": null,
	"id": null,
	"topic_id": null
}, {
	"sub_cat_id": null,
	"answer": "James Clerk Maxwell",
	"question": "Notable developments in this century include the work of Georg Ohm, who in 1827 quantified the relationship between the electric current and potential difference in a conductor, of Michael Faraday, the discoverer of electromagnetic induction in 1831, and of ___________________, who in 1873 published a unified theory of electricity and magnetism in his treatise Electricity and Magnetism.",
	"category_id": null,
	"id": null,
	"topic_id": null
}, {
	"sub_cat_id": null,
	"answer": "efforts",
	"question": "Beginning in the 1830s, _______ were made to apply electricity to practical use in the telegraph.",
	"category_id": null,
	"id": null,
	"topic_id": null
}, {
	"sub_cat_id": null,
	"answer": "electricity",
	"question": "Beginning in the 1830s, efforts were made to apply ___________ to practical use in the telegraph.",
	"category_id": null,
	"id": null,
	"topic_id": null
}, {
	"sub_cat_id": null,
	"answer": "the world",
	"question": "By the end of the 19th century, _________ had been forever changed by the rapid communication made possible by the engineering development of land-lines, submarine cables, and, from about 1890, wireless telegraphy.",
	"category_id": null,
	"id": null,
	"topic_id": null
}, {
	"sub_cat_id": null,
	"answer": "the definitions",
	"question": "This was achieved at an international conference in Chicago in 1893.",
	"category_id": null,
	"id": null,
	"topic_id": null
}, {
	"sub_cat_id": null,
	"answer": "the definitions",
	"question": "The publication of these standards formed the basis of future advances in standardisation in various industries, and in many countries _______________ were immediately recognised in relevant legislation.",
	"category_id": null,
	"id": null,
	"topic_id": null
}, {
	"sub_cat_id": null,
	"answer": "early electrical technology",
	"question": "That's because ___________________________ was electromechanical in nature.",
	"category_id": null,
	"id": null,
	"topic_id": null
}, {
	"sub_cat_id": null,
	"answer": "Thomas Edison",
	"question": "In 1882, _____________ switched on the world's first large-scale electric power network that provided 110 volts \u2014 direct current (DC) \u2014 to 59 customers on Manhattan Island in New York City.",
	"category_id": null,
	"id": null,
	"topic_id": null
}, {
	"sub_cat_id": null,
	"answer": "Sir Charles Parsons",
	"question": "In 1884, ___________________ invented the steam turbine allowing for more efficient electric power generation.",
	"category_id": null,
	"id": null,
	"topic_id": null
}, {
	"sub_cat_id": null,
	"answer": "invisible airborne waves",
	"question": "The mathematical work of James Clerk Maxwell during the 1850s had shown the relationship of different forms of electromagnetic radiation including possibility of ________________________ (later called \"radio waves\").",
	"category_id": null,
	"id": null,
	"topic_id": null
}, {
	"sub_cat_id": null,
	"answer": "physical systems",
	"question": "Statics is the branch of mechanics that is concerned with the analysis of loads (force and torque, or \"moment\") acting on ________________ that do not experience an acceleration (a=0), but rather, are in static equilibrium with their environment.",
	"category_id": null,
	"id": null,
	"topic_id": null
}, {
	"sub_cat_id": null,
	"answer": "the system",
	"question": "When in static equilibrium, the acceleration of __________ is zero and __________ is either at rest, or its center of mass moves at constant velocity.",
	"category_id": null,
	"id": null,
	"topic_id": null
}, {
	"sub_cat_id": null,
	"answer": "bold font",
	"question": "Where _________ indicates a vector that has magnitude and direction.",
	"category_id": null,
	"id": null,
	"topic_id": null
}, {
	"sub_cat_id": null,
	"answer": "a vector",
	"question": "Where bold font indicates ________ that has magnitude and direction.",
	"category_id": null,
	"id": null,
	"topic_id": null
}, {
	"sub_cat_id": null,
	"answer": "the forces",
	"question": "F is the total of __________ acting on the system, m is the mass of the system and a is the acceleration of the system.",
	"category_id": null,
	"id": null,
	"topic_id": null
}, {
	"sub_cat_id": null,
	"answer": "These two equations",
	"question": "___________________ together, can be applied to solve for as many as two loads (forces and moments) acting on the system.",
	"category_id": null,
	"id": null,
	"topic_id": null
}, {
	"sub_cat_id": null,
	"answer": "The net forces",
	"question": "______________ equaling zero is known as the first condition for equilibrium, and the net torque equaling zero is known as the second condition for equilibrium.",
	"category_id": null,
	"id": null,
	"topic_id": null
}, {
	"sub_cat_id": null,
	"answer": "the net torque",
	"question": "The net forces equaling zero is known as the first condition for equilibrium, and ______________ equaling zero is known as the second condition for equilibrium.",
	"category_id": null,
	"id": null,
	"topic_id": null
}, {
	"sub_cat_id": null,
	"answer": "A scalar",
	"question": "________ is a quantity which only has a magnitude, such as mass or temperature.",
	"category_id": null,
	"id": null,
	"topic_id": null
}, {
	"sub_cat_id": null,
	"answer": "A vector",
	"question": "________ has a magnitude and a direction.",
	"category_id": null,
	"id": null,
	"topic_id": null
}, {
	"sub_cat_id": null,
	"answer": "Vectors",
	"question": "_______ are added using the parallelogram law or the triangle law.",
	"category_id": null,
	"id": null,
	"topic_id": null
}, {
	"sub_cat_id": null,
	"answer": "Vectors",
	"question": "_______ contain components in orthogonal bases.",
	"category_id": null,
	"id": null,
	"topic_id": null
}, {
	"sub_cat_id": null,
	"answer": "A force",
	"question": "_______ is either a push or a pull.",
	"category_id": null,
	"id": null,
	"topic_id": null
}, {
	"sub_cat_id": null,
	"answer": "A force",
	"question": "_______ tends to move a body in the direction of its action.",
	"category_id": null,
	"id": null,
	"topic_id": null
}, {
	"sub_cat_id": null,
	"answer": "by its magnitude",
	"question": "The action of a force is characterized ________________, by the direction of its action, and by its point of application.",
	"category_id": null,
	"id": null,
	"topic_id": null
}, {
	"sub_cat_id": null,
	"answer": "force",
	"question": "Thus, _____ is a vector quantity, because its effect depends on the direction as well as on the magnitude of the action.",
	"category_id": null,
	"id": null,
	"topic_id": null
}, {
	"sub_cat_id": null,
	"answer": "its effect",
	"question": "Thus, force is a vector quantity, because __________ depends on the direction as well as on the magnitude of the action.",
	"category_id": null,
	"id": null,
	"topic_id": null
}, {
	"sub_cat_id": null,
	"answer": "Forces",
	"question": "______ are classified as either contact or body forces.",
	"category_id": null,
	"id": null,
	"topic_id": null
}, {
	"sub_cat_id": null,
	"answer": "A contact force",
	"question": "_______________ is produced by direct physical contact; an example is the force exerted on a body by a supporting surface.",
	"category_id": null,
	"id": null,
	"topic_id": null
}, {
	"sub_cat_id": null,
	"answer": "the force",
	"question": "A contact force is produced by direct physical contact; an example is _________ exerted on a body by a supporting surface.",
	"category_id": null,
	"id": null,
	"topic_id": null
}, {
	"sub_cat_id": null,
	"answer": "A body force",
	"question": "____________ is generated by virtue of the position of a body within a force field such as a gravitational, electric, or magnetic field and is independent of contact with any other body.",
	"category_id": null,
	"id": null,
	"topic_id": null
}, {
	"sub_cat_id": null,
	"answer": "a force",
	"question": "In addition to the tendency to move a body in the direction of its application, _______ can also tend to rotate a body about an axis.",
	"category_id": null,
	"id": null,
	"topic_id": null
}, {
	"sub_cat_id": null,
	"answer": "The axis",
	"question": "________ may be any line which neither intersects nor is parallel to the line of action of the force.",
	"category_id": null,
	"id": null,
	"topic_id": null
}, {
	"sub_cat_id": null,
	"answer": "This rotational tendency",
	"question": "________________________ is known as the moment (M) of the force.",
	"category_id": null,
	"id": null,
	"topic_id": null
}, {
	"sub_cat_id": null,
	"answer": "Moment",
	"question": "______ is also referred to as torque.",
	"category_id": null,
	"id": null,
	"topic_id": null
}, {
	"sub_cat_id": null,
	"answer": "This perpendicular distance",
	"question": "___________________________ is called the moment arm.",
	"category_id": null,
	"id": null,
	"topic_id": null
}, {
	"sub_cat_id": null,
	"answer": "structural\u2014which",
	"question": "It is concerned particularly with the forms of biological molecules and [.",
	"category_id": null,
	"id": null,
	"topic_id": null
}, {
	"sub_cat_id": null,
	"answer": "Biochemistry",
	"question": "____________ is the study of the chemical substances and vital processes occurring in live organisms.",
	"category_id": null,
	"id": null,
	"topic_id": null
}, {
	"sub_cat_id": null,
	"answer": "Genetics",
	"question": "________ is the study of the effect of genetic differences on organisms.",
	"category_id": null,
	"id": null,
	"topic_id": null
}, {
	"sub_cat_id": null,
	"answer": "Genetic interactions (epistasis)",
	"question": "________________________________ can often confound simple interpretations of such \"knockout\" studies.",
	"category_id": null,
	"id": null,
	"topic_id": null
}, {
	"sub_cat_id": null,
	"answer": "Molecular biology",
	"question": "_________________ is the study of molecular underpinnings of the processes of replication, transcription, translation, and cell function.",
	"category_id": null,
	"id": null,
	"topic_id": null
}, {
	"sub_cat_id": null,
	"answer": "genetic material",
	"question": "The central dogma of molecular biology where ________________ is transcribed into RNA and then translated into protein, despite being an oversimplified picture of molecular biology, still provides a good starting point for understanding the field.",
	"category_id": null,
	"id": null,
	"topic_id": null
}, {
	"sub_cat_id": null,
	"answer": "This picture",
	"question": "____________, however, is undergoing revision in light of emerging novel roles for RNA.",
	"category_id": null,
	"id": null,
	"topic_id": null
}, {
	"sub_cat_id": null,
	"answer": "revision",
	"question": "This picture, however, is undergoing ________ in light of emerging novel roles for RNA.",
	"category_id": null,
	"id": null,
	"topic_id": null
}, {
	"sub_cat_id": null,
	"answer": "recently much work",
	"question": "Much of the work in molecular biology is quantitative, and __________________ has been done at the interface of molecular biology and computer science in bioinformatics and computational biology.",
	"category_id": null,
	"id": null,
	"topic_id": null
}, {
	"sub_cat_id": null,
	"answer": "molecular biologists",
	"question": "Since the late 1950s and early 1960s, ____________________ have learned to characterize, isolate, and manipulate the molecular components of cells and organisms.",
	"category_id": null,
	"id": null,
	"topic_id": null
}, {
	"sub_cat_id": null,
	"answer": "molecular biology",
	"question": "One of the most basic techniques of _________________ to study protein function is molecular cloning.",
	"category_id": null,
	"id": null,
	"topic_id": null
}, {
	"sub_cat_id": null,
	"answer": "a plasmid",
	"question": "In this technique, DNA coding for a protein of interest is cloned (using PCR and/or restriction enzymes) into _________ (known as an expression vector).",
	"category_id": null,
	"id": null,
	"topic_id": null
}, {
	"sub_cat_id": null,
	"answer": "A vector",
	"question": "________ has 3 distinctive features: an origin of replication, a multiple cloning site (MCS), and a selective marker (usually antibiotic resistance).",
	"category_id": null,
	"id": null,
	"topic_id": null
}, {
	"sub_cat_id": null,
	"answer": "This plasmid",
	"question": "____________ can be inserted into either bacterial or animal cells.",
	"category_id": null,
	"id": null,
	"topic_id": null
}, {
	"sub_cat_id": null,
	"answer": "by transformation",
	"question": "Introducing DNA into bacterial cells can be done _________________ (via uptake of naked DNA), conjugation (via cell-cell contact) or by transduction (via viral vector).",
	"category_id": null,
	"id": null,
	"topic_id": null
}, {
	"sub_cat_id": null,
	"answer": "Electrical engineering",
	"question": "______________________ is a field of engineering that generally deals with the study and application of electricity, electronics, and electromagnetism.",
	"category_id": null,
	"id": null,
	"topic_id": null
}, {
	"sub_cat_id": null,
	"answer": "This field",
	"question": "__________ first became an identifiable occupation in the latter half of the 19th century after commercialization of the electric telegraph, the telephone, and electric power distribution and use.",
	"category_id": null,
	"id": null,
	"topic_id": null
}, {
	"sub_cat_id": null,
	"answer": "Electrical engineering",
	"question": "______________________ has now subdivided into a wide range of subfields including electronics, digital computers, power engineering, telecommunications, control systems, radio-frequency engineering, signal processing, instrumentation, and microelectronics.",
	"category_id": null,
	"id": null,
	"topic_id": null
}, {
	"sub_cat_id": null,
	"answer": "Electrical engineers",
	"question": "____________________ typically hold a degree in electrical engineering or electronic engineering.",
	"category_id": null,
	"id": null,
	"topic_id": null
}, {
	"sub_cat_id": null,
	"answer": "engineers",
	"question": "Practicing _________ may have professional certification and be members of a professional body.",
	"category_id": null,
	"id": null,
	"topic_id": null
}, {
	"sub_cat_id": null,
	"answer": "Practicing engineers",
	"question": "____________________ may have professional certification and be members of a professional body.",
	"category_id": null,
	"id": null,
	"topic_id": null
}, {
	"sub_cat_id": null,
	"answer": "Electricity",
	"question": "___________ has been a subject of scientific interest since at least the early 17th century.",
	"category_id": null,
	"id": null,
	"topic_id": null
}, {
	"sub_cat_id": null,
	"answer": "William Gilbert",
	"question": "The first electrical engineer was probably _______________ who designed the versorium: a device that detected the presence of statically charged objects.",
	"category_id": null,
	"id": null,
	"topic_id": null
}, {
	"sub_cat_id": null,
	"answer": "a device",
	"question": "The first electrical engineer was probably William Gilbert who designed the versorium: ________ that detected the presence of statically charged objects.",
	"category_id": null,
	"id": null,
	"topic_id": null
}, {
	"sub_cat_id": null,
	"answer": "1800 Volta",
	"question": "He was also the first to draw a clear distinction between magnetism and static electricity and is credited with establishing the term electricity.",
	"category_id": null,
	"id": null,
	"topic_id": null
}, {
	"sub_cat_id": null,
	"answer": "1800 Volta",
	"question": "Then in 1762 Swedish professor Johan Carl Wilcke invented, and in 1775 Alessandro Volta improved, a device (for which Volta coined the name electrophorus) that produced a static electric charge, and by __________ had developed the voltaic pile, a forerunner of the electric battery.",
	"category_id": null,
	"id": null,
	"topic_id": null
}, {
	"sub_cat_id": null,
	"answer": "James Clerk Maxwell",
	"question": "Notable developments in this century include the work of Georg Ohm, who in 1827 quantified the relationship between the electric current and potential difference in a conductor, of Michael Faraday, the discoverer of electromagnetic induction in 1831, and of ___________________, who in 1873 published a unified theory of electricity and magnetism in his treatise Electricity and Magnetism.",
	"category_id": null,
	"id": null,
	"topic_id": null
}, {
	"sub_cat_id": null,
	"answer": "efforts",
	"question": "Beginning in the 1830s, _______ were made to apply electricity to practical use in the telegraph.",
	"category_id": null,
	"id": null,
	"topic_id": null
}, {
	"sub_cat_id": null,
	"answer": "electricity",
	"question": "Beginning in the 1830s, efforts were made to apply ___________ to practical use in the telegraph.",
	"category_id": null,
	"id": null,
	"topic_id": null
}, {
	"sub_cat_id": null,
	"answer": "the world",
	"question": "By the end of the 19th century, _________ had been forever changed by the rapid communication made possible by the engineering development of land-lines, submarine cables, and, from about 1890, wireless telegraphy.",
	"category_id": null,
	"id": null,
	"topic_id": null
}, {
	"sub_cat_id": null,
	"answer": "the definitions",
	"question": "This was achieved at an international conference in Chicago in 1893.",
	"category_id": null,
	"id": null,
	"topic_id": null
}, {
	"sub_cat_id": null,
	"answer": "the definitions",
	"question": "The publication of these standards formed the basis of future advances in standardisation in various industries, and in many countries _______________ were immediately recognised in relevant legislation.",
	"category_id": null,
	"id": null,
	"topic_id": null
}, {
	"sub_cat_id": null,
	"answer": "early electrical technology",
	"question": "That's because ___________________________ was electromechanical in nature.",
	"category_id": null,
	"id": null,
	"topic_id": null
}, {
	"sub_cat_id": null,
	"answer": "Thomas Edison",
	"question": "In 1882, _____________ switched on the world's first large-scale electric power network that provided 110 volts \u2014 direct current (DC) \u2014 to 59 customers on Manhattan Island in New York City.",
	"category_id": null,
	"id": null,
	"topic_id": null
}, {
	"sub_cat_id": null,
	"answer": "Sir Charles Parsons",
	"question": "In 1884, ___________________ invented the steam turbine allowing for more efficient electric power generation.",
	"category_id": null,
	"id": null,
	"topic_id": null
}, {
	"sub_cat_id": null,
	"answer": "invisible airborne waves",
	"question": "The mathematical work of James Clerk Maxwell during the 1850s had shown the relationship of different forms of electromagnetic radiation including possibility of ________________________ (later called \"radio waves\").",
	"category_id": null,
	"id": null,
	"topic_id": null
}, {
	"sub_cat_id": null,
	"answer": "physical systems",
	"question": "Statics is the branch of mechanics that is concerned with the analysis of loads (force and torque, or \"moment\") acting on ________________ that do not experience an acceleration (a=0), but rather, are in static equilibrium with their environment.",
	"category_id": null,
	"id": null,
	"topic_id": null
}, {
	"sub_cat_id": null,
	"answer": "the system",
	"question": "When in static equilibrium, the acceleration of __________ is zero and __________ is either at rest, or its center of mass moves at constant velocity.",
	"category_id": null,
	"id": null,
	"topic_id": null
}, {
	"sub_cat_id": null,
	"answer": "bold font",
	"question": "Where _________ indicates a vector that has magnitude and direction.",
	"category_id": null,
	"id": null,
	"topic_id": null
}, {
	"sub_cat_id": null,
	"answer": "a vector",
	"question": "Where bold font indicates ________ that has magnitude and direction.",
	"category_id": null,
	"id": null,
	"topic_id": null
}, {
	"sub_cat_id": null,
	"answer": "the forces",
	"question": "F is the total of __________ acting on the system, m is the mass of the system and a is the acceleration of the system.",
	"category_id": null,
	"id": null,
	"topic_id": null
}, {
	"sub_cat_id": null,
	"answer": "These two equations",
	"question": "___________________ together, can be applied to solve for as many as two loads (forces and moments) acting on the system.",
	"category_id": null,
	"id": null,
	"topic_id": null
}, {
	"sub_cat_id": null,
	"answer": "The net forces",
	"question": "______________ equaling zero is known as the first condition for equilibrium, and the net torque equaling zero is known as the second condition for equilibrium.",
	"category_id": null,
	"id": null,
	"topic_id": null
}, {
	"sub_cat_id": null,
	"answer": "the net torque",
	"question": "The net forces equaling zero is known as the first condition for equilibrium, and ______________ equaling zero is known as the second condition for equilibrium.",
	"category_id": null,
	"id": null,
	"topic_id": null
}, {
	"sub_cat_id": null,
	"answer": "A scalar",
	"question": "________ is a quantity which only has a magnitude, such as mass or temperature.",
	"category_id": null,
	"id": null,
	"topic_id": null
}, {
	"sub_cat_id": null,
	"answer": "A vector",
	"question": "________ has a magnitude and a direction.",
	"category_id": null,
	"id": null,
	"topic_id": null
}, {
	"sub_cat_id": null,
	"answer": "Vectors",
	"question": "_______ are added using the parallelogram law or the triangle law.",
	"category_id": null,
	"id": null,
	"topic_id": null
}, {
	"sub_cat_id": null,
	"answer": "Vectors",
	"question": "_______ contain components in orthogonal bases.",
	"category_id": null,
	"id": null,
	"topic_id": null
}, {
	"sub_cat_id": null,
	"answer": "A force",
	"question": "_______ is either a push or a pull.",
	"category_id": null,
	"id": null,
	"topic_id": null
}, {
	"sub_cat_id": null,
	"answer": "A force",
	"question": "_______ tends to move a body in the direction of its action.",
	"category_id": null,
	"id": null,
	"topic_id": null
}, {
	"sub_cat_id": null,
	"answer": "by its magnitude",
	"question": "The action of a force is characterized ________________, by the direction of its action, and by its point of application.",
	"category_id": null,
	"id": null,
	"topic_id": null
}, {
	"sub_cat_id": null,
	"answer": "force",
	"question": "Thus, _____ is a vector quantity, because its effect depends on the direction as well as on the magnitude of the action.",
	"category_id": null,
	"id": null,
	"topic_id": null
}, {
	"sub_cat_id": null,
	"answer": "its effect",
	"question": "Thus, force is a vector quantity, because __________ depends on the direction as well as on the magnitude of the action.",
	"category_id": null,
	"id": null,
	"topic_id": null
}, {
	"sub_cat_id": null,
	"answer": "Forces",
	"question": "______ are classified as either contact or body forces.",
	"category_id": null,
	"id": null,
	"topic_id": null
}, {
	"sub_cat_id": null,
	"answer": "A contact force",
	"question": "_______________ is produced by direct physical contact; an example is the force exerted on a body by a supporting surface.",
	"category_id": null,
	"id": null,
	"topic_id": null
}, {
	"sub_cat_id": null,
	"answer": "the force",
	"question": "A contact force is produced by direct physical contact; an example is _________ exerted on a body by a supporting surface.",
	"category_id": null,
	"id": null,
	"topic_id": null
}, {
	"sub_cat_id": null,
	"answer": "A body force",
	"question": "____________ is generated by virtue of the position of a body within a force field such as a gravitational, electric, or magnetic field and is independent of contact with any other body.",
	"category_id": null,
	"id": null,
	"topic_id": null
}, {
	"sub_cat_id": null,
	"answer": "a force",
	"question": "In addition to the tendency to move a body in the direction of its application, _______ can also tend to rotate a body about an axis.",
	"category_id": null,
	"id": null,
	"topic_id": null
}, {
	"sub_cat_id": null,
	"answer": "The axis",
	"question": "________ may be any line which neither intersects nor is parallel to the line of action of the force.",
	"category_id": null,
	"id": null,
	"topic_id": null
}, {
	"sub_cat_id": null,
	"answer": "This rotational tendency",
	"question": "________________________ is known as the moment (M) of the force.",
	"category_id": null,
	"id": null,
	"topic_id": null
}, {
	"sub_cat_id": null,
	"answer": "Moment",
	"question": "______ is also referred to as torque.",
	"category_id": null,
	"id": null,
	"topic_id": null
}, {
	"sub_cat_id": null,
	"answer": "This perpendicular distance",
	"question": "___________________________ is called the moment arm.",
	"category_id": null,
	"id": null,
	"topic_id": null
}, {
	"sub_cat_id": null,
	"answer": "General relativity (GR",
	"question": "______________________, also known as the general theory of relativity or GTR) is the geometric theory of gravitation published by Albert Einstein in 1915[2] and the current description of gravitation in modern physics.",
	"category_id": null,
	"id": null,
	"topic_id": null
}, {
	"sub_cat_id": null,
	"answer": "by Albert Einstein",
	"question": "General relativity (GR, also known as the general theory of relativity or GTR) is the geometric theory of gravitation published __________________ in 1915[2] and the current description of gravitation in modern physics.",
	"category_id": null,
	"id": null,
	"topic_id": null
}, {
	"sub_cat_id": null,
	"answer": "General relativity",
	"question": "__________________ generalizes special relativity and Newton's law of universal gravitation, providing a unified description of gravity as a geometric property of space and time, or spacetime.",
	"category_id": null,
	"id": null,
	"topic_id": null
}, {
	"sub_cat_id": null,
	"answer": "The relation",
	"question": "____________ is specified by the Einstein field equations, a system of partial differential equations.",
	"category_id": null,
	"id": null,
	"topic_id": null
}, {
	"sub_cat_id": null,
	"answer": "gravitational time dilation",
	"question": "Examples of such differences include ___________________________, gravitational lensing, the gravitational redshift of light, and the gravitational time delay.",
	"category_id": null,
	"id": null,
	"topic_id": null
}, {
	"sub_cat_id": null,
	"answer": "general relativity",
	"question": "Although __________________ is not the only relativistic theory of gravity, it is the simplest theory that is consistent with experimental data.",
	"category_id": null,
	"id": null,
	"topic_id": null
}, {
	"sub_cat_id": null,
	"answer": "the simplest theory",
	"question": "Although general relativity is not the only relativistic theory of gravity, it is ___________________ that is consistent with experimental data.",
	"category_id": null,
	"id": null,
	"topic_id": null
}, {
	"sub_cat_id": null,
	"answer": "general relativity",
	"question": "However, unanswered questions remain, the most fundamental being how __________________ can be reconciled with the laws of quantum physics to produce a complete and self-consistent theory of quantum gravity.",
	"category_id": null,
	"id": null,
	"topic_id": null
}, {
	"sub_cat_id": null,
	"answer": "Einstein's theory",
	"question": "_________________ has important astrophysical implications.",
	"category_id": null,
	"id": null,
	"topic_id": null
}, {
	"sub_cat_id": null,
	"answer": "General relativity",
	"question": "__________________ also predicts the existence of gravitational waves, which have since been observed directly by physics collaboration LIGO.",
	"category_id": null,
	"id": null,
	"topic_id": null
}, {
	"sub_cat_id": null,
	"answer": "general relativity",
	"question": "In addition, __________________ is the basis of current cosmological models of a consistently expanding universe.",
	"category_id": null,
	"id": null,
	"topic_id": null
}, {
	"sub_cat_id": null,
	"answer": "Einstein",
	"question": "Soon after publishing the special theory of relativity in 1905, ________ started thinking about how to incorporate gravity into his new relativistic framework.",
	"category_id": null,
	"id": null,
	"topic_id": null
}, {
	"sub_cat_id": null,
	"answer": "his work",
	"question": "After numerous detours and false starts, ________ culminated in the presentation to the Prussian Academy of Science in November 1915 of what are now known as the Einstein field equations.",
	"category_id": null,
	"id": null,
	"topic_id": null
}, {
	"sub_cat_id": null,
	"answer": "These equations",
	"question": "_______________ specify how the geometry of space and time is influenced by whatever matter and radiation are present, and form the core of Einstein's general theory of relativity.",
	"category_id": null,
	"id": null,
	"topic_id": null
}, {
	"sub_cat_id": null,
	"answer": "Einstein",
	"question": "________ used approximation methods in working out initial predictions of the theory.",
	"category_id": null,
	"id": null,
	"topic_id": null
}, {
	"sub_cat_id": null,
	"answer": "This solution",
	"question": "_____________ laid the groundwork for the description of the final stages of gravitational collapse, and the objects known today as black holes.",
	"category_id": null,
	"id": null,
	"topic_id": null
}, {
	"sub_cat_id": null,
	"answer": "the objects",
	"question": "This solution laid the groundwork for the description of the final stages of gravitational collapse, and ___________ known today as black holes.",
	"category_id": null,
	"id": null,
	"topic_id": null
}, {
	"sub_cat_id": null,
	"answer": "Schwarzschild",
	"question": "In the same year, the first steps towards generalizing _____________'s solution to electrically charged objects were taken, which eventually resulted in the Reissner\u2013Nordstr\u00f6m solution, now associated with electrically charged black holes.",
	"category_id": null,
	"id": null,
	"topic_id": null
}, {
	"sub_cat_id": null,
	"answer": "Schwarzschild",
	"question": "In 1917, Einstein applied his theory to the universe as a whole, initiating the field of relativistic cosmology.",
	"category_id": null,
	"id": null,
	"topic_id": null
}, {
	"sub_cat_id": null,
	"answer": "electrically charged objects",
	"question": "In the same year, the first steps towards generalizing Schwarzschild's solution to ____________________________ were taken, which eventually resulted in the Reissner\u2013Nordstr\u00f6m solution, now associated with electrically charged black holes.",
	"category_id": null,
	"id": null,
	"topic_id": null
}, {
	"sub_cat_id": null,
	"answer": "Einstein",
	"question": "In the same year, the first steps towards generalizing Schwarzschild's solution to electrically charged objects were taken, which eventually resulted in the Reissner\u2013Nordstr\u00f6m solution, now associated with electrically charged black holes.",
	"category_id": null,
	"id": null,
	"topic_id": null
}, {
	"sub_cat_id": null,
	"answer": "Einstein",
	"question": "In 1917, ________ applied his theory to the universe as a whole, initiating the field of relativistic cosmology.",
	"category_id": null,
	"id": null,
	"topic_id": null
}, {
	"sub_cat_id": null,
	"answer": "by Friedmann",
	"question": "This is readily described by the expanding cosmological solutions found ____________ in 1922, which do not require a cosmological constant.",
	"category_id": null,
	"id": null,
	"topic_id": null
}, {
	"sub_cat_id": null,
	"answer": "Lema\u00eetre",
	"question": "________ used these solutions to formulate the earliest version of the Big Bang models, in which our universe has evolved from an extremely hot and dense earlier state.",
	"category_id": null,
	"id": null,
	"topic_id": null
}, {
	"sub_cat_id": null,
	"answer": "Lema\u00eetre",
	"question": "Einstein later declared the cosmological constant the biggest blunder of his life.",
	"category_id": null,
	"id": null,
	"topic_id": null
}, {
	"answer": "The moraine",
	"topic_id": null,
	"sub_cat_id": null,
	"question": "___________ is the high bank of debris in the top left hand quarter of the picture.",
	"category_id": null,
	"id": null
}, {
	"answer": "study of ice\")",
	"topic_id": null,
	"sub_cat_id": null,
	"question": "Glaciology (from Latin: glacies, \"frost, ice\", and Ancient Greek: \u03bb\u03cc\u03b3\u03bf\u03c2, logos, \"subject matter\"; literally \"______________ is the scientific study of glaciers, or more generally ice and natural phenomena that involve ice.",
	"category_id": null,
	"id": null
}, {
	"answer": "A glaciologist",
	"topic_id": null,
	"sub_cat_id": null,
	"question": "______________ is a person who studies glaciers.",
	"category_id": null,
	"id": null
}, {
	"answer": "a person",
	"topic_id": null,
	"sub_cat_id": null,
	"question": "A glaciologist is ________ who studies glaciers.",
	"category_id": null,
	"id": null
}, {
	"answer": "Glaciology",
	"topic_id": null,
	"sub_cat_id": null,
	"question": "__________ is one of the key areas of polar research.",
	"category_id": null,
	"id": null
}, {
	"answer": "A glacier",
	"topic_id": null,
	"sub_cat_id": null,
	"question": "_________ is an extended mass of ice formed from snow falling and accumulating over a long period of time; they move very slowly, either descending from high mountains, as in valley glaciers, or moving outward from centers of accumulation, as in continental glaciers.",
	"category_id": null,
	"id": null
}, {
	"answer": "Alpine glaciers",
	"topic_id": null,
	"sub_cat_id": null,
	"question": "_______________ tend to make the topography more rugged, by adding and improving the scale of existing features such as large ravines called cirques and ridges where the rims of two cirques meet called ar\u00eates.",
	"category_id": null,
	"id": null
}, {
	"answer": "an ice sheet",
	"topic_id": null,
	"sub_cat_id": null,
	"question": "Continental - ____________ found today, only in high latitudes (Greenland/Antarctica), thousands of square kilometers in area and thousands of meters thick.",
	"category_id": null,
	"id": null
}, {
	"answer": "These",
	"topic_id": null,
	"sub_cat_id": null,
	"question": "_____ tend to smooth out the landscapes.",
	"category_id": null,
	"id": null
}, {
	"answer": "Wastage or Ablation",
	"topic_id": null,
	"sub_cat_id": null,
	"question": "___________________, where the sum of melting and evaporation (sublimation) is greater than the amount of snow added each year.",
	"category_id": null,
	"id": null
}, {
	"answer": "The tunnel valley",
	"topic_id": null,
	"sub_cat_id": null,
	"question": "_________________ is what remains of it in the underlying rock when the ice sheet has melted.",
	"category_id": null,
	"id": null
}, {
	"answer": "Summer conditions",
	"topic_id": null,
	"sub_cat_id": null,
	"question": "_________________ deposit more and coarser material and those of the winter, less and finer.",
	"category_id": null,
	"id": null
}, {
	"answer": "Terminal) material",
	"topic_id": null,
	"sub_cat_id": null,
	"question": "__________________ deposited at the end; (Ground) material deposited as glacier melts; (lateral) material deposited along the sides.",
	"category_id": null,
	"id": null
}, {
	"answer": "Ground) material",
	"topic_id": null,
	"sub_cat_id": null,
	"question": "Terminal) material deposited at the end; (________________ deposited as glacier melts; (lateral) material deposited along the sides.",
	"category_id": null,
	"id": null
}, {
	"answer": "lateral) material",
	"topic_id": null,
	"sub_cat_id": null,
	"question": "Terminal) material deposited at the end; (Ground) material deposited as glacier melts; (_________________ deposited along the sides.",
	"category_id": null,
	"id": null
}, {
	"answer": "The moraine",
	"topic_id": null,
	"sub_cat_id": null,
	"question": "___________ is the high bank of debris in the top left hand quarter of the picture.",
	"category_id": null,
	"id": null
}, {
	"answer": "study of ice\")",
	"topic_id": null,
	"sub_cat_id": null,
	"question": "Glaciology (from Latin: glacies, \"frost, ice\", and Ancient Greek: \u03bb\u03cc\u03b3\u03bf\u03c2, logos, \"subject matter\"; literally \"______________ is the scientific study of glaciers, or more generally ice and natural phenomena that involve ice.",
	"category_id": null,
	"id": null
}, {
	"answer": "A glaciologist",
	"topic_id": null,
	"sub_cat_id": null,
	"question": "______________ is a person who studies glaciers.",
	"category_id": null,
	"id": null
}, {
	"answer": "a person",
	"topic_id": null,
	"sub_cat_id": null,
	"question": "A glaciologist is ________ who studies glaciers.",
	"category_id": null,
	"id": null
}, {
	"answer": "Glaciology",
	"topic_id": null,
	"sub_cat_id": null,
	"question": "__________ is one of the key areas of polar research.",
	"category_id": null,
	"id": null
}, {
	"answer": "A glacier",
	"topic_id": null,
	"sub_cat_id": null,
	"question": "_________ is an extended mass of ice formed from snow falling and accumulating over a long period of time; they move very slowly, either descending from high mountains, as in valley glaciers, or moving outward from centers of accumulation, as in continental glaciers.",
	"category_id": null,
	"id": null
}, {
	"answer": "Alpine glaciers",
	"topic_id": null,
	"sub_cat_id": null,
	"question": "_______________ tend to make the topography more rugged, by adding and improving the scale of existing features such as large ravines called cirques and ridges where the rims of two cirques meet called ar\u00eates.",
	"category_id": null,
	"id": null
}, {
	"answer": "an ice sheet",
	"topic_id": null,
	"sub_cat_id": null,
	"question": "Continental - ____________ found today, only in high latitudes (Greenland/Antarctica), thousands of square kilometers in area and thousands of meters thick.",
	"category_id": null,
	"id": null
}, {
	"answer": "These",
	"topic_id": null,
	"sub_cat_id": null,
	"question": "_____ tend to smooth out the landscapes.",
	"category_id": null,
	"id": null
}, {
	"answer": "Wastage or Ablation",
	"topic_id": null,
	"sub_cat_id": null,
	"question": "___________________, where the sum of melting and evaporation (sublimation) is greater than the amount of snow added each year.",
	"category_id": null,
	"id": null
}, {
	"answer": "The tunnel valley",
	"topic_id": null,
	"sub_cat_id": null,
	"question": "_________________ is what remains of it in the underlying rock when the ice sheet has melted.",
	"category_id": null,
	"id": null
}, {
	"answer": "Summer conditions",
	"topic_id": null,
	"sub_cat_id": null,
	"question": "_________________ deposit more and coarser material and those of the winter, less and finer.",
	"category_id": null,
	"id": null
}, {
	"answer": "Terminal) material",
	"topic_id": null,
	"sub_cat_id": null,
	"question": "__________________ deposited at the end; (Ground) material deposited as glacier melts; (lateral) material deposited along the sides.",
	"category_id": null,
	"id": null
}, {
	"answer": "Ground) material",
	"topic_id": null,
	"sub_cat_id": null,
	"question": "Terminal) material deposited at the end; (________________ deposited as glacier melts; (lateral) material deposited along the sides.",
	"category_id": null,
	"id": null
}, {
	"answer": "lateral) material",
	"topic_id": null,
	"sub_cat_id": null,
	"question": "Terminal) material deposited at the end; (Ground) material deposited as glacier melts; (_________________ deposited along the sides.",
	"category_id": null,
	"id": null
}, {
	"answer": "Metrology",
	"topic_id": null,
	"sub_cat_id": null,
	"question": "_________ is the science of measurement.",
	"category_id": null,
	"id": null
}, {
	"answer": "Metrology",
	"topic_id": null,
	"sub_cat_id": null,
	"question": "_________ is defined by the International Bureau of Weights and Measures (BIPM) as \"the science of measurement, embracing both experimental and theoretical determinations at any level of uncertainty in any field of science and technology.",
	"category_id": null,
	"id": null
}, {
	"answer": "Metrology",
	"topic_id": null,
	"sub_cat_id": null,
	"question": "The ontology and international vocabulary of metrology (VIM) is maintained by the Joint Committee for Guides in _________ (JCGM), a group made up of eight international organisations \u2013 BIPM, IEC, IFCC, ISO, IUPAC, IUPAP, OIML and ILAC.",
	"category_id": null,
	"id": null
}, {
	"answer": "The BIPM",
	"topic_id": null,
	"sub_cat_id": null,
	"question": "________ maintains a database of the metrological calibration and measurement capabilities of various institutes around the world.",
	"category_id": null,
	"id": null
}, {
	"answer": "the BIPM",
	"topic_id": null,
	"sub_cat_id": null,
	"question": "In the area of measurement ________ has identified nine metrology areas including length, mass and time.",
	"category_id": null,
	"id": null
}, {
	"answer": "length",
	"topic_id": null,
	"sub_cat_id": null,
	"question": "In the area of measurement the BIPM has identified nine metrology areas including ______, mass and time.",
	"category_id": null,
	"id": null
}, {
	"answer": "Legal metrology",
	"topic_id": null,
	"sub_cat_id": null,
	"question": "_______________ \"concerns activities which result from statutory requirements and concern measurement, units of measurement, measuring instruments and methods of measurement and which are performed by competent bodies.",
	"category_id": null,
	"id": null
}, {
	"answer": "Legal metrology",
	"topic_id": null,
	"sub_cat_id": null,
	"question": "Such statutory requirements might arise from, amongst others, the needs for protection of health, public safety, the environment, enabling taxation, protection of consumers and fair trade.",
	"category_id": null,
	"id": null
}, {
	"answer": "The OIML",
	"topic_id": null,
	"sub_cat_id": null,
	"question": "________ was set up to assist in harmonising such regulations across national boundaries to ensure that legal requirements do not inhibit trade.",
	"category_id": null,
	"id": null
}, {
	"answer": "legal requirements",
	"topic_id": null,
	"sub_cat_id": null,
	"question": "The OIML was set up to assist in harmonising such regulations across national boundaries to ensure that __________________ do not inhibit trade.",
	"category_id": null,
	"id": null
}, {
	"answer": "WELMEC",
	"topic_id": null,
	"sub_cat_id": null,
	"question": "In Europe ______ was established to promote cooperation on the field of legal metrology.",
	"category_id": null,
	"id": null
}, {
	"answer": "cooperation",
	"topic_id": null,
	"sub_cat_id": null,
	"question": "In Europe WELMEC was established to promote ___________ on the field of legal metrology.",
	"category_id": null,
	"id": null
}, {
	"answer": "the result",
	"topic_id": null,
	"sub_cat_id": null,
	"question": "A core concept in metrology is metrological traceability,[7] defined by the Joint Committee for Guides in Metrology as \"property of a measurement result whereby __________ can be related to a reference through a documented unbroken chain of calibrations, each contributing to the measurement uncertainty\".",
	"category_id": null,
	"id": null
}, {
	"answer": "the result",
	"topic_id": null,
	"sub_cat_id": null,
	"question": "Metrological traceability permits comparison of measurements, whether __________ is compared to the previous result in the same laboratory, a measurement result a year ago, or to __________ of a measurement performed anywhere else in the world.",
	"category_id": null,
	"id": null
}, {
	"answer": "Metrological traceability",
	"topic_id": null,
	"sub_cat_id": null,
	"question": "A core concept in metrology is metrological traceability,[7] defined by the Joint Committee for Guides in Metrology as \"property of a measurement result whereby the result can be related to a reference through a documented unbroken chain of calibrations, each contributing to the measurement uncertainty\".",
	"category_id": null,
	"id": null
}, {
	"answer": "Metrological traceability",
	"topic_id": null,
	"sub_cat_id": null,
	"question": "_________________________ permits comparison of measurements, whether the result is compared to the previous result in the same laboratory, a measurement result a year ago, or to the result of a measurement performed anywhere else in the world.",
	"category_id": null,
	"id": null
}, {
	"answer": "a measurement",
	"topic_id": null,
	"sub_cat_id": null,
	"question": "A core concept in metrology is metrological traceability,[7] defined by the Joint Committee for Guides in Metrology as \"property of _____________ result whereby the result can be related to a reference through a documented unbroken chain of calibrations, each contributing to the measurement uncertainty\".",
	"category_id": null,
	"id": null
}, {
	"answer": "a measurement",
	"topic_id": null,
	"sub_cat_id": null,
	"question": "Metrological traceability permits comparison of measurements, whether the result is compared to the previous result in the same laboratory, _____________ result a year ago, or to the result of _____________ performed anywhere else in the world.",
	"category_id": null,
	"id": null
}, {
	"answer": "Traceability",
	"topic_id": null,
	"sub_cat_id": null,
	"question": "____________ is most often obtained by calibration, establishing the relation between the indication of a measuring instrument and the value of a measurement standard.",
	"category_id": null,
	"id": null
}, {
	"answer": "by calibration",
	"topic_id": null,
	"sub_cat_id": null,
	"question": "Traceability is most often obtained ______________, establishing the relation between the indication of a measuring instrument and the value of a measurement standard.",
	"category_id": null,
	"id": null
}, {
	"answer": "These standards",
	"topic_id": null,
	"sub_cat_id": null,
	"question": "_______________ are usually coordinated by national metrological institutes: National Institute of Standards and Technology; National Physical Laboratory, UK; Physikalisch-Technische Bundesanstalt; etc.",
	"category_id": null,
	"id": null
}, {
	"answer": "Sufficiently correct measurements",
	"topic_id": null,
	"sub_cat_id": null,
	"question": "_________________________________ are essential to commerce.",
	"category_id": null,
	"id": null
}, {
	"answer": "every ten people",
	"topic_id": null,
	"sub_cat_id": null,
	"question": "About nine out of ________________ working in metrology specialize in commercial measurement, most at the technician level.",
	"category_id": null,
	"id": null
}, {
	"answer": "Correct measurements",
	"topic_id": null,
	"sub_cat_id": null,
	"question": "____________________ are beneficial to manufacturing, but other methods are available and sometimes are more appropriate.",
	"category_id": null,
	"id": null
}, {
	"answer": "other methods",
	"topic_id": null,
	"sub_cat_id": null,
	"question": "Correct measurements are beneficial to manufacturing, but _____________ are available and sometimes are more appropriate.",
	"category_id": null,
	"id": null
}, {
	"answer": "Metrology",
	"topic_id": null,
	"sub_cat_id": null,
	"question": "_________ has thrived at the interface between science and manufacturing.",
	"category_id": null,
	"id": null
}, {
	"answer": "Metrology laboratories",
	"topic_id": null,
	"sub_cat_id": null,
	"question": "______________________ are places where both metrology and calibration work are performed.",
	"category_id": null,
	"id": null
}, {
	"answer": "Calibration laboratories",
	"topic_id": null,
	"sub_cat_id": null,
	"question": "________________________ generally specialize in calibration work only.",
	"category_id": null,
	"id": null
}, {
	"answer": "The moraine",
	"topic_id": null,
	"sub_cat_id": null,
	"question": "___________ is the high bank of debris in the top left hand quarter of the picture.",
	"category_id": null,
	"id": null
}, {
	"answer": "study of ice\")",
	"topic_id": null,
	"sub_cat_id": null,
	"question": "Glaciology (from Latin: glacies, \"frost, ice\", and Ancient Greek: \u03bb\u03cc\u03b3\u03bf\u03c2, logos, \"subject matter\"; literally \"______________ is the scientific study of glaciers, or more generally ice and natural phenomena that involve ice.",
	"category_id": null,
	"id": null
}, {
	"answer": "A glaciologist",
	"topic_id": null,
	"sub_cat_id": null,
	"question": "______________ is a person who studies glaciers.",
	"category_id": null,
	"id": null
}, {
	"answer": "a person",
	"topic_id": null,
	"sub_cat_id": null,
	"question": "A glaciologist is ________ who studies glaciers.",
	"category_id": null,
	"id": null
}, {
	"answer": "Glaciology",
	"topic_id": null,
	"sub_cat_id": null,
	"question": "__________ is one of the key areas of polar research.",
	"category_id": null,
	"id": null
}, {
	"answer": "A glacier",
	"topic_id": null,
	"sub_cat_id": null,
	"question": "_________ is an extended mass of ice formed from snow falling and accumulating over a long period of time; they move very slowly, either descending from high mountains, as in valley glaciers, or moving outward from centers of accumulation, as in continental glaciers.",
	"category_id": null,
	"id": null
}, {
	"answer": "Alpine glaciers",
	"topic_id": null,
	"sub_cat_id": null,
	"question": "_______________ tend to make the topography more rugged, by adding and improving the scale of existing features such as large ravines called cirques and ridges where the rims of two cirques meet called ar\u00eates.",
	"category_id": null,
	"id": null
}, {
	"answer": "an ice sheet",
	"topic_id": null,
	"sub_cat_id": null,
	"question": "Continental - ____________ found today, only in high latitudes (Greenland/Antarctica), thousands of square kilometers in area and thousands of meters thick.",
	"category_id": null,
	"id": null
}, {
	"answer": "These",
	"topic_id": null,
	"sub_cat_id": null,
	"question": "_____ tend to smooth out the landscapes.",
	"category_id": null,
	"id": null
}, {
	"answer": "Wastage or Ablation",
	"topic_id": null,
	"sub_cat_id": null,
	"question": "___________________, where the sum of melting and evaporation (sublimation) is greater than the amount of snow added each year.",
	"category_id": null,
	"id": null
}, {
	"answer": "The tunnel valley",
	"topic_id": null,
	"sub_cat_id": null,
	"question": "_________________ is what remains of it in the underlying rock when the ice sheet has melted.",
	"category_id": null,
	"id": null
}, {
	"answer": "Summer conditions",
	"topic_id": null,
	"sub_cat_id": null,
	"question": "_________________ deposit more and coarser material and those of the winter, less and finer.",
	"category_id": null,
	"id": null
}, {
	"answer": "Terminal) material",
	"topic_id": null,
	"sub_cat_id": null,
	"question": "__________________ deposited at the end; (Ground) material deposited as glacier melts; (lateral) material deposited along the sides.",
	"category_id": null,
	"id": null
}, {
	"answer": "Ground) material",
	"topic_id": null,
	"sub_cat_id": null,
	"question": "Terminal) material deposited at the end; (________________ deposited as glacier melts; (lateral) material deposited along the sides.",
	"category_id": null,
	"id": null
}, {
	"answer": "lateral) material",
	"topic_id": null,
	"sub_cat_id": null,
	"question": "Terminal) material deposited at the end; (Ground) material deposited as glacier melts; (_________________ deposited along the sides.",
	"category_id": null,
	"id": null
}, {
	"answer": "Metrology",
	"topic_id": null,
	"sub_cat_id": null,
	"question": "_________ is the science of measurement.",
	"category_id": null,
	"id": null
}, {
	"answer": "Metrology",
	"topic_id": null,
	"sub_cat_id": null,
	"question": "_________ is defined by the International Bureau of Weights and Measures (BIPM) as \"the science of measurement, embracing both experimental and theoretical determinations at any level of uncertainty in any field of science and technology.",
	"category_id": null,
	"id": null
}, {
	"answer": "Metrology",
	"topic_id": null,
	"sub_cat_id": null,
	"question": "The ontology and international vocabulary of metrology (VIM) is maintained by the Joint Committee for Guides in _________ (JCGM), a group made up of eight international organisations \u2013 BIPM, IEC, IFCC, ISO, IUPAC, IUPAP, OIML and ILAC.",
	"category_id": null,
	"id": null
}, {
	"answer": "The BIPM",
	"topic_id": null,
	"sub_cat_id": null,
	"question": "________ maintains a database of the metrological calibration and measurement capabilities of various institutes around the world.",
	"category_id": null,
	"id": null
}, {
	"answer": "the BIPM",
	"topic_id": null,
	"sub_cat_id": null,
	"question": "In the area of measurement ________ has identified nine metrology areas including length, mass and time.",
	"category_id": null,
	"id": null
}, {
	"answer": "length",
	"topic_id": null,
	"sub_cat_id": null,
	"question": "In the area of measurement the BIPM has identified nine metrology areas including ______, mass and time.",
	"category_id": null,
	"id": null
}, {
	"answer": "Legal metrology",
	"topic_id": null,
	"sub_cat_id": null,
	"question": "_______________ \"concerns activities which result from statutory requirements and concern measurement, units of measurement, measuring instruments and methods of measurement and which are performed by competent bodies.",
	"category_id": null,
	"id": null
}, {
	"answer": "Legal metrology",
	"topic_id": null,
	"sub_cat_id": null,
	"question": "Such statutory requirements might arise from, amongst others, the needs for protection of health, public safety, the environment, enabling taxation, protection of consumers and fair trade.",
	"category_id": null,
	"id": null
}, {
	"answer": "The OIML",
	"topic_id": null,
	"sub_cat_id": null,
	"question": "________ was set up to assist in harmonising such regulations across national boundaries to ensure that legal requirements do not inhibit trade.",
	"category_id": null,
	"id": null
}, {
	"answer": "legal requirements",
	"topic_id": null,
	"sub_cat_id": null,
	"question": "The OIML was set up to assist in harmonising such regulations across national boundaries to ensure that __________________ do not inhibit trade.",
	"category_id": null,
	"id": null
}, {
	"answer": "WELMEC",
	"topic_id": null,
	"sub_cat_id": null,
	"question": "In Europe ______ was established to promote cooperation on the field of legal metrology.",
	"category_id": null,
	"id": null
}, {
	"answer": "cooperation",
	"topic_id": null,
	"sub_cat_id": null,
	"question": "In Europe WELMEC was established to promote ___________ on the field of legal metrology.",
	"category_id": null,
	"id": null
}, {
	"answer": "the result",
	"topic_id": null,
	"sub_cat_id": null,
	"question": "A core concept in metrology is metrological traceability,[7] defined by the Joint Committee for Guides in Metrology as \"property of a measurement result whereby __________ can be related to a reference through a documented unbroken chain of calibrations, each contributing to the measurement uncertainty\".",
	"category_id": null,
	"id": null
}, {
	"answer": "the result",
	"topic_id": null,
	"sub_cat_id": null,
	"question": "Metrological traceability permits comparison of measurements, whether __________ is compared to the previous result in the same laboratory, a measurement result a year ago, or to __________ of a measurement performed anywhere else in the world.",
	"category_id": null,
	"id": null
}, {
	"answer": "Metrological traceability",
	"topic_id": null,
	"sub_cat_id": null,
	"question": "A core concept in metrology is metrological traceability,[7] defined by the Joint Committee for Guides in Metrology as \"property of a measurement result whereby the result can be related to a reference through a documented unbroken chain of calibrations, each contributing to the measurement uncertainty\".",
	"category_id": null,
	"id": null
}, {
	"answer": "Metrological traceability",
	"topic_id": null,
	"sub_cat_id": null,
	"question": "_________________________ permits comparison of measurements, whether the result is compared to the previous result in the same laboratory, a measurement result a year ago, or to the result of a measurement performed anywhere else in the world.",
	"category_id": null,
	"id": null
}, {
	"answer": "a measurement",
	"topic_id": null,
	"sub_cat_id": null,
	"question": "A core concept in metrology is metrological traceability,[7] defined by the Joint Committee for Guides in Metrology as \"property of _____________ result whereby the result can be related to a reference through a documented unbroken chain of calibrations, each contributing to the measurement uncertainty\".",
	"category_id": null,
	"id": null
}, {
	"answer": "a measurement",
	"topic_id": null,
	"sub_cat_id": null,
	"question": "Metrological traceability permits comparison of measurements, whether the result is compared to the previous result in the same laboratory, _____________ result a year ago, or to the result of _____________ performed anywhere else in the world.",
	"category_id": null,
	"id": null
}, {
	"answer": "Traceability",
	"topic_id": null,
	"sub_cat_id": null,
	"question": "____________ is most often obtained by calibration, establishing the relation between the indication of a measuring instrument and the value of a measurement standard.",
	"category_id": null,
	"id": null
}, {
	"answer": "by calibration",
	"topic_id": null,
	"sub_cat_id": null,
	"question": "Traceability is most often obtained ______________, establishing the relation between the indication of a measuring instrument and the value of a measurement standard.",
	"category_id": null,
	"id": null
}, {
	"answer": "These standards",
	"topic_id": null,
	"sub_cat_id": null,
	"question": "_______________ are usually coordinated by national metrological institutes: National Institute of Standards and Technology; National Physical Laboratory, UK; Physikalisch-Technische Bundesanstalt; etc.",
	"category_id": null,
	"id": null
}, {
	"answer": "Sufficiently correct measurements",
	"topic_id": null,
	"sub_cat_id": null,
	"question": "_________________________________ are essential to commerce.",
	"category_id": null,
	"id": null
}, {
	"answer": "every ten people",
	"topic_id": null,
	"sub_cat_id": null,
	"question": "About nine out of ________________ working in metrology specialize in commercial measurement, most at the technician level.",
	"category_id": null,
	"id": null
}, {
	"answer": "Correct measurements",
	"topic_id": null,
	"sub_cat_id": null,
	"question": "____________________ are beneficial to manufacturing, but other methods are available and sometimes are more appropriate.",
	"category_id": null,
	"id": null
}, {
	"answer": "other methods",
	"topic_id": null,
	"sub_cat_id": null,
	"question": "Correct measurements are beneficial to manufacturing, but _____________ are available and sometimes are more appropriate.",
	"category_id": null,
	"id": null
}, {
	"answer": "Metrology",
	"topic_id": null,
	"sub_cat_id": null,
	"question": "_________ has thrived at the interface between science and manufacturing.",
	"category_id": null,
	"id": null
}, {
	"answer": "Metrology laboratories",
	"topic_id": null,
	"sub_cat_id": null,
	"question": "______________________ are places where both metrology and calibration work are performed.",
	"category_id": null,
	"id": null
}, {
	"answer": "Calibration laboratories",
	"topic_id": null,
	"sub_cat_id": null,
	"question": "________________________ generally specialize in calibration work only.",
	"category_id": null,
	"id": null
}, {
	"answer": "The engineering field",
	"topic_id": null,
	"sub_cat_id": null,
	"question": "_____________________ requires an understanding of core concepts including mechanics, kinematics, thermodynamics, materials science, structural analysis, and electricity.",
	"category_id": null,
	"id": null
}, {
	"answer": "Mechanical engineers",
	"topic_id": null,
	"sub_cat_id": null,
	"question": "____________________ use these core principles along with tools like computer-aided design, and product lifecycle management to design and analyze manufacturing plants, industrial equipment and machinery, heating and cooling systems, transport systems, aircraft, watercraft, robotics, medical devices, weapons, and others.",
	"category_id": null,
	"id": null
}, {
	"answer": "Mechanical engineering",
	"topic_id": null,
	"sub_cat_id": null,
	"question": "______________________ emerged as a field during the industrial revolution in Europe in the 18th century; however, its development can be traced back several thousand years around the world.",
	"category_id": null,
	"id": null
}, {
	"answer": "its development",
	"topic_id": null,
	"sub_cat_id": null,
	"question": "Mechanical engineering emerged as a field during the industrial revolution in Europe in the 18th century; however, _______________ can be traced back several thousand years around the world.",
	"category_id": null,
	"id": null
}, {
	"answer": "Mechanical engineering science",
	"topic_id": null,
	"sub_cat_id": null,
	"question": "______________________________ emerged in the 19th century as a result of developments in the field of physics.",
	"category_id": null,
	"id": null
}, {
	"answer": "The field",
	"topic_id": null,
	"sub_cat_id": null,
	"question": "_________ has continually evolved to incorporate advancements in technology, and mechanical engineers today are pursuing developments in such fields as composites, mechatronics, and nanotechnology.",
	"category_id": null,
	"id": null
}, {
	"answer": "mechanical engineers today",
	"topic_id": null,
	"sub_cat_id": null,
	"question": "The field has continually evolved to incorporate advancements in technology, and __________________________ are pursuing developments in such fields as composites, mechatronics, and nanotechnology.",
	"category_id": null,
	"id": null
}, {
	"answer": "mechanical engineers",
	"topic_id": null,
	"sub_cat_id": null,
	"question": "The field has continually evolved to incorporate advancements in technology, and ____________________ today are pursuing developments in such fields as composites, mechatronics, and nanotechnology.",
	"category_id": null,
	"id": null
}, {
	"answer": "Mechanical engineers",
	"topic_id": null,
	"sub_cat_id": null,
	"question": "____________________ may also work in the field of biomedical engineering, specifically with biomechanics, transport phenomena, biomechatronics, bionanotechnology, and modeling of biological systems.",
	"category_id": null,
	"id": null
}, {
	"answer": "Mechanical engineering",
	"topic_id": null,
	"sub_cat_id": null,
	"question": "______________________ finds its application in the archives of various ancient and medieval societies throughout mankind.",
	"category_id": null,
	"id": null
}, {
	"answer": "any escapement",
	"topic_id": null,
	"sub_cat_id": null,
	"question": "The medieval Chinese horologist and engineer Su Song (1020\u20131101 AD) incorporated an escapement mechanism into his astronomical clock tower two centuries before ______________ can be found in clocks of medieval Europe, as well as the world's first known endless power-transmitting chain drive.",
	"category_id": null,
	"id": null
}, {
	"answer": "endless power-transmitting chain",
	"topic_id": null,
	"sub_cat_id": null,
	"question": "The medieval Chinese horologist and engineer Su Song (1020\u20131101 AD) incorporated an escapement mechanism into his astronomical clock tower two centuries before any escapement can be found in clocks of medieval Europe, as well as the world's first known ________________________________ drive.",
	"category_id": null,
	"id": null
}, {
	"answer": "the era",
	"topic_id": null,
	"sub_cat_id": null,
	"question": "During the years from 7th to 15th century, _______ called the Islamic Golden Age, there were remarkable contributions from Muslim inventors in the field of mechanical technology.",
	"category_id": null,
	"id": null
}, {
	"answer": "remarkable contributions",
	"topic_id": null,
	"sub_cat_id": null,
	"question": "During the years from 7th to 15th century, the era called the Islamic Golden Age, there were ________________________ from Muslim inventors in the field of mechanical technology.",
	"category_id": null,
	"id": null
}, {
	"answer": "Al-Jazari",
	"topic_id": null,
	"sub_cat_id": null,
	"question": "_________, who was one of them, wrote his famous Book of Knowledge of Ingenious Mechanical Devices in 1206, and presented many mechanical designs.",
	"category_id": null,
	"id": null
}, {
	"answer": "such mechanical devices",
	"topic_id": null,
	"sub_cat_id": null,
	"question": "He is also considered to be the inventor of _______________________ which now form the very basic of mechanisms, such as the crankshaft and camshaft.",
	"category_id": null,
	"id": null
}, {
	"answer": "Sir Isaac Newton",
	"topic_id": null,
	"sub_cat_id": null,
	"question": "Important breakthroughs in the foundations of mechanical engineering occurred in England during the 17th century when ________________ both formulated the three Newton's Laws of Motion and developed Calculus, the mathematical basis of physics.",
	"category_id": null,
	"id": null
}, {
	"answer": "Newton",
	"topic_id": null,
	"sub_cat_id": null,
	"question": "______ was reluctant to publish his methods and laws for years, but he was finally persuaded to do so by his colleagues, such as Sir Edmund Halley, much to the benefit of all mankind.",
	"category_id": null,
	"id": null
}, {
	"answer": "Gottfried Wilhelm Leibniz",
	"topic_id": null,
	"sub_cat_id": null,
	"question": "_________________________ is also credited with creating Calculus during the same time frame.",
	"category_id": null,
	"id": null
}, {
	"answer": "Calculus",
	"topic_id": null,
	"sub_cat_id": null,
	"question": "Gottfried Wilhelm Leibniz is also credited with creating ________ during the same time frame.",
	"category_id": null,
	"id": null
}, {
	"answer": "an engineering education",
	"topic_id": null,
	"sub_cat_id": null,
	"question": "In the United States, the American Society of Mechanical Engineers (ASME) was formed in 1880, becoming the third such professional engineering society, after the American Society of Civil Engineers (1852) and the American Institute of Mining Engineers (1871).",
	"category_id": null,
	"id": null
}, {
	"answer": "an engineering education",
	"topic_id": null,
	"sub_cat_id": null,
	"question": "The first schools in the United States to offer ________________________ were the United States Military Academy in 1817, an institution now known as Norwich University in 1819, and Rensselaer Polytechnic Institute in 1825.",
	"category_id": null,
	"id": null
}, {
	"answer": "an institution",
	"topic_id": null,
	"sub_cat_id": null,
	"question": "The first schools in the United States to offer an engineering education were the United States Military Academy in 1817, ______________ now known as Norwich University in 1819, and Rensselaer Polytechnic Institute in 1825.",
	"category_id": null,
	"id": null
}, {
	"answer": "The moraine",
	"topic_id": null,
	"sub_cat_id": null,
	"question": "___________ is the high bank of debris in the top left hand quarter of the picture.",
	"category_id": null,
	"id": null
}, {
	"answer": "study of ice\")",
	"topic_id": null,
	"sub_cat_id": null,
	"question": "Glaciology (from Latin: glacies, \"frost, ice\", and Ancient Greek: \u03bb\u03cc\u03b3\u03bf\u03c2, logos, \"subject matter\"; literally \"______________ is the scientific study of glaciers, or more generally ice and natural phenomena that involve ice.",
	"category_id": null,
	"id": null
}, {
	"answer": "A glaciologist",
	"topic_id": null,
	"sub_cat_id": null,
	"question": "______________ is a person who studies glaciers.",
	"category_id": null,
	"id": null
}, {
	"answer": "a person",
	"topic_id": null,
	"sub_cat_id": null,
	"question": "A glaciologist is ________ who studies glaciers.",
	"category_id": null,
	"id": null
}, {
	"answer": "Glaciology",
	"topic_id": null,
	"sub_cat_id": null,
	"question": "__________ is one of the key areas of polar research.",
	"category_id": null,
	"id": null
}, {
	"answer": "A glacier",
	"topic_id": null,
	"sub_cat_id": null,
	"question": "_________ is an extended mass of ice formed from snow falling and accumulating over a long period of time; they move very slowly, either descending from high mountains, as in valley glaciers, or moving outward from centers of accumulation, as in continental glaciers.",
	"category_id": null,
	"id": null
}, {
	"answer": "Alpine glaciers",
	"topic_id": null,
	"sub_cat_id": null,
	"question": "_______________ tend to make the topography more rugged, by adding and improving the scale of existing features such as large ravines called cirques and ridges where the rims of two cirques meet called ar\u00eates.",
	"category_id": null,
	"id": null
}, {
	"answer": "an ice sheet",
	"topic_id": null,
	"sub_cat_id": null,
	"question": "Continental - ____________ found today, only in high latitudes (Greenland/Antarctica), thousands of square kilometers in area and thousands of meters thick.",
	"category_id": null,
	"id": null
}, {
	"answer": "These",
	"topic_id": null,
	"sub_cat_id": null,
	"question": "_____ tend to smooth out the landscapes.",
	"category_id": null,
	"id": null
}, {
	"answer": "Wastage or Ablation",
	"topic_id": null,
	"sub_cat_id": null,
	"question": "___________________, where the sum of melting and evaporation (sublimation) is greater than the amount of snow added each year.",
	"category_id": null,
	"id": null
}, {
	"answer": "The tunnel valley",
	"topic_id": null,
	"sub_cat_id": null,
	"question": "_________________ is what remains of it in the underlying rock when the ice sheet has melted.",
	"category_id": null,
	"id": null
}, {
	"answer": "Summer conditions",
	"topic_id": null,
	"sub_cat_id": null,
	"question": "_________________ deposit more and coarser material and those of the winter, less and finer.",
	"category_id": null,
	"id": null
}, {
	"answer": "Terminal) material",
	"topic_id": null,
	"sub_cat_id": null,
	"question": "__________________ deposited at the end; (Ground) material deposited as glacier melts; (lateral) material deposited along the sides.",
	"category_id": null,
	"id": null
}, {
	"answer": "Ground) material",
	"topic_id": null,
	"sub_cat_id": null,
	"question": "Terminal) material deposited at the end; (________________ deposited as glacier melts; (lateral) material deposited along the sides.",
	"category_id": null,
	"id": null
}, {
	"answer": "lateral) material",
	"topic_id": null,
	"sub_cat_id": null,
	"question": "Terminal) material deposited at the end; (Ground) material deposited as glacier melts; (_________________ deposited along the sides.",
	"category_id": null,
	"id": null
}, {
	"answer": "Metrology",
	"topic_id": null,
	"sub_cat_id": null,
	"question": "_________ is the science of measurement.",
	"category_id": null,
	"id": null
}, {
	"answer": "Metrology",
	"topic_id": null,
	"sub_cat_id": null,
	"question": "_________ is defined by the International Bureau of Weights and Measures (BIPM) as \"the science of measurement, embracing both experimental and theoretical determinations at any level of uncertainty in any field of science and technology.",
	"category_id": null,
	"id": null
}, {
	"answer": "Metrology",
	"topic_id": null,
	"sub_cat_id": null,
	"question": "The ontology and international vocabulary of metrology (VIM) is maintained by the Joint Committee for Guides in _________ (JCGM), a group made up of eight international organisations \u2013 BIPM, IEC, IFCC, ISO, IUPAC, IUPAP, OIML and ILAC.",
	"category_id": null,
	"id": null
}, {
	"answer": "The BIPM",
	"topic_id": null,
	"sub_cat_id": null,
	"question": "________ maintains a database of the metrological calibration and measurement capabilities of various institutes around the world.",
	"category_id": null,
	"id": null
}, {
	"answer": "the BIPM",
	"topic_id": null,
	"sub_cat_id": null,
	"question": "In the area of measurement ________ has identified nine metrology areas including length, mass and time.",
	"category_id": null,
	"id": null
}, {
	"answer": "length",
	"topic_id": null,
	"sub_cat_id": null,
	"question": "In the area of measurement the BIPM has identified nine metrology areas including ______, mass and time.",
	"category_id": null,
	"id": null
}, {
	"answer": "Legal metrology",
	"topic_id": null,
	"sub_cat_id": null,
	"question": "_______________ \"concerns activities which result from statutory requirements and concern measurement, units of measurement, measuring instruments and methods of measurement and which are performed by competent bodies.",
	"category_id": null,
	"id": null
}, {
	"answer": "Legal metrology",
	"topic_id": null,
	"sub_cat_id": null,
	"question": "Such statutory requirements might arise from, amongst others, the needs for protection of health, public safety, the environment, enabling taxation, protection of consumers and fair trade.",
	"category_id": null,
	"id": null
}, {
	"answer": "The OIML",
	"topic_id": null,
	"sub_cat_id": null,
	"question": "________ was set up to assist in harmonising such regulations across national boundaries to ensure that legal requirements do not inhibit trade.",
	"category_id": null,
	"id": null
}, {
	"answer": "legal requirements",
	"topic_id": null,
	"sub_cat_id": null,
	"question": "The OIML was set up to assist in harmonising such regulations across national boundaries to ensure that __________________ do not inhibit trade.",
	"category_id": null,
	"id": null
}, {
	"answer": "WELMEC",
	"topic_id": null,
	"sub_cat_id": null,
	"question": "In Europe ______ was established to promote cooperation on the field of legal metrology.",
	"category_id": null,
	"id": null
}, {
	"answer": "cooperation",
	"topic_id": null,
	"sub_cat_id": null,
	"question": "In Europe WELMEC was established to promote ___________ on the field of legal metrology.",
	"category_id": null,
	"id": null
}, {
	"answer": "the result",
	"topic_id": null,
	"sub_cat_id": null,
	"question": "A core concept in metrology is metrological traceability,[7] defined by the Joint Committee for Guides in Metrology as \"property of a measurement result whereby __________ can be related to a reference through a documented unbroken chain of calibrations, each contributing to the measurement uncertainty\".",
	"category_id": null,
	"id": null
}, {
	"answer": "the result",
	"topic_id": null,
	"sub_cat_id": null,
	"question": "Metrological traceability permits comparison of measurements, whether __________ is compared to the previous result in the same laboratory, a measurement result a year ago, or to __________ of a measurement performed anywhere else in the world.",
	"category_id": null,
	"id": null
}, {
	"answer": "Metrological traceability",
	"topic_id": null,
	"sub_cat_id": null,
	"question": "A core concept in metrology is metrological traceability,[7] defined by the Joint Committee for Guides in Metrology as \"property of a measurement result whereby the result can be related to a reference through a documented unbroken chain of calibrations, each contributing to the measurement uncertainty\".",
	"category_id": null,
	"id": null
}, {
	"answer": "Metrological traceability",
	"topic_id": null,
	"sub_cat_id": null,
	"question": "_________________________ permits comparison of measurements, whether the result is compared to the previous result in the same laboratory, a measurement result a year ago, or to the result of a measurement performed anywhere else in the world.",
	"category_id": null,
	"id": null
}, {
	"answer": "a measurement",
	"topic_id": null,
	"sub_cat_id": null,
	"question": "A core concept in metrology is metrological traceability,[7] defined by the Joint Committee for Guides in Metrology as \"property of _____________ result whereby the result can be related to a reference through a documented unbroken chain of calibrations, each contributing to the measurement uncertainty\".",
	"category_id": null,
	"id": null
}, {
	"answer": "a measurement",
	"topic_id": null,
	"sub_cat_id": null,
	"question": "Metrological traceability permits comparison of measurements, whether the result is compared to the previous result in the same laboratory, _____________ result a year ago, or to the result of _____________ performed anywhere else in the world.",
	"category_id": null,
	"id": null
}, {
	"answer": "Traceability",
	"topic_id": null,
	"sub_cat_id": null,
	"question": "____________ is most often obtained by calibration, establishing the relation between the indication of a measuring instrument and the value of a measurement standard.",
	"category_id": null,
	"id": null
}, {
	"answer": "by calibration",
	"topic_id": null,
	"sub_cat_id": null,
	"question": "Traceability is most often obtained ______________, establishing the relation between the indication of a measuring instrument and the value of a measurement standard.",
	"category_id": null,
	"id": null
}, {
	"answer": "These standards",
	"topic_id": null,
	"sub_cat_id": null,
	"question": "_______________ are usually coordinated by national metrological institutes: National Institute of Standards and Technology; National Physical Laboratory, UK; Physikalisch-Technische Bundesanstalt; etc.",
	"category_id": null,
	"id": null
}, {
	"answer": "Sufficiently correct measurements",
	"topic_id": null,
	"sub_cat_id": null,
	"question": "_________________________________ are essential to commerce.",
	"category_id": null,
	"id": null
}, {
	"answer": "every ten people",
	"topic_id": null,
	"sub_cat_id": null,
	"question": "About nine out of ________________ working in metrology specialize in commercial measurement, most at the technician level.",
	"category_id": null,
	"id": null
}, {
	"answer": "Correct measurements",
	"topic_id": null,
	"sub_cat_id": null,
	"question": "____________________ are beneficial to manufacturing, but other methods are available and sometimes are more appropriate.",
	"category_id": null,
	"id": null
}, {
	"answer": "other methods",
	"topic_id": null,
	"sub_cat_id": null,
	"question": "Correct measurements are beneficial to manufacturing, but _____________ are available and sometimes are more appropriate.",
	"category_id": null,
	"id": null
}, {
	"answer": "Metrology",
	"topic_id": null,
	"sub_cat_id": null,
	"question": "_________ has thrived at the interface between science and manufacturing.",
	"category_id": null,
	"id": null
}, {
	"answer": "Metrology laboratories",
	"topic_id": null,
	"sub_cat_id": null,
	"question": "______________________ are places where both metrology and calibration work are performed.",
	"category_id": null,
	"id": null
}, {
	"answer": "Calibration laboratories",
	"topic_id": null,
	"sub_cat_id": null,
	"question": "________________________ generally specialize in calibration work only.",
	"category_id": null,
	"id": null
}, {
	"answer": "The engineering field",
	"topic_id": null,
	"sub_cat_id": null,
	"question": "_____________________ requires an understanding of core concepts including mechanics, kinematics, thermodynamics, materials science, structural analysis, and electricity.",
	"category_id": null,
	"id": null
}, {
	"answer": "Mechanical engineers",
	"topic_id": null,
	"sub_cat_id": null,
	"question": "____________________ use these core principles along with tools like computer-aided design, and product lifecycle management to design and analyze manufacturing plants, industrial equipment and machinery, heating and cooling systems, transport systems, aircraft, watercraft, robotics, medical devices, weapons, and others.",
	"category_id": null,
	"id": null
}, {
	"answer": "Mechanical engineering",
	"topic_id": null,
	"sub_cat_id": null,
	"question": "______________________ emerged as a field during the industrial revolution in Europe in the 18th century; however, its development can be traced back several thousand years around the world.",
	"category_id": null,
	"id": null
}, {
	"answer": "its development",
	"topic_id": null,
	"sub_cat_id": null,
	"question": "Mechanical engineering emerged as a field during the industrial revolution in Europe in the 18th century; however, _______________ can be traced back several thousand years around the world.",
	"category_id": null,
	"id": null
}, {
	"answer": "Mechanical engineering science",
	"topic_id": null,
	"sub_cat_id": null,
	"question": "______________________________ emerged in the 19th century as a result of developments in the field of physics.",
	"category_id": null,
	"id": null
}, {
	"answer": "The field",
	"topic_id": null,
	"sub_cat_id": null,
	"question": "_________ has continually evolved to incorporate advancements in technology, and mechanical engineers today are pursuing developments in such fields as composites, mechatronics, and nanotechnology.",
	"category_id": null,
	"id": null
}, {
	"answer": "mechanical engineers today",
	"topic_id": null,
	"sub_cat_id": null,
	"question": "The field has continually evolved to incorporate advancements in technology, and __________________________ are pursuing developments in such fields as composites, mechatronics, and nanotechnology.",
	"category_id": null,
	"id": null
}, {
	"answer": "mechanical engineers",
	"topic_id": null,
	"sub_cat_id": null,
	"question": "The field has continually evolved to incorporate advancements in technology, and ____________________ today are pursuing developments in such fields as composites, mechatronics, and nanotechnology.",
	"category_id": null,
	"id": null
}, {
	"answer": "Mechanical engineers",
	"topic_id": null,
	"sub_cat_id": null,
	"question": "____________________ may also work in the field of biomedical engineering, specifically with biomechanics, transport phenomena, biomechatronics, bionanotechnology, and modeling of biological systems.",
	"category_id": null,
	"id": null
}, {
	"answer": "Mechanical engineering",
	"topic_id": null,
	"sub_cat_id": null,
	"question": "______________________ finds its application in the archives of various ancient and medieval societies throughout mankind.",
	"category_id": null,
	"id": null
}, {
	"answer": "any escapement",
	"topic_id": null,
	"sub_cat_id": null,
	"question": "The medieval Chinese horologist and engineer Su Song (1020\u20131101 AD) incorporated an escapement mechanism into his astronomical clock tower two centuries before ______________ can be found in clocks of medieval Europe, as well as the world's first known endless power-transmitting chain drive.",
	"category_id": null,
	"id": null
}, {
	"answer": "endless power-transmitting chain",
	"topic_id": null,
	"sub_cat_id": null,
	"question": "The medieval Chinese horologist and engineer Su Song (1020\u20131101 AD) incorporated an escapement mechanism into his astronomical clock tower two centuries before any escapement can be found in clocks of medieval Europe, as well as the world's first known ________________________________ drive.",
	"category_id": null,
	"id": null
}, {
	"answer": "the era",
	"topic_id": null,
	"sub_cat_id": null,
	"question": "During the years from 7th to 15th century, _______ called the Islamic Golden Age, there were remarkable contributions from Muslim inventors in the field of mechanical technology.",
	"category_id": null,
	"id": null
}, {
	"answer": "remarkable contributions",
	"topic_id": null,
	"sub_cat_id": null,
	"question": "During the years from 7th to 15th century, the era called the Islamic Golden Age, there were ________________________ from Muslim inventors in the field of mechanical technology.",
	"category_id": null,
	"id": null
}, {
	"answer": "Al-Jazari",
	"topic_id": null,
	"sub_cat_id": null,
	"question": "_________, who was one of them, wrote his famous Book of Knowledge of Ingenious Mechanical Devices in 1206, and presented many mechanical designs.",
	"category_id": null,
	"id": null
}, {
	"answer": "such mechanical devices",
	"topic_id": null,
	"sub_cat_id": null,
	"question": "He is also considered to be the inventor of _______________________ which now form the very basic of mechanisms, such as the crankshaft and camshaft.",
	"category_id": null,
	"id": null
}, {
	"answer": "Sir Isaac Newton",
	"topic_id": null,
	"sub_cat_id": null,
	"question": "Important breakthroughs in the foundations of mechanical engineering occurred in England during the 17th century when ________________ both formulated the three Newton's Laws of Motion and developed Calculus, the mathematical basis of physics.",
	"category_id": null,
	"id": null
}, {
	"answer": "Newton",
	"topic_id": null,
	"sub_cat_id": null,
	"question": "______ was reluctant to publish his methods and laws for years, but he was finally persuaded to do so by his colleagues, such as Sir Edmund Halley, much to the benefit of all mankind.",
	"category_id": null,
	"id": null
}, {
	"answer": "Gottfried Wilhelm Leibniz",
	"topic_id": null,
	"sub_cat_id": null,
	"question": "_________________________ is also credited with creating Calculus during the same time frame.",
	"category_id": null,
	"id": null
}, {
	"answer": "Calculus",
	"topic_id": null,
	"sub_cat_id": null,
	"question": "Gottfried Wilhelm Leibniz is also credited with creating ________ during the same time frame.",
	"category_id": null,
	"id": null
}, {
	"answer": "an engineering education",
	"topic_id": null,
	"sub_cat_id": null,
	"question": "In the United States, the American Society of Mechanical Engineers (ASME) was formed in 1880, becoming the third such professional engineering society, after the American Society of Civil Engineers (1852) and the American Institute of Mining Engineers (1871).",
	"category_id": null,
	"id": null
}, {
	"answer": "an engineering education",
	"topic_id": null,
	"sub_cat_id": null,
	"question": "The first schools in the United States to offer ________________________ were the United States Military Academy in 1817, an institution now known as Norwich University in 1819, and Rensselaer Polytechnic Institute in 1825.",
	"category_id": null,
	"id": null
}, {
	"answer": "an institution",
	"topic_id": null,
	"sub_cat_id": null,
	"question": "The first schools in the United States to offer an engineering education were the United States Military Academy in 1817, ______________ now known as Norwich University in 1819, and Rensselaer Polytechnic Institute in 1825.",
	"category_id": null,
	"id": null
}, {
	"answer": "Engineering",
	"topic_id": null,
	"sub_cat_id": null,
	"question": "___________ has been an aspect of life since the beginnings of human existence.",
	"category_id": null,
	"id": null
}, {
	"answer": "humans",
	"topic_id": null,
	"sub_cat_id": null,
	"question": "The earliest practice of civil engineering may have commenced between 4000 and 2000 BC in Ancient Egypt, the Indus Valley Civilization, and Mesopotamia (Ancient Iraq) when ______ started to abandon a nomadic existence, creating a need for the construction of shelter.",
	"category_id": null,
	"id": null
}, {
	"answer": "transportation",
	"topic_id": null,
	"sub_cat_id": null,
	"question": "During this time, ______________ became increasingly important leading to the development of the wheel and sailing.",
	"category_id": null,
	"id": null
}, {
	"answer": "the oldest",
	"topic_id": null,
	"sub_cat_id": null,
	"question": "Other ancient historic civil engineering constructions include the Qanat water management system (__________ is older than 3000 years and longer than 71\u00a0km,[8]) the Parthenon by Iktinos in Ancient Greece (447\u2013438 BC), the Appian Way by Roman engineers (c.",
	"category_id": null,
	"id": null
}, {
	"answer": "the oldest",
	"topic_id": null,
	"sub_cat_id": null,
	"question": "BC), the Great Wall of China by General Meng T'ien under orders from Ch'in Emperor Shih Huang Ti (c.",
	"category_id": null,
	"id": null
}, {
	"answer": "the oldest",
	"topic_id": null,
	"sub_cat_id": null,
	"question": "BC)[6] and the stupas constructed in ancient Sri Lanka like the Jetavanaramaya and the extensive irrigation works in Anuradhapura.",
	"category_id": null,
	"id": null
}, {
	"answer": "The Romans",
	"topic_id": null,
	"sub_cat_id": null,
	"question": "__________ developed civil structures throughout their empire, including especially aqueducts, insulae, harbors, bridges, dams and roads.",
	"category_id": null,
	"id": null
}, {
	"answer": "John Smeaton",
	"topic_id": null,
	"sub_cat_id": null,
	"question": "In the 18th century, the term civil engineering was coined to incorporate all things civilian as opposed to military engineering.",
	"category_id": null,
	"id": null
}, {
	"answer": "John Smeaton",
	"topic_id": null,
	"sub_cat_id": null,
	"question": "The first self-proclaimed civil engineer was ____________, who constructed the Eddystone Lighthouse.",
	"category_id": null,
	"id": null
}, {
	"answer": "John Smeaton",
	"topic_id": null,
	"sub_cat_id": null,
	"question": "In 1771 Smeaton and some of his colleagues formed the Smeatonian Society of Civil Engineers, a group of leaders of the profession who met informally over dinner.",
	"category_id": null,
	"id": null
}, {
	"answer": "Civil Engineers",
	"topic_id": null,
	"sub_cat_id": null,
	"question": "In 1818 the Institution of _______________ was founded in London, and in 1820 the eminent engineer Thomas Telford became its first president.",
	"category_id": null,
	"id": null
}, {
	"answer": "The institution",
	"topic_id": null,
	"sub_cat_id": null,
	"question": "_______________ received a Royal Charter in 1828, formally recognising civil engineering as a profession.",
	"category_id": null,
	"id": null
}, {
	"answer": "a woman",
	"topic_id": null,
	"sub_cat_id": null,
	"question": "The first private college to teach civil engineering in the United States was Norwich University, founded in 1819 by Captain Alden Partridge.",
	"category_id": null,
	"id": null
}, {
	"answer": "a woman",
	"topic_id": null,
	"sub_cat_id": null,
	"question": "The first degree in civil engineering in the United States was awarded by Rensselaer Polytechnic Institute in 1835.",
	"category_id": null,
	"id": null
}, {
	"answer": "a woman",
	"topic_id": null,
	"sub_cat_id": null,
	"question": "The first such degree to be awarded to _______ was granted by Cornell University to Nora Stanton Blatch in 1905.",
	"category_id": null,
	"id": null
}, {
	"answer": "by Cornell University",
	"topic_id": null,
	"sub_cat_id": null,
	"question": "The first such degree to be awarded to a woman was granted _____________________ to Nora Stanton Blatch in 1905.",
	"category_id": null,
	"id": null
}, {
	"answer": "Civil engineering",
	"topic_id": null,
	"sub_cat_id": null,
	"question": "_________________ is the application of physical and scientific principles for solving the problems of society, and its history is intricately linked to advances in understanding of physics and mathematics throughout history.",
	"category_id": null,
	"id": null
}, {
	"answer": "its history",
	"topic_id": null,
	"sub_cat_id": null,
	"question": "Because civil engineering is a wide ranging profession, including several separate specialized sub-disciplines, ___________ is linked to knowledge of structures, materials science, geography, geology, soils, hydrology, environment, mechanics and other fields.",
	"category_id": null,
	"id": null
}, {
	"answer": "Knowledge",
	"topic_id": null,
	"sub_cat_id": null,
	"question": "_________ was retained in guilds and seldom supplanted by advances.",
	"category_id": null,
	"id": null
}, {
	"answer": "by advances",
	"topic_id": null,
	"sub_cat_id": null,
	"question": "Knowledge was retained in guilds and seldom supplanted ___________.",
	"category_id": null,
	"id": null
}, {
	"answer": "increases in scale",
	"topic_id": null,
	"sub_cat_id": null,
	"question": "Structures, roads and infrastructure that existed were repetitive, and __________________ were incremental.",
	"category_id": null,
	"id": null
}, {
	"answer": "Civil engineers",
	"topic_id": null,
	"sub_cat_id": null,
	"question": "_______________ typically possess an academic degree in civil engineering.",
	"category_id": null,
	"id": null
}, {
	"answer": "the completed degree",
	"topic_id": null,
	"sub_cat_id": null,
	"question": "The length of study is three to five years, and ____________________ is designated as a bachelor of engineering, or a bachelor of science.",
	"category_id": null,
	"id": null
}, {
	"sub_cat_id": null,
	"topic_id": null,
	"question": "_____________________ is the primary field of engineering concerned with the development of aircraft and spacecraft.",
	"category_id": null,
	"answer": "Aerospace engineering",
	"id": null
}, {
	"sub_cat_id": null,
	"topic_id": null,
	"question": "It is divided into two major and overlapping branches: aeronautical engineering and astronautical engineering.",
	"category_id": null,
	"answer": "Aerospace engineering",
	"id": null
}, {
	"sub_cat_id": null,
	"topic_id": null,
	"question": "________________________ was the original term for the field, but as flight technology advanced to include craft operating in outer space, the broader term \"aerospace engineering\" has largely replaced it in common usage.",
	"category_id": null,
	"answer": "Aeronautical engineering",
	"id": null
}, {
	"sub_cat_id": null,
	"topic_id": null,
	"question": "Aerospace engineering, particularly the astronautics branch, is often incorrectly referred to as \"rocket science\".",
	"category_id": null,
	"answer": "Aeronautical engineering",
	"id": null
}, {
	"sub_cat_id": null,
	"topic_id": null,
	"question": "_______________ are subjected to demanding conditions such as those produced by changes in atmospheric pressure and temperature, with structural loads applied upon vehicle components.",
	"category_id": null,
	"answer": "Flight vehicles",
	"id": null
}, {
	"sub_cat_id": null,
	"topic_id": null,
	"question": "One of the most important people in the history of aeronautics,[7] ______ was a pioneer in aeronautical engineering[8] and is credited as the first person to separate the forces of lift and drag, which are in effect on any flight vehicle.",
	"category_id": null,
	"answer": "Cayley",
	"id": null
}, {
	"sub_cat_id": null,
	"topic_id": null,
	"question": "Early knowledge of aeronautical engineering was largely empirical with some concepts and skills imported from other branches of engineering.",
	"category_id": null,
	"answer": "Cayley",
	"id": null
}, {
	"sub_cat_id": null,
	"topic_id": null,
	"question": "Scientists understood some key elements of aerospace engineering, like fluid dynamics, in the 18th century.",
	"category_id": null,
	"answer": "Cayley",
	"id": null
}, {
	"sub_cat_id": null,
	"topic_id": null,
	"question": "One of the most important people in the history of aeronautics,[7] Cayley was a pioneer in aeronautical engineering[8] and is credited as the first person to separate the forces of _____________, which are in effect on any flight vehicle.",
	"category_id": null,
	"answer": "lift and drag",
	"id": null
}, {
	"sub_cat_id": null,
	"topic_id": null,
	"question": "Many years later after the successful flights by the Wright brothers, _________ saw the development of aeronautical engineering through the design of World War I military aircraft.",
	"category_id": null,
	"answer": "the 1910s",
	"id": null
}, {
	"sub_cat_id": null,
	"topic_id": null,
	"question": "The first definition of aerospace engineering appeared in February 1958.",
	"category_id": null,
	"answer": "The definition",
	"id": null
}, {
	"sub_cat_id": null,
	"topic_id": null,
	"question": "______________ considered the Earth's atmosphere and the outer space as a single realm, thereby encompassing both aircraft (aero) and spacecraft (space) under a newly coined word aerospace.",
	"category_id": null,
	"answer": "The definition",
	"id": null
}, {
	"sub_cat_id": null,
	"topic_id": null,
	"question": "The definition considered the Earth's atmosphere and the outer space as a single realm, thereby encompassing both aircraft (aero) and spacecraft (space) under a newly coined ______________.",
	"category_id": null,
	"answer": "word aerospace",
	"id": null
}, {
	"sub_cat_id": null,
	"topic_id": null,
	"question": "In response to ________ launching the first satellite, Sputnik into space on October 4, 1957, U.",
	"category_id": null,
	"answer": "the USSR",
	"id": null
}, {
	"sub_cat_id": null,
	"topic_id": null,
	"question": "S.",
	"category_id": null,
	"answer": "the USSR",
	"id": null
}, {
	"sub_cat_id": null,
	"topic_id": null,
	"question": "American satellite on January 31, 1958.",
	"category_id": null,
	"answer": "the USSR",
	"id": null
}, {
	"sub_cat_id": null,
	"topic_id": null,
	"question": "In response to the USSR launching the first satellite, Sputnik into space on October 4, 1957, U.",
	"category_id": null,
	"answer": "U.S. aerospace engineers",
	"id": null
}, {
	"sub_cat_id": null,
	"topic_id": null,
	"question": "Specifically ____________ concerning the flow of air over bodies such as wings or through objects such as wind tunnels (see also lift and aeronautics).",
	"category_id": null,
	"answer": "aerodynamics",
	"id": null
}, {
	"sub_cat_id": null,
	"topic_id": null,
	"question": "While few schools in the United States teach this at the undergraduate level, several have graduate programs covering __________ (usually in conjunction with the Physics department of said college or university).",
	"category_id": null,
	"answer": "this topic",
	"id": null
}, {
	"sub_cat_id": null,
	"topic_id": null,
	"question": "Control engineering\u00a0\u2013 the study of mathematical modeling of the dynamic behavior of systems and designing them, usually using ________________, so that their dynamic behavior is desirable (stable, without large excursions, with minimum error).",
	"category_id": null,
	"answer": "feedback signals",
	"id": null
}, {
	"sub_cat_id": null,
	"topic_id": null,
	"question": "Control engineering\u00a0\u2013 the study of mathematical modeling of the dynamic behavior of systems and designing them, usually using feedback signals, so that ______________________ is desirable (stable, without large excursions, with minimum error).",
	"category_id": null,
	"answer": "their dynamic behavior",
	"id": null
}, {
	"sub_cat_id": null,
	"topic_id": null,
	"question": "Aircraft structures\u00a0\u2013 design of the physical configuration of the craft to withstand __________ encountered during flight.",
	"category_id": null,
	"answer": "the forces",
	"id": null
}, {
	"sub_cat_id": null,
	"topic_id": null,
	"question": "_____________________ aims to keep structures lightweight and low-cost, while maintaining structural integrity.",
	"category_id": null,
	"answer": "Aerospace engineering",
	"id": null
}, {
	"sub_cat_id": null,
	"topic_id": null,
	"question": "___________________ related to structures, aerospace engineering also studies the materials of which the aerospace structures are to be built.",
	"category_id": null,
	"answer": "Materials science\u00a0\u2013",
	"id": null
}, {
	"sub_cat_id": null,
	"topic_id": null,
	"question": "New materials with very specific properties are invented, or _____________ are modified to improve their performance.",
	"category_id": null,
	"answer": "existing ones",
	"id": null
}, {
	"sub_cat_id": null,
	"topic_id": null,
	"question": "Solid mechanics\u00a0\u2013 Closely related to material science is _______________ which deals with stress and strain analysis of the components of the vehicle.",
	"category_id": null,
	"answer": "solid mechanics",
	"id": null
}, {
	"sub_cat_id": null,
	"topic_id": null,
	"question": "_____________________ is the primary field of engineering concerned with the development of aircraft and spacecraft.",
	"category_id": null,
	"answer": "Aerospace engineering",
	"id": null
}, {
	"sub_cat_id": null,
	"topic_id": null,
	"question": "It is divided into two major and overlapping branches: aeronautical engineering and astronautical engineering.",
	"category_id": null,
	"answer": "Aerospace engineering",
	"id": null
}, {
	"sub_cat_id": null,
	"topic_id": null,
	"question": "________________________ was the original term for the field, but as flight technology advanced to include craft operating in outer space, the broader term \"aerospace engineering\" has largely replaced it in common usage.",
	"category_id": null,
	"answer": "Aeronautical engineering",
	"id": null
}, {
	"sub_cat_id": null,
	"topic_id": null,
	"question": "Aerospace engineering, particularly the astronautics branch, is often incorrectly referred to as \"rocket science\".",
	"category_id": null,
	"answer": "Aeronautical engineering",
	"id": null
}, {
	"sub_cat_id": null,
	"topic_id": null,
	"question": "_______________ are subjected to demanding conditions such as those produced by changes in atmospheric pressure and temperature, with structural loads applied upon vehicle components.",
	"category_id": null,
	"answer": "Flight vehicles",
	"id": null
}, {
	"sub_cat_id": null,
	"topic_id": null,
	"question": "One of the most important people in the history of aeronautics,[7] ______ was a pioneer in aeronautical engineering[8] and is credited as the first person to separate the forces of lift and drag, which are in effect on any flight vehicle.",
	"category_id": null,
	"answer": "Cayley",
	"id": null
}, {
	"sub_cat_id": null,
	"topic_id": null,
	"question": "Early knowledge of aeronautical engineering was largely empirical with some concepts and skills imported from other branches of engineering.",
	"category_id": null,
	"answer": "Cayley",
	"id": null
}, {
	"sub_cat_id": null,
	"topic_id": null,
	"question": "Scientists understood some key elements of aerospace engineering, like fluid dynamics, in the 18th century.",
	"category_id": null,
	"answer": "Cayley",
	"id": null
}, {
	"sub_cat_id": null,
	"topic_id": null,
	"question": "One of the most important people in the history of aeronautics,[7] Cayley was a pioneer in aeronautical engineering[8] and is credited as the first person to separate the forces of _____________, which are in effect on any flight vehicle.",
	"category_id": null,
	"answer": "lift and drag",
	"id": null
}, {
	"sub_cat_id": null,
	"topic_id": null,
	"question": "Many years later after the successful flights by the Wright brothers, _________ saw the development of aeronautical engineering through the design of World War I military aircraft.",
	"category_id": null,
	"answer": "the 1910s",
	"id": null
}, {
	"sub_cat_id": null,
	"topic_id": null,
	"question": "The first definition of aerospace engineering appeared in February 1958.",
	"category_id": null,
	"answer": "The definition",
	"id": null
}, {
	"sub_cat_id": null,
	"topic_id": null,
	"question": "______________ considered the Earth's atmosphere and the outer space as a single realm, thereby encompassing both aircraft (aero) and spacecraft (space) under a newly coined word aerospace.",
	"category_id": null,
	"answer": "The definition",
	"id": null
}, {
	"sub_cat_id": null,
	"topic_id": null,
	"question": "The definition considered the Earth's atmosphere and the outer space as a single realm, thereby encompassing both aircraft (aero) and spacecraft (space) under a newly coined ______________.",
	"category_id": null,
	"answer": "word aerospace",
	"id": null
}, {
	"sub_cat_id": null,
	"topic_id": null,
	"question": "In response to ________ launching the first satellite, Sputnik into space on October 4, 1957, U.",
	"category_id": null,
	"answer": "the USSR",
	"id": null
}, {
	"sub_cat_id": null,
	"topic_id": null,
	"question": "S.",
	"category_id": null,
	"answer": "the USSR",
	"id": null
}, {
	"sub_cat_id": null,
	"topic_id": null,
	"question": "American satellite on January 31, 1958.",
	"category_id": null,
	"answer": "the USSR",
	"id": null
}, {
	"sub_cat_id": null,
	"topic_id": null,
	"question": "In response to the USSR launching the first satellite, Sputnik into space on October 4, 1957, U.",
	"category_id": null,
	"answer": "U.S. aerospace engineers",
	"id": null
}, {
	"sub_cat_id": null,
	"topic_id": null,
	"question": "Specifically ____________ concerning the flow of air over bodies such as wings or through objects such as wind tunnels (see also lift and aeronautics).",
	"category_id": null,
	"answer": "aerodynamics",
	"id": null
}, {
	"sub_cat_id": null,
	"topic_id": null,
	"question": "While few schools in the United States teach this at the undergraduate level, several have graduate programs covering __________ (usually in conjunction with the Physics department of said college or university).",
	"category_id": null,
	"answer": "this topic",
	"id": null
}, {
	"sub_cat_id": null,
	"topic_id": null,
	"question": "Control engineering\u00a0\u2013 the study of mathematical modeling of the dynamic behavior of systems and designing them, usually using ________________, so that their dynamic behavior is desirable (stable, without large excursions, with minimum error).",
	"category_id": null,
	"answer": "feedback signals",
	"id": null
}, {
	"sub_cat_id": null,
	"topic_id": null,
	"question": "Control engineering\u00a0\u2013 the study of mathematical modeling of the dynamic behavior of systems and designing them, usually using feedback signals, so that ______________________ is desirable (stable, without large excursions, with minimum error).",
	"category_id": null,
	"answer": "their dynamic behavior",
	"id": null
}, {
	"sub_cat_id": null,
	"topic_id": null,
	"question": "Aircraft structures\u00a0\u2013 design of the physical configuration of the craft to withstand __________ encountered during flight.",
	"category_id": null,
	"answer": "the forces",
	"id": null
}, {
	"sub_cat_id": null,
	"topic_id": null,
	"question": "_____________________ aims to keep structures lightweight and low-cost, while maintaining structural integrity.",
	"category_id": null,
	"answer": "Aerospace engineering",
	"id": null
}, {
	"sub_cat_id": null,
	"topic_id": null,
	"question": "___________________ related to structures, aerospace engineering also studies the materials of which the aerospace structures are to be built.",
	"category_id": null,
	"answer": "Materials science\u00a0\u2013",
	"id": null
}, {
	"sub_cat_id": null,
	"topic_id": null,
	"question": "New materials with very specific properties are invented, or _____________ are modified to improve their performance.",
	"category_id": null,
	"answer": "existing ones",
	"id": null
}, {
	"sub_cat_id": null,
	"topic_id": null,
	"question": "Solid mechanics\u00a0\u2013 Closely related to material science is _______________ which deals with stress and strain analysis of the components of the vehicle.",
	"category_id": null,
	"answer": "solid mechanics",
	"id": null
}, {
	"sub_cat_id": null,
	"topic_id": null,
	"question": "The American Society of ______________________, now known as the American Society of Agricultural and Biological Engineers, was founded in 1907.",
	"category_id": null,
	"answer": "Agricultural Engineers",
	"id": null
}, {
	"sub_cat_id": null,
	"topic_id": null,
	"question": "______________________ may perform tasks such as planning, supervising and managing the building of dairy effluent schemes, irrigation, drainage, flood and water control systems, performing environmental impact assessments, agricultural product processing and interpret research results and implement relevant practices.",
	"category_id": null,
	"answer": "Agricultural engineers",
	"id": null
}, {
	"sub_cat_id": null,
	"topic_id": null,
	"question": "Some are consultants, employed by private engineering firms, while ______ work in industry, for manufacturers of agricultural machinery, equipment, processing technology, and structures for housing livestock and storing crops.",
	"category_id": null,
	"answer": "others",
	"id": null
}, {
	"sub_cat_id": null,
	"topic_id": null,
	"question": "______________________ work in production, sales, management, research and development, or applied science.",
	"category_id": null,
	"answer": "Agricultural engineers",
	"id": null
}, {
	"sub_cat_id": null,
	"topic_id": null,
	"question": "In the United Kingdom the term Agricultural Engineer is often also used to describe ________ that repairs or modifies agricultural equipment.",
	"category_id": null,
	"answer": "a person",
	"id": null
}, {
	"sub_cat_id": null,
	"topic_id": null,
	"question": "_____________________ is the primary field of engineering concerned with the development of aircraft and spacecraft.",
	"category_id": null,
	"answer": "Aerospace engineering",
	"id": null
}, {
	"sub_cat_id": null,
	"topic_id": null,
	"question": "It is divided into two major and overlapping branches: aeronautical engineering and astronautical engineering.",
	"category_id": null,
	"answer": "Aerospace engineering",
	"id": null
}, {
	"sub_cat_id": null,
	"topic_id": null,
	"question": "________________________ was the original term for the field, but as flight technology advanced to include craft operating in outer space, the broader term \"aerospace engineering\" has largely replaced it in common usage.",
	"category_id": null,
	"answer": "Aeronautical engineering",
	"id": null
}, {
	"sub_cat_id": null,
	"topic_id": null,
	"question": "Aerospace engineering, particularly the astronautics branch, is often incorrectly referred to as \"rocket science\".",
	"category_id": null,
	"answer": "Aeronautical engineering",
	"id": null
}, {
	"sub_cat_id": null,
	"topic_id": null,
	"question": "_______________ are subjected to demanding conditions such as those produced by changes in atmospheric pressure and temperature, with structural loads applied upon vehicle components.",
	"category_id": null,
	"answer": "Flight vehicles",
	"id": null
}, {
	"sub_cat_id": null,
	"topic_id": null,
	"question": "One of the most important people in the history of aeronautics,[7] ______ was a pioneer in aeronautical engineering[8] and is credited as the first person to separate the forces of lift and drag, which are in effect on any flight vehicle.",
	"category_id": null,
	"answer": "Cayley",
	"id": null
}, {
	"sub_cat_id": null,
	"topic_id": null,
	"question": "Early knowledge of aeronautical engineering was largely empirical with some concepts and skills imported from other branches of engineering.",
	"category_id": null,
	"answer": "Cayley",
	"id": null
}, {
	"sub_cat_id": null,
	"topic_id": null,
	"question": "Scientists understood some key elements of aerospace engineering, like fluid dynamics, in the 18th century.",
	"category_id": null,
	"answer": "Cayley",
	"id": null
}, {
	"sub_cat_id": null,
	"topic_id": null,
	"question": "One of the most important people in the history of aeronautics,[7] Cayley was a pioneer in aeronautical engineering[8] and is credited as the first person to separate the forces of _____________, which are in effect on any flight vehicle.",
	"category_id": null,
	"answer": "lift and drag",
	"id": null
}, {
	"sub_cat_id": null,
	"topic_id": null,
	"question": "Many years later after the successful flights by the Wright brothers, _________ saw the development of aeronautical engineering through the design of World War I military aircraft.",
	"category_id": null,
	"answer": "the 1910s",
	"id": null
}, {
	"sub_cat_id": null,
	"topic_id": null,
	"question": "The first definition of aerospace engineering appeared in February 1958.",
	"category_id": null,
	"answer": "The definition",
	"id": null
}, {
	"sub_cat_id": null,
	"topic_id": null,
	"question": "______________ considered the Earth's atmosphere and the outer space as a single realm, thereby encompassing both aircraft (aero) and spacecraft (space) under a newly coined word aerospace.",
	"category_id": null,
	"answer": "The definition",
	"id": null
}, {
	"sub_cat_id": null,
	"topic_id": null,
	"question": "The definition considered the Earth's atmosphere and the outer space as a single realm, thereby encompassing both aircraft (aero) and spacecraft (space) under a newly coined ______________.",
	"category_id": null,
	"answer": "word aerospace",
	"id": null
}, {
	"sub_cat_id": null,
	"topic_id": null,
	"question": "In response to ________ launching the first satellite, Sputnik into space on October 4, 1957, U.",
	"category_id": null,
	"answer": "the USSR",
	"id": null
}, {
	"sub_cat_id": null,
	"topic_id": null,
	"question": "S.",
	"category_id": null,
	"answer": "the USSR",
	"id": null
}, {
	"sub_cat_id": null,
	"topic_id": null,
	"question": "American satellite on January 31, 1958.",
	"category_id": null,
	"answer": "the USSR",
	"id": null
}, {
	"sub_cat_id": null,
	"topic_id": null,
	"question": "In response to the USSR launching the first satellite, Sputnik into space on October 4, 1957, U.",
	"category_id": null,
	"answer": "U.S. aerospace engineers",
	"id": null
}, {
	"sub_cat_id": null,
	"topic_id": null,
	"question": "Specifically ____________ concerning the flow of air over bodies such as wings or through objects such as wind tunnels (see also lift and aeronautics).",
	"category_id": null,
	"answer": "aerodynamics",
	"id": null
}, {
	"sub_cat_id": null,
	"topic_id": null,
	"question": "While few schools in the United States teach this at the undergraduate level, several have graduate programs covering __________ (usually in conjunction with the Physics department of said college or university).",
	"category_id": null,
	"answer": "this topic",
	"id": null
}, {
	"sub_cat_id": null,
	"topic_id": null,
	"question": "Control engineering\u00a0\u2013 the study of mathematical modeling of the dynamic behavior of systems and designing them, usually using ________________, so that their dynamic behavior is desirable (stable, without large excursions, with minimum error).",
	"category_id": null,
	"answer": "feedback signals",
	"id": null
}, {
	"sub_cat_id": null,
	"topic_id": null,
	"question": "Control engineering\u00a0\u2013 the study of mathematical modeling of the dynamic behavior of systems and designing them, usually using feedback signals, so that ______________________ is desirable (stable, without large excursions, with minimum error).",
	"category_id": null,
	"answer": "their dynamic behavior",
	"id": null
}, {
	"sub_cat_id": null,
	"topic_id": null,
	"question": "Aircraft structures\u00a0\u2013 design of the physical configuration of the craft to withstand __________ encountered during flight.",
	"category_id": null,
	"answer": "the forces",
	"id": null
}, {
	"sub_cat_id": null,
	"topic_id": null,
	"question": "_____________________ aims to keep structures lightweight and low-cost, while maintaining structural integrity.",
	"category_id": null,
	"answer": "Aerospace engineering",
	"id": null
}, {
	"sub_cat_id": null,
	"topic_id": null,
	"question": "___________________ related to structures, aerospace engineering also studies the materials of which the aerospace structures are to be built.",
	"category_id": null,
	"answer": "Materials science\u00a0\u2013",
	"id": null
}, {
	"sub_cat_id": null,
	"topic_id": null,
	"question": "New materials with very specific properties are invented, or _____________ are modified to improve their performance.",
	"category_id": null,
	"answer": "existing ones",
	"id": null
}, {
	"sub_cat_id": null,
	"topic_id": null,
	"question": "Solid mechanics\u00a0\u2013 Closely related to material science is _______________ which deals with stress and strain analysis of the components of the vehicle.",
	"category_id": null,
	"answer": "solid mechanics",
	"id": null
}, {
	"sub_cat_id": null,
	"topic_id": null,
	"question": "The American Society of ______________________, now known as the American Society of Agricultural and Biological Engineers, was founded in 1907.",
	"category_id": null,
	"answer": "Agricultural Engineers",
	"id": null
}, {
	"sub_cat_id": null,
	"topic_id": null,
	"question": "______________________ may perform tasks such as planning, supervising and managing the building of dairy effluent schemes, irrigation, drainage, flood and water control systems, performing environmental impact assessments, agricultural product processing and interpret research results and implement relevant practices.",
	"category_id": null,
	"answer": "Agricultural engineers",
	"id": null
}, {
	"sub_cat_id": null,
	"topic_id": null,
	"question": "Some are consultants, employed by private engineering firms, while ______ work in industry, for manufacturers of agricultural machinery, equipment, processing technology, and structures for housing livestock and storing crops.",
	"category_id": null,
	"answer": "others",
	"id": null
}, {
	"sub_cat_id": null,
	"topic_id": null,
	"question": "______________________ work in production, sales, management, research and development, or applied science.",
	"category_id": null,
	"answer": "Agricultural engineers",
	"id": null
}, {
	"sub_cat_id": null,
	"topic_id": null,
	"question": "In the United Kingdom the term Agricultural Engineer is often also used to describe ________ that repairs or modifies agricultural equipment.",
	"category_id": null,
	"answer": "a person",
	"id": null
}, {
	"sub_cat_id": null,
	"topic_id": null,
	"question": "____________________________ is the application of engineering principles and design concepts to medicine and biology for healthcare purposes (e.",
	"category_id": null,
	"answer": "Biomedical engineering (BME)",
	"id": null
}, {
	"sub_cat_id": null,
	"topic_id": null,
	"question": "__________ seeks to close the gap between engineering and medicine, combining the design and problem solving skills of engineering with medical and biological sciences to advance health care treatment, including diagnosis, monitoring, and therapy.",
	"category_id": null,
	"answer": "This field",
	"id": null
}, {
	"sub_cat_id": null,
	"topic_id": null,
	"question": "Biomedical engineering has only recently emerged as its own study, compared to many other engineering fields.",
	"category_id": null,
	"answer": "This field",
	"id": null
}, {
	"sub_cat_id": null,
	"topic_id": null,
	"question": "This field seeks to close the gap between engineering and medicine, combining the design and problem solving skills of engineering with medical and biological sciences to advance health care treatment, including _________, monitoring, and therapy.",
	"category_id": null,
	"answer": "diagnosis",
	"id": null
}, {
	"sub_cat_id": null,
	"topic_id": null,
	"question": "This field seeks to close the gap between engineering and medicine, combining the design and problem solving skills of engineering with medical and biological sciences to advance health care treatment, including diagnosis, monitoring, and therapy.",
	"category_id": null,
	"answer": "therapy.[1] Biomedical engineering",
	"id": null
}, {
	"sub_cat_id": null,
	"topic_id": null,
	"question": "Biomedical engineering has only recently emerged as _____________, compared to many other engineering fields.",
	"category_id": null,
	"answer": "its own study",
	"id": null
}, {
	"sub_cat_id": null,
	"topic_id": null,
	"question": "_________________ is common as a new field transitions from being an interdisciplinary specialization among already-established fields, to being considered a field in itself.",
	"category_id": null,
	"answer": "Such an evolution",
	"id": null
}, {
	"sub_cat_id": null,
	"topic_id": null,
	"question": "______________________ has existed for centuries, perhaps even thousands of years.",
	"category_id": null,
	"answer": "Biomedical engineering",
	"id": null
}, {
	"sub_cat_id": null,
	"topic_id": null,
	"question": "___________ said the wear on the bottom surface suggests that it could be the oldest known limb prosthesis.",
	"category_id": null,
	"answer": "Researchers",
	"id": null
}, {
	"sub_cat_id": null,
	"topic_id": null,
	"question": "________________ accidentally discovered that a cathode-ray tube could make a sheet of paper coated with barium platinocyanide glow, even when the tube and the paper were in separate rooms.",
	"category_id": null,
	"answer": "Wilhelm Roentgen",
	"id": null
}, {
	"sub_cat_id": null,
	"topic_id": null,
	"question": "________ decided the tube must be emitting some kind of penetrating rays, which he called \u201cX\u201d rays.",
	"category_id": null,
	"answer": "Roentgen",
	"id": null
}, {
	"sub_cat_id": null,
	"topic_id": null,
	"question": "Roentgen decided ________ must be emitting some kind of penetrating rays, which he called \u201cX\u201d rays.",
	"category_id": null,
	"answer": "the tube",
	"id": null
}, {
	"sub_cat_id": null,
	"topic_id": null,
	"question": "______________________ originated during World War II.",
	"category_id": null,
	"answer": "Biomedical engineering",
	"id": null
}, {
	"sub_cat_id": null,
	"topic_id": null,
	"question": "Biologists were needed to do work involving advances on radar technology, which led them to the electronic developments in medicine.",
	"category_id": null,
	"answer": "Biomedical engineering",
	"id": null
}, {
	"sub_cat_id": null,
	"topic_id": null,
	"question": "Biomedical engineering originated during World War II.",
	"category_id": null,
	"answer": "Biologists",
	"id": null
}, {
	"sub_cat_id": null,
	"topic_id": null,
	"question": "__________ were needed to do work involving advances on radar technology, which led them to the electronic developments in medicine.",
	"category_id": null,
	"answer": "Biologists",
	"id": null
}, {
	"sub_cat_id": null,
	"topic_id": null,
	"question": "Biologists were needed to do work involving advances on ________________, which led them to the electronic developments in medicine.",
	"category_id": null,
	"answer": "radar technology",
	"id": null
}, {
	"sub_cat_id": null,
	"topic_id": null,
	"question": "Due to these developments, the next generation of biologists could not benefit ____________________, as they couldn\u2019t understand it.",
	"category_id": null,
	"answer": "from this technology",
	"id": null
}, {
	"sub_cat_id": null,
	"topic_id": null,
	"question": "Doctors and biologists who were interested in engineering and ____________________ interested in biology became the first bioengineers.",
	"category_id": null,
	"answer": "electrical engineers",
	"id": null
}, {
	"sub_cat_id": null,
	"topic_id": null,
	"question": "_________________________ discovered the X-ray using gas discharged tubes.",
	"category_id": null,
	"answer": "Conrad Roentgen (Germany)",
	"id": null
}, {
	"sub_cat_id": null,
	"topic_id": null,
	"question": "________________________ discovered X-rays were emitted from uranium ore.",
	"category_id": null,
	"answer": "Henry Becquerel (France)",
	"id": null
}, {
	"sub_cat_id": null,
	"topic_id": null,
	"question": "________ received the Nobel Prize for discovery of X-Rays.",
	"category_id": null,
	"answer": "Roentgen",
	"id": null
}, {
	"sub_cat_id": null,
	"topic_id": null,
	"question": "_________________ invented the electrocardiogram (ECG).",
	"category_id": null,
	"answer": "William Eindhoven",
	"id": null
}, {
	"sub_cat_id": null,
	"topic_id": null,
	"question": "___________ invents the electroencephalogram (EEG).",
	"category_id": null,
	"answer": "Hans Berger",
	"id": null
}, {
	"sub_cat_id": null,
	"topic_id": null,
	"question": "______ were being used to visualize most organ systems using radio-opaque materials, refrigeration, permitted blood banks.",
	"category_id": null,
	"answer": "X-rays",
	"id": null
}, {
	"sub_cat_id": null,
	"topic_id": null,
	"question": "___________________ was founded.",
	"category_id": null,
	"answer": "Whitaker Foundation",
	"id": null
}, {
	"sub_cat_id": null,
	"topic_id": null,
	"question": "_____________________ is the primary field of engineering concerned with the development of aircraft and spacecraft.",
	"category_id": null,
	"answer": "Aerospace engineering",
	"id": null
}, {
	"sub_cat_id": null,
	"topic_id": null,
	"question": "It is divided into two major and overlapping branches: aeronautical engineering and astronautical engineering.",
	"category_id": null,
	"answer": "Aerospace engineering",
	"id": null
}, {
	"sub_cat_id": null,
	"topic_id": null,
	"question": "________________________ was the original term for the field, but as flight technology advanced to include craft operating in outer space, the broader term \"aerospace engineering\" has largely replaced it in common usage.",
	"category_id": null,
	"answer": "Aeronautical engineering",
	"id": null
}, {
	"sub_cat_id": null,
	"topic_id": null,
	"question": "Aerospace engineering, particularly the astronautics branch, is often incorrectly referred to as \"rocket science\".",
	"category_id": null,
	"answer": "Aeronautical engineering",
	"id": null
}, {
	"sub_cat_id": null,
	"topic_id": null,
	"question": "_______________ are subjected to demanding conditions such as those produced by changes in atmospheric pressure and temperature, with structural loads applied upon vehicle components.",
	"category_id": null,
	"answer": "Flight vehicles",
	"id": null
}, {
	"sub_cat_id": null,
	"topic_id": null,
	"question": "One of the most important people in the history of aeronautics,[7] ______ was a pioneer in aeronautical engineering[8] and is credited as the first person to separate the forces of lift and drag, which are in effect on any flight vehicle.",
	"category_id": null,
	"answer": "Cayley",
	"id": null
}, {
	"sub_cat_id": null,
	"topic_id": null,
	"question": "Early knowledge of aeronautical engineering was largely empirical with some concepts and skills imported from other branches of engineering.",
	"category_id": null,
	"answer": "Cayley",
	"id": null
}, {
	"sub_cat_id": null,
	"topic_id": null,
	"question": "Scientists understood some key elements of aerospace engineering, like fluid dynamics, in the 18th century.",
	"category_id": null,
	"answer": "Cayley",
	"id": null
}, {
	"sub_cat_id": null,
	"topic_id": null,
	"question": "One of the most important people in the history of aeronautics,[7] Cayley was a pioneer in aeronautical engineering[8] and is credited as the first person to separate the forces of _____________, which are in effect on any flight vehicle.",
	"category_id": null,
	"answer": "lift and drag",
	"id": null
}, {
	"sub_cat_id": null,
	"topic_id": null,
	"question": "Many years later after the successful flights by the Wright brothers, _________ saw the development of aeronautical engineering through the design of World War I military aircraft.",
	"category_id": null,
	"answer": "the 1910s",
	"id": null
}, {
	"sub_cat_id": null,
	"topic_id": null,
	"question": "The first definition of aerospace engineering appeared in February 1958.",
	"category_id": null,
	"answer": "The definition",
	"id": null
}, {
	"sub_cat_id": null,
	"topic_id": null,
	"question": "______________ considered the Earth's atmosphere and the outer space as a single realm, thereby encompassing both aircraft (aero) and spacecraft (space) under a newly coined word aerospace.",
	"category_id": null,
	"answer": "The definition",
	"id": null
}, {
	"sub_cat_id": null,
	"topic_id": null,
	"question": "The definition considered the Earth's atmosphere and the outer space as a single realm, thereby encompassing both aircraft (aero) and spacecraft (space) under a newly coined ______________.",
	"category_id": null,
	"answer": "word aerospace",
	"id": null
}, {
	"sub_cat_id": null,
	"topic_id": null,
	"question": "In response to ________ launching the first satellite, Sputnik into space on October 4, 1957, U.",
	"category_id": null,
	"answer": "the USSR",
	"id": null
}, {
	"sub_cat_id": null,
	"topic_id": null,
	"question": "S.",
	"category_id": null,
	"answer": "the USSR",
	"id": null
}, {
	"sub_cat_id": null,
	"topic_id": null,
	"question": "American satellite on January 31, 1958.",
	"category_id": null,
	"answer": "the USSR",
	"id": null
}, {
	"sub_cat_id": null,
	"topic_id": null,
	"question": "In response to the USSR launching the first satellite, Sputnik into space on October 4, 1957, U.",
	"category_id": null,
	"answer": "U.S. aerospace engineers",
	"id": null
}, {
	"sub_cat_id": null,
	"topic_id": null,
	"question": "Specifically ____________ concerning the flow of air over bodies such as wings or through objects such as wind tunnels (see also lift and aeronautics).",
	"category_id": null,
	"answer": "aerodynamics",
	"id": null
}, {
	"sub_cat_id": null,
	"topic_id": null,
	"question": "While few schools in the United States teach this at the undergraduate level, several have graduate programs covering __________ (usually in conjunction with the Physics department of said college or university).",
	"category_id": null,
	"answer": "this topic",
	"id": null
}, {
	"sub_cat_id": null,
	"topic_id": null,
	"question": "Control engineering\u00a0\u2013 the study of mathematical modeling of the dynamic behavior of systems and designing them, usually using ________________, so that their dynamic behavior is desirable (stable, without large excursions, with minimum error).",
	"category_id": null,
	"answer": "feedback signals",
	"id": null
}, {
	"sub_cat_id": null,
	"topic_id": null,
	"question": "Control engineering\u00a0\u2013 the study of mathematical modeling of the dynamic behavior of systems and designing them, usually using feedback signals, so that ______________________ is desirable (stable, without large excursions, with minimum error).",
	"category_id": null,
	"answer": "their dynamic behavior",
	"id": null
}, {
	"sub_cat_id": null,
	"topic_id": null,
	"question": "Aircraft structures\u00a0\u2013 design of the physical configuration of the craft to withstand __________ encountered during flight.",
	"category_id": null,
	"answer": "the forces",
	"id": null
}, {
	"sub_cat_id": null,
	"topic_id": null,
	"question": "_____________________ aims to keep structures lightweight and low-cost, while maintaining structural integrity.",
	"category_id": null,
	"answer": "Aerospace engineering",
	"id": null
}, {
	"sub_cat_id": null,
	"topic_id": null,
	"question": "___________________ related to structures, aerospace engineering also studies the materials of which the aerospace structures are to be built.",
	"category_id": null,
	"answer": "Materials science\u00a0\u2013",
	"id": null
}, {
	"sub_cat_id": null,
	"topic_id": null,
	"question": "New materials with very specific properties are invented, or _____________ are modified to improve their performance.",
	"category_id": null,
	"answer": "existing ones",
	"id": null
}, {
	"sub_cat_id": null,
	"topic_id": null,
	"question": "Solid mechanics\u00a0\u2013 Closely related to material science is _______________ which deals with stress and strain analysis of the components of the vehicle.",
	"category_id": null,
	"answer": "solid mechanics",
	"id": null
}, {
	"sub_cat_id": null,
	"topic_id": null,
	"question": "The American Society of ______________________, now known as the American Society of Agricultural and Biological Engineers, was founded in 1907.",
	"category_id": null,
	"answer": "Agricultural Engineers",
	"id": null
}, {
	"sub_cat_id": null,
	"topic_id": null,
	"question": "______________________ may perform tasks such as planning, supervising and managing the building of dairy effluent schemes, irrigation, drainage, flood and water control systems, performing environmental impact assessments, agricultural product processing and interpret research results and implement relevant practices.",
	"category_id": null,
	"answer": "Agricultural engineers",
	"id": null
}, {
	"sub_cat_id": null,
	"topic_id": null,
	"question": "Some are consultants, employed by private engineering firms, while ______ work in industry, for manufacturers of agricultural machinery, equipment, processing technology, and structures for housing livestock and storing crops.",
	"category_id": null,
	"answer": "others",
	"id": null
}, {
	"sub_cat_id": null,
	"topic_id": null,
	"question": "______________________ work in production, sales, management, research and development, or applied science.",
	"category_id": null,
	"answer": "Agricultural engineers",
	"id": null
}, {
	"sub_cat_id": null,
	"topic_id": null,
	"question": "In the United Kingdom the term Agricultural Engineer is often also used to describe ________ that repairs or modifies agricultural equipment.",
	"category_id": null,
	"answer": "a person",
	"id": null
}, {
	"sub_cat_id": null,
	"topic_id": null,
	"question": "____________________________ is the application of engineering principles and design concepts to medicine and biology for healthcare purposes (e.",
	"category_id": null,
	"answer": "Biomedical engineering (BME)",
	"id": null
}, {
	"sub_cat_id": null,
	"topic_id": null,
	"question": "__________ seeks to close the gap between engineering and medicine, combining the design and problem solving skills of engineering with medical and biological sciences to advance health care treatment, including diagnosis, monitoring, and therapy.",
	"category_id": null,
	"answer": "This field",
	"id": null
}, {
	"sub_cat_id": null,
	"topic_id": null,
	"question": "Biomedical engineering has only recently emerged as its own study, compared to many other engineering fields.",
	"category_id": null,
	"answer": "This field",
	"id": null
}, {
	"sub_cat_id": null,
	"topic_id": null,
	"question": "This field seeks to close the gap between engineering and medicine, combining the design and problem solving skills of engineering with medical and biological sciences to advance health care treatment, including _________, monitoring, and therapy.",
	"category_id": null,
	"answer": "diagnosis",
	"id": null
}, {
	"sub_cat_id": null,
	"topic_id": null,
	"question": "This field seeks to close the gap between engineering and medicine, combining the design and problem solving skills of engineering with medical and biological sciences to advance health care treatment, including diagnosis, monitoring, and therapy.",
	"category_id": null,
	"answer": "therapy.[1] Biomedical engineering",
	"id": null
}, {
	"sub_cat_id": null,
	"topic_id": null,
	"question": "Biomedical engineering has only recently emerged as _____________, compared to many other engineering fields.",
	"category_id": null,
	"answer": "its own study",
	"id": null
}, {
	"sub_cat_id": null,
	"topic_id": null,
	"question": "_________________ is common as a new field transitions from being an interdisciplinary specialization among already-established fields, to being considered a field in itself.",
	"category_id": null,
	"answer": "Such an evolution",
	"id": null
}, {
	"sub_cat_id": null,
	"topic_id": null,
	"question": "______________________ has existed for centuries, perhaps even thousands of years.",
	"category_id": null,
	"answer": "Biomedical engineering",
	"id": null
}, {
	"sub_cat_id": null,
	"topic_id": null,
	"question": "___________ said the wear on the bottom surface suggests that it could be the oldest known limb prosthesis.",
	"category_id": null,
	"answer": "Researchers",
	"id": null
}, {
	"sub_cat_id": null,
	"topic_id": null,
	"question": "________________ accidentally discovered that a cathode-ray tube could make a sheet of paper coated with barium platinocyanide glow, even when the tube and the paper were in separate rooms.",
	"category_id": null,
	"answer": "Wilhelm Roentgen",
	"id": null
}, {
	"sub_cat_id": null,
	"topic_id": null,
	"question": "________ decided the tube must be emitting some kind of penetrating rays, which he called \u201cX\u201d rays.",
	"category_id": null,
	"answer": "Roentgen",
	"id": null
}, {
	"sub_cat_id": null,
	"topic_id": null,
	"question": "Roentgen decided ________ must be emitting some kind of penetrating rays, which he called \u201cX\u201d rays.",
	"category_id": null,
	"answer": "the tube",
	"id": null
}, {
	"sub_cat_id": null,
	"topic_id": null,
	"question": "______________________ originated during World War II.",
	"category_id": null,
	"answer": "Biomedical engineering",
	"id": null
}, {
	"sub_cat_id": null,
	"topic_id": null,
	"question": "Biologists were needed to do work involving advances on radar technology, which led them to the electronic developments in medicine.",
	"category_id": null,
	"answer": "Biomedical engineering",
	"id": null
}, {
	"sub_cat_id": null,
	"topic_id": null,
	"question": "Biomedical engineering originated during World War II.",
	"category_id": null,
	"answer": "Biologists",
	"id": null
}, {
	"sub_cat_id": null,
	"topic_id": null,
	"question": "__________ were needed to do work involving advances on radar technology, which led them to the electronic developments in medicine.",
	"category_id": null,
	"answer": "Biologists",
	"id": null
}, {
	"sub_cat_id": null,
	"topic_id": null,
	"question": "Biologists were needed to do work involving advances on ________________, which led them to the electronic developments in medicine.",
	"category_id": null,
	"answer": "radar technology",
	"id": null
}, {
	"sub_cat_id": null,
	"topic_id": null,
	"question": "Due to these developments, the next generation of biologists could not benefit ____________________, as they couldn\u2019t understand it.",
	"category_id": null,
	"answer": "from this technology",
	"id": null
}, {
	"sub_cat_id": null,
	"topic_id": null,
	"question": "Doctors and biologists who were interested in engineering and ____________________ interested in biology became the first bioengineers.",
	"category_id": null,
	"answer": "electrical engineers",
	"id": null
}, {
	"sub_cat_id": null,
	"topic_id": null,
	"question": "_________________________ discovered the X-ray using gas discharged tubes.",
	"category_id": null,
	"answer": "Conrad Roentgen (Germany)",
	"id": null
}, {
	"sub_cat_id": null,
	"topic_id": null,
	"question": "________________________ discovered X-rays were emitted from uranium ore.",
	"category_id": null,
	"answer": "Henry Becquerel (France)",
	"id": null
}, {
	"sub_cat_id": null,
	"topic_id": null,
	"question": "________ received the Nobel Prize for discovery of X-Rays.",
	"category_id": null,
	"answer": "Roentgen",
	"id": null
}, {
	"sub_cat_id": null,
	"topic_id": null,
	"question": "_________________ invented the electrocardiogram (ECG).",
	"category_id": null,
	"answer": "William Eindhoven",
	"id": null
}, {
	"sub_cat_id": null,
	"topic_id": null,
	"question": "___________ invents the electroencephalogram (EEG).",
	"category_id": null,
	"answer": "Hans Berger",
	"id": null
}, {
	"sub_cat_id": null,
	"topic_id": null,
	"question": "______ were being used to visualize most organ systems using radio-opaque materials, refrigeration, permitted blood banks.",
	"category_id": null,
	"answer": "X-rays",
	"id": null
}, {
	"sub_cat_id": null,
	"topic_id": null,
	"question": "___________________ was founded.",
	"category_id": null,
	"answer": "Whitaker Foundation",
	"id": null
}, {
	"sub_cat_id": null,
	"topic_id": null,
	"question": "________ is the study of genes, genetic variation, and heredity in living organisms.",
	"category_id": null,
	"answer": "Genetics",
	"id": null
}, {
	"sub_cat_id": null,
	"topic_id": null,
	"question": "It is generally considered a field of biology, but it intersects frequently with many of the life sciences and is strongly linked with the study of information systems.",
	"category_id": null,
	"answer": "Genetics",
	"id": null
}, {
	"sub_cat_id": null,
	"topic_id": null,
	"question": "______ studied 'trait inheritance', patterns in the way traits were handed down from parents to offspring.",
	"category_id": null,
	"answer": "Mendel",
	"id": null
}, {
	"sub_cat_id": null,
	"topic_id": null,
	"question": "_________, still used today, is a somewhat ambiguous definition of what is referred to as a gene.",
	"category_id": null,
	"answer": "This term",
	"id": null
}, {
	"sub_cat_id": null,
	"topic_id": null,
	"question": "Trait inheritance and molecular inheritance mechanisms of genes are still primary principles of genetics in the 21st century, but _______________ has expanded beyond inheritance to studying the function and behavior of genes.",
	"category_id": null,
	"answer": "modern genetics",
	"id": null
}, {
	"sub_cat_id": null,
	"topic_id": null,
	"question": "________ has given rise to a number of sub-fields including epigenetics and population genetics.",
	"category_id": null,
	"answer": "Genetics",
	"id": null
}, {
	"sub_cat_id": null,
	"topic_id": null,
	"question": "_________ studied within the broad field span the domain of life, including bacteria, plants, animals, and humans.",
	"category_id": null,
	"answer": "Organisms",
	"id": null
}, {
	"sub_cat_id": null,
	"topic_id": null,
	"question": "_________________ is two seeds of genetically identical corn, one placed in a temperate climate and one in an arid climate.",
	"category_id": null,
	"answer": "A classic example",
	"id": null
}, {
	"sub_cat_id": null,
	"topic_id": null,
	"question": "_________________ stems from the Ancient Greek \u03b3\u03b5\u03bd\u03b5\u03c4\u03b9\u03ba\u03cc\u03c2 genetikos meaning \"genitive\"/\"generative\", which in turn derives from \u03b3\u03ad\u03bd\u03b5\u03c3\u03b9\u03c2 genesis meaning \"origin\".",
	"category_id": null,
	"answer": "The word genetics",
	"id": null
}, {
	"sub_cat_id": null,
	"topic_id": null,
	"question": "_______________ is most similar to a single 'word' in the English language.",
	"category_id": null,
	"answer": "A single 'gene'",
	"id": null
}, {
	"sub_cat_id": null,
	"topic_id": null,
	"question": "___________________________ that make up genes can be seen as 'letters' in the English language.",
	"category_id": null,
	"answer": "The nucleotides (molecules)",
	"id": null
}, {
	"sub_cat_id": null,
	"topic_id": null,
	"question": "___________ are named according to which of the four nitrogenous bases they contain.",
	"category_id": null,
	"answer": "Nucleotides",
	"id": null
}, {
	"sub_cat_id": null,
	"topic_id": null,
	"question": "______________ are cytosine, guanine, adenine, and thymine.",
	"category_id": null,
	"answer": "The four bases",
	"id": null
}, {
	"sub_cat_id": null,
	"topic_id": null,
	"question": "_____________ may have a small number of nucleotides or a large number of nucleotides, in the same way that a word may be small or large (e.",
	"category_id": null,
	"answer": "A single gene",
	"id": null
}, {
	"sub_cat_id": null,
	"topic_id": null,
	"question": "A single gene may have a small number of nucleotides or a large number of nucleotides, in the same way that ______ may be small or large (e.",
	"category_id": null,
	"answer": "a word",
	"id": null
}, {
	"sub_cat_id": null,
	"topic_id": null,
	"question": "_____________ often interacts with neighboring genes to produce a cellular function and can even be ineffectual without those neighboring genes.",
	"category_id": null,
	"answer": "A single gene",
	"id": null
}, {
	"sub_cat_id": null,
	"topic_id": null,
	"question": "This can be seen in the same way that ________ may have meaning only in the context of a 'sentence.",
	"category_id": null,
	"answer": "a 'word'",
	"id": null
}, {
	"sub_cat_id": null,
	"topic_id": null,
	"question": "Nonetheless, _________ have letters, like all genes must have nucleotides.",
	"category_id": null,
	"answer": "all words",
	"id": null
}, {
	"sub_cat_id": null,
	"topic_id": null,
	"question": "Nonetheless, all words have letters, like _________ must have nucleotides.",
	"category_id": null,
	"answer": "all genes",
	"id": null
}, {
	"sub_cat_id": null,
	"topic_id": null,
	"question": "_________________ that is often used (but not always true) is \"one gene, one protein\" meaning a singular gene codes for a singular protein type in a cell (enzyme, transcription factor, etc.",
	"category_id": null,
	"answer": "A quick heuristic",
	"id": null
}]